<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Millennials &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<atom:link href="https://onereach.ai/category/millennials/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<description>Intelligently Automate Your Company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 11:39:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/cropped-OR-ICON-GOLD-W-DOTS-Larger-Background-02-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Millennials &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Texting Isn&#8217;t Just for Kids</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/texting-isnt-just-for-kids/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/texting-isnt-just-for-kids/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Millennials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/texting-isnt-just-for-kids/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>“My kids would love that!” </em></p>
<p>I heard that recently from a middle-aged businessman when I told him that customers can now text businesses over their existing phone numbers. It’s not that he’s wrong (his kids would, in fact, love that), it’s just that he doesn’t understand how truly ubiquitous text messaging is. (And, by the way, that same guy admitted to text messaging on a daily basis himself.)</p>
<p><span id="more-7220"></span>We can understand this reality by looking at the numbers. Far from being a technology used just by teenagers, texting is now common across all demographics. <a href="http://www.pewinternet.org/2013/09/19/cell-phone-activities-2013/">According to Pew Internet</a>, 91% of all American adults owns a cell phone. And, of these, 81% use text messaging, making it the most popular activity. Let’s break this down by age group:</p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>Age</strong></td>
<td><strong>% cell phone owners who send or receive text messages</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>18-29</td>
<td>97%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>30-49</td>
<td>94%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>50-64</td>
<td>75%</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>65+</td>
<td>35%</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>So if the vast majority of adults are using text messaging on their phones, why are we so quick to associate the activity with just the young? Well, first of all, the number of texters in the youngest age bracket <i>is </i>a few percentage points higher than in the next bracket. So there’s that. Plus, the young are known for their sheer quantity of texting. Experian discovered that 18-24-year-old American smartphone owners send and receive an average of <a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/chart-of-the-day-number-of-texts-sent-2013-3">3,853 texts per month</a>. That’s 1600 more than the number sent by 25-34-year-olds. No wonder we get the impression that young adults are the texters.</p>
<p>But research shows that older people love texting, too, and are very willing to engage in that channel. That number will grow even more as the current population ages. Plus, older Americans own pretty cool technology. In fact, according to <a href="http://www.nielsen.com/us/en/insights/news/2014/smartphone-milestone-half-of-americans-ages-55-own-smartphones.html">Nielsen</a>, for the first time ever, the majority of Americans in <i>all</i> age brackets now own smartphones—including those 55 and over.</p>
<p>Companies who don’t fully take advantage of their texting capabilities are not only missing out on almost all of their under-50 market, but also 35%-75% of the 50 and older cell phone crowd. That is a huge market share to ignore.</p>
<p>So how could this impact business? Let’s look at the medical field—known for catering to a high percentage of those over 50. I met with an administrator at a doctor’s office who has the frustrating job of rescheduling appointments. The task often turns into a game of phone tag, taking 2-3 voicemails before connecting. At another office, a staff member sits in his car during breaks, just to escape the incessant ringing of the telephone.</p>
<p>Both of these offices would greatly benefit from focusing on their text strategy and text-enabling their customer support. That way, patients can schedule their appointments or ask questions through text. In fact, one staff member admitted that patients ask several times a day if they can use text instead of calling.</p>
<p>Texters of all ages would prefer to use texting rather than voice for customer support. A study conducted by Harris Poll and commissioned by OneReach found that <a href="http://onereachcontactcenter.com/high-demand-for-customer-service-via-text-message/">64% of Americans</a> who text would prefer to use text over voice for customer service, jumping to 76% for millennials and 86% for students over 18. But young people aren&#8217;t the only ones who would rather use texting: 70% of parents who text would prefer to use texting for customer service, and <a href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/?p=1036">over 50% of baby boomers</a> who text would prefer to text to phone for customer service as well.</p>
<p>The reality is that texting is fast becoming the assumed method of communication for all ages. Is your business ready?</p>
<p><em><strong>To learn more about customers&#8217; preference for texting for customer service, <a href="http://onereachcontactcenter.com/high-demand-for-customer-service-via-text-message/">download the 2014 Harris Report here</a>.</strong></em></p>
<p>Photo by <a href="http://startupstockphotos.com/">Startup Stock Photos</a>. Edited.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/texting-isnt-just-for-kids/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Call Me Maybe: A Millennial Perspective on the Decline of Voicemail</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/call-me-maybe-a-millennial-perspective-on-the-decline-of-voicemail/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/call-me-maybe-a-millennial-perspective-on-the-decline-of-voicemail/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Big Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Millennials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/call-me-maybe-a-millennial-perspective-on-the-decline-of-voicemail/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr"><em>The New York Times</em> recently reported that <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/06/15/fashion/millennials-shy-away-from-voice-mail.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">millennials are using voicemail less</a> (in other news, water is wet). What’s really interesting about the article is that it pins the decline of voicemail squarely on Gen Y: “Teenagers are texting more…and calling far less on their cellphones than they used to. Those who make daily landline calls to friends have become nearly extinct: 14 percent as compared with 30 percent in 2009.”</p>
<p dir="ltr"><span id="more-7118"></span>Every other article on millennials says the same thing: anyone age 18-34 is enamored with text and social media. In general, we never make calls unless they’re really urgent, and even if we do, there’s a good chance no one will answer. According to the <em>Times</em>, leaving voicemails is a herculean task due to the lack of “formative experience leaving spoken or relayed messages over the phone.”</p>
<p dir="ltr">While it’s true that millennials are using the traditional phone less, so is the rest of America. A Vonage study shows that voicemail deposits dropped 8% between October 2013 and April 2014 (coincidentally, age brackets not included). The amount of people actually listening to voicemails fell 14% in that six month period.</p>
<p dir="ltr">There aren’t a lot more stone cold facts on the fall of voicemail, but there are some solid trends you can pick up on just by talking to a few friends:</p>
<ul>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">A lot of people don’t expect their voicemails to be listened to, partly because they aren’t even listening to their own messages.</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Most people call back instead of listening to messages, figuring the call itself was a big enough sign that they should call back.</p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">A decent amount of messages have gone unheard (I’ve got 12 on my phone. Sorry, Mom and Dad!)</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p dir="ltr">If <em>The New York Times</em> wants to assign blame for the fall of voicemail, there’s a prime suspect: text messaging. Now, I know what you’re thinking: millennials were early adopters, they’re digital natives, and they send twice as many texts as anyone else. That’s totally true.</p>
<p dir="ltr" style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/kyXQwsG0OL4415WLaST-O30_3xmrzMN9hOJuhHWqqUa5jiNltyARMwS-JWexLRq9Oif5mxZ8nyyEjYx1TIYLHc5juO-IVryQVXKbc7EmIf89UoFUhwpchbXClaqU-3EN2g" alt="" width="411px;" height="308px;" /></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="text-align: center;">Really, really true.</p>
<p dir="ltr">We love to text, probably way more than most. But just like voicemail, our increasing use of text echoes a larger trend in America. Pew Research reports that texting was the top activity of 2013, with 81% of people 18 and older using their phone to text. The average person also makes three calls and receives three calls a day, compared to 20-30 texts.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Texting has become popular because it’s shorter and faster, but also because it gets the same message across with a lot less effort. (It’s already pretty minimal effort to begin with, but I digress). When you get a voicemail, you have to enter your pin, open it and listen to it to find out what the call is about, then decide whether to call back or not. That is, if you ever check it at all: 37% of people hardly or never bother to check. Texts, on the other hand, send quickly and have a near immediate response time (unless you’re looking up cat pictures on your phone).</p>
<p dir="ltr">Even with texting on the rise, there’s still something to be said for voice communication. Over 50% of customers call turn to live agents in a contact center when they can’t figure their problem out with the help of technology. Why? Because that’s what they’re used to. The point here different customers prefer different communication channels. (You can read more about that here: <a href="http://www.icmi.com/Resources/Customer-Experience/2014/06/Ill-Tell-You-What-I-Want-What-I-Really-Really-Want">I’ll Tell You What I Want, What I Really, Really Want</a>.)</p>
<p dir="ltr">Traditional phone and voicemail had their day in the sun, but now texting is casting a pretty large shadow. Still, who’s to say the two can’t coexist? When you can combine the familiarity of voice with the reach of text, you’ve got something really powerful. That’s what we’re going for here at <a href="www.onereach.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">OneReach</a>.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Interested in learning more? Check out these other articles:</p>
<ul>
<li><a style="font-style: normal;" href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/?p=69" rel="bookmark">Appointment Reminders: Please Stop Calling Me</a></li>
<li><a style="font-style: normal;" href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/?p=197" rel="bookmark">95% of People Say They Don’t Text with Companies… But They’re Wrong.</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/call-me-maybe-a-millennial-perspective-on-the-decline-of-voicemail/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
