<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Interviews &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<atom:link href="https://onereach.ai/category/interviews/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<description>Intelligently Automate Your Company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 11:39:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/cropped-OR-ICON-GOLD-W-DOTS-Larger-Background-02-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Interviews &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Forrester: 10% of U.S. jobs will be lost to automation in 2019</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/forrester_jobs/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 17:56:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Learning about AI and Bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OmniChannel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Phone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-popular]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-recent]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://onereach.ai/?p=5249</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Raconteur explores how bots are changing the role of Chief Financial Officers (CFO) and their corresponding departments [...]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">VentureBeat’s recent article on Forrester’s latest report on artificial intelligence brings up some interesting points. There is often talk of the gloom and doom that AI will bring on, especially in terms of eliminating key jobs through automation. There is no doubt that AI is going to have a massive impact on the way businesses operate, but what does this new future look like?</span></p>
<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-4588 size-large" src="https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-1024x725.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="725" srcset="https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-1024x725.jpg 1024w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-300x212.jpg 300w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-768x543.jpg 768w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-150x106.jpg 150w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-600x425.jpg 600w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-900x637.jpg 900w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-20x13.jpg 20w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-340x240.jpg 340w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p><b>The rise of digital workers</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Firstly, companies and startups alike are going to see an increase in digital workers created by robotic process automation (RPA) and AI. An increasing number of businesses are looking to scale at faster levels than before, and are going to be searching for solutions that can automate and optimize tasks traditionally done by humans. </span></p>
<p><b>Automation is all about giving and taking</b></p>
<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-2433 size-large" src="https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-1024x463.png" alt="" width="1024" height="463" srcset="https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-1024x463.png 1024w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-768x348.png 768w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-300x136.png 300w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-1200x544.png 1200w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-20x9.png 20w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-150x68.png 150w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-600x272.png 600w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-900x407.png 900w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai.png 1202w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Automation tends to be associated with loss of jobs, and while this holds true in Forrester’s findings, that is not the whole story. 2019 will see roughly 10% of US jobs eliminated due to automation, but that same automation will also </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">create</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> about 3% of today’s jobs.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, this new increase in automation has bigger implications down the line. As companies begin to fully scale operations to keep up with the rest, it means the marketplace for AI solutions is going to be fiercely competitive. A Deloitte survey currently posits the annual global growth rate for AI-as-a-serve at 48.2%, with no signs of slowing down. This ripple effect then bleeds into other business areas, such as recruitment for AI talent, as businesses look for ways to retain their edge. Forrester’s survey posits that this search for talent will lead to “unprecedented job match success rates.”</span></p>
<p><b>Use cases you need to know about</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Forrester’s research points to four use cases wherein businesses see a real return on investment: </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Analytics that solve platform issues</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chatbots integrated with RPA bots</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Internet-of-things (IoT) events that trigger “digital workers”</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Text analytics that organize unstructured data into “clean files” for RPA software.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Spot some commonalities? These use cases all point towards the future of AI &#8212; intelligent automation. Rather than strip away necessary jobs, AI is being used to free up employee time from rote tasks, and increase overall job satisfaction. These solutions are able to bridge the gap between menial tasks and human expertise, rather than limit the personal touch. According to the report, ML’s [machine learning] strength is data. Knowledge engineering’s strength is human wisdom. Used together, enterprises can dramatically accelerate the development of AI applications.</span><b>”</b></p>
<p>Read the full article <a href="https://venturebeat.com/2018/11/06/forrester-10-of-u-s-jobs-will-be-lost-to-automation-in-2019/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 Global CFO’s Say Goodbye &#8211; Bots &#038; Blockchain Take-Over</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/science_behind_hold-2/</link>
				<pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 00:15:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Robb]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OmniChannel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Phone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-recent]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://onereach.ai/?p=1959</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Raconteur explores how bots are changing the role of Chief Financial Officers (CFO) and their corresponding departments [...]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Technology is developing at speeds that were previously unheard of, and as a result artificial intelligence (AI) is changing the face of business.</strong> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In <a href="https://www.raconteur.net/finance/goodbye-cfo-bots-and-blockchain-are-taking-over-soon">a recent Raconteur article by Jon Card</a>, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Goodbye CFO? Bots and blockchain are taking over soon </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Card explores how bots are changing the role of Chief Financial Officer (CFO) and their corresponding departments. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tim Briant (Airswift), Sankar Narayan (Xero), and Todd Ford (Coupa) shared what has changed within their companies, and what changes they expect to see in the future. From complete automation lacking a human touch, to changing the way companies analyze information, AI looks to have a significant impact on how companies will operate in the future. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tim Briant is not at all conservative in how he anticipates AI impacting business. Card wrote that Briant believes that AI is going to replace people completely. Briant cites his previous employment (as CFO at Adecco) as an example for how businesses will automate in the future. At Adecco many processes are already automated. At Airswift they are planning on implementing their own changes, by investing in bots. In a similar way to which humans learn, bots can do so as well. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>This ability to learn is what puts future accounting jobs at risk for humans.</strong> With the cost of technology dropping, it may one day become cheaper to have bots (who are able to learn from their mistakes) that are able to do the work (24 hours a day) than it would be to have humans doing the same work 8 hours a day.  According to Card, Briant believes that between AI technology and blockchain (a system that stores data in a public and accessible way – making it impossible for hackers to hack) there will not be a need for companies to retain a Chief Financial Officer in the future. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Card found an alternate point of view while interviewing Sankar Narayan of Xero. Narayan does not necessarily have the same doom and gloom type attitude that Briant has. Instead, Narayan seems exceptionally optimistic by what technology is able to offer, especially in terms of what it is doing for his current business.  </span></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-4557" src="https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/chris-liverani-552652-unsplash-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/chris-liverani-552652-unsplash-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/chris-liverani-552652-unsplash-300x225.jpg 300w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/chris-liverani-552652-unsplash-768x576.jpg 768w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/chris-liverani-552652-unsplash-150x112.jpg 150w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/chris-liverani-552652-unsplash-600x450.jpg 600w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/chris-liverani-552652-unsplash-900x675.jpg 900w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/chris-liverani-552652-unsplash-20x16.jpg 20w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Narayan has found that the role of CFO is taking on a more analytical position than it has in the past, but that is because of the massive amounts of data that they have at their fingertips</strong>. Boasting that he essentially knows exactly how much growth his company has experienced over any given time, Narayan seems to embrace what technology offers his company. However, Narayan wasn’t always this easy going in terms of AI. He’s been a CFO for over 17 years, which means he has had to see his position grown and change in order to stay relevant. Narayan believes that using artificial intelligence in business will be about more than efficiency in the future, and will instead help determine what decisions will make the company more profitable. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Todd Ford, of Coupa, is another CFO doomsayer. According to Card, Ford recognizes that with the advances in AI, the role of CFO may become obsolete.</strong> Though not necessarily as unforgiving as Briant, Ford recognizes that things have already changed significantly in the field. Humans are now competing with bots. Ford’s solution is to become more than just an accountant, he is also skilled in sales and marketing. This enables him to combine his two knowledge bases, and makes him more valuable. Card states that Mr. Ford sees the CFO position as one that consists of both chief accounting officer, as well as chief operations officer. It is Ford’s assumption that the CFO position will disappear in favor of a chief accounting officer and a chief operations officer, as those two skillsets don’t always coincide. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These three men are at the top of their field, and area already starting to see changes in terms of how AI has changed their business. With this constantly evolving landscape, it offers a plethora of opportunity, especially to businesses. However, accountants in the field will need to find a way to ensure that they stay relevant despite changes in the future. For some, this raises more questions than it does provide answers. Even so, bots offer many benefits that human counterparts cannot: longer work hours, reduced risk of human error, and the ability to provide analysis almost instantaneously. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These reasons alone make AI development worth a risk. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
