<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Government &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<atom:link href="https://onereach.ai/category/government/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<description>Intelligently Automate Your Company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 11:39:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/cropped-OR-ICON-GOLD-W-DOTS-Larger-Background-02-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Government &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Clinton Uses Texting and Voice To Attack Sanders</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/clinton-uses-texting-and-voice-to-attack-sanders/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/clinton-uses-texting-and-voice-to-attack-sanders/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Use Cases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/clinton-uses-texting-and-voice-to-attack-sanders/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/election-texting-post/">We&#8217;ve written before</a> about how texting could be used for political campaigns. You could use it for voter registration, voting day reminders, or even to set up a text hotline to get real-time feedback on what&#8217;s going on at polling places.</p>
<p>But now we can add a new texting use case to the list: attack ads.</p>
<p><span id="more-7393"></span>BuzzFeed News Reporter Evan McMorris-Santoro <a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/evanmcsan/clinton-uses-presidents-day-to-accuse-sanders-of-disloyalty#.hroMQE3RY">had a firsthand experience</a> with this texting use case. He received a text message from the Clinton campaign touting her support of Barack Obama and calling out &#8220;someone&#8221; who didn&#8217;t support Obama.</p>
<p>When Evan texted back the word HEAR to learn more, he got an automated call from the Hillary campaign with a soundbite of her supporting one of Obama&#8217;s decisions and Bernie Sanders opposing him. After the call, it ended with a text saying Hillary was the only one who would continue Obama&#8217;s legacy.</p>
<p>This is definitely a unique texting use case, not only for its message but for its use of two communication channels to get that message across. I won&#8217;t get into politics here, but I commend Clinton for using two powerful communication channels together to interact with her base and deliver a one-on-one experience that other channels can&#8217;t.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/evanmcsan/clinton-uses-presidents-day-to-accuse-sanders-of-disloyalty#.hroMQE3RY">Check out the full article on BuzzFeed</a>, and don&#8217;t forget to <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/10-things-about-text">download our whitepaper</a> on the 10 things you need to know when adding texting to your business.</strong></p>
<p><em>The opinions expressed here are solely that of the contributor and don&#8217;t necessarily represent the views of OneReach.</em></p>
<p>Photo by Flickr user <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/cornstalker/23575629583/">Matt A.J</a>. <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/">CC2.0 License</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/clinton-uses-texting-and-voice-to-attack-sanders/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>OneReach Helps Power City of Evanston&#8217;s Restaurant Inspection Text Messages</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/onereach-helps-power-city-of-evanstons-restaurant-inspection-text-messages/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/onereach-helps-power-city-of-evanstons-restaurant-inspection-text-messages/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Big Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ITR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Use Cases]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/onereach-helps-power-city-of-evanstons-restaurant-inspection-text-messages/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The city of Evanston, Ill. has worked with OneReach to provide residents with the ability to check the health inspection scores of local restaurants over text.</p>
<p><span id="more-7369"></span>Diners can text the keyword &#8220;food&#8221; to the city&#8217;s 311 number, and then text the name of the restaurant to see the health inspection score, as well as the date the inspection took place.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.govtech.com/health/Texting-Helps-in-Fight-Against-Foodborne-Illnesses-in-Evanston-Ill.html">Government Technology</a> points out that the use of texting makes getting restaurant scores a lot easier for consumers:</p>
<blockquote><p>It’s simple and much easier than Yelp’s mobile app, which compels users to tap and swipe their way to a restaurant’s “More Info” tab and deep dive through a list of miscellaneous information.</p></blockquote>
<p>The food safety text initiative follows the city&#8217;s initiative to local restaurant inspection scores onto Yelp.</p>
<p><strong>Check out the full article on <a href="http://www.govtech.com/health/Texting-Helps-in-Fight-Against-Foodborne-Illnesses-in-Evanston-Ill.html">Government Technology</a>, and don&#8217;t forget to <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/high-demand-for-text-message-2014-report">download our report</a> on why 64% of customers would rather text than call your business. </strong></p>
<p>Image credit: <a href="https://pixabay.com/en/iphone-5s-cafe-office-apple-hand-1114403/">dangquocbuu</a>. CC0 license. Edited.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/onereach-helps-power-city-of-evanstons-restaurant-inspection-text-messages/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Can You Text Your City?</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/can-you-text-your-city/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/can-you-text-your-city/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Big Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Use Cases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[text your city]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/can-you-text-your-city/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Can you text your city? You could if you lived in <a href="http://www.cityofevanston.org/">Evanston, Ill.</a></p>
<p>Just north of Chicago, Evanston is one of the most tech-savvy cities in the country. Ever since they launched long code texting a couple of months ago, they’ve been able to reach out to community members as well as allow the community to reach out to their city.</p>
<p>Luke Stowe, digital services coordinator at the <a href="http://www.cityofevanston.org/">City of Evanston</a>, spoke with <a href="http://www.onereach.com">OneReach</a> to talk about how texting is transforming their community outreach efforts.</p>
<h2><span id="more-7156"></span><b>First Time Isn’t Always a Charm</b></h2>
<p>Evanston is a city ahead of the curve. They introduced shortcode texting as early as 2012, asking citizens to text the word “Evanston” to 311311 with questions or concerns.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, things didn’t go exactly as projected.</p>
<p>“It was a little bit clunky for people to use,” admits Stowe. “It didn’t get the adoption we were anticipating.”</p>
<p>Stowe cites a difficult-to-remember short code and having to send a keyword as factors that deterred constituents. He also said people weren’t sure how to text a short code, and that it looked unusual compared to a regular 10-digit phone number.</p>
<p>“It never quite took off,” says Stowe. “We asked ourselves, ‘Are there other ways?’”</p>
<p>Luckily for Evanston, there were.</p>
<h2><b> Truly Out and About</b></h2>
<p>After working with OneReach on a long code text messaging program, Evanston quietly launched their new system in late summer. Residents can text the city’s 10-digit 311 phone number (847-448-4311) no matter whether they are.</p>
<p>Stowe says they’ve already had dozens of text messages come in to 311, and he thinks he knows why: people want to report events as they’re happening.</p>
<p>“Being able to SMS directly to 311 is even more real-time than web chat,” says Stowe. “Web chat could be about an issue that has already occurred, but with texting you’re truly out and about in the city.”</p>
<p>Evanston believes text messaging is helping the city better respond to events in real-time.</p>
<p>“The other day, someone sent a text message saying there were a couple of cars parked illegally,” says Stowe. “They were texting in the moment, at that particular place, and 311 was able to immediately assist them.”</p>
<h2><b>How You Can Text Your City</b></h2>
<p>So far, Evanston has been using SMS for both inbound and outbound messaging. Citizens can opt-in to receive emergency notifications, or they can text in to report issues or ask about different events in the city.</p>
<p>But that’s not all Evanston is capable of doing with texting. They also use texting for:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Outbound messages</strong> – Traffic updates, snow alerts, beach status updates</li>
<li><strong>Inbound messages</strong> – Report broken traffic lights, inquire about park activities</li>
<li><strong>Surveying their residents</strong> to help improve services</li>
<li><strong>Automated updates</strong> on events like such as art fairs, festivals, concerts, etc.</li>
</ul>
<h2><b>Back to the Future</b></h2>
<p>Texting may be about 20 years old, but Stowe thinks its staying power will contribute to its success.</p>
<p>“This technology has been around for a while,” says Stowe. “I think it’s safe to say that SMS texting isn’t going anywhere anytime soon.”</p>
<p>Still, the city has a few ideas about updating text for a modern audience.  “We’ve been working with our restaurant inspection software vendor on setting up a OneReach number provided by Twilio,” says Stowe. “We want to create something where residents could text a restaurant name to the 311 phone number and it would send the latest inspection score.”</p>
<p>The city also recently went live with restaurant inspection in the popular app and website Yelp.</p>
<p>“It’s ‘Web 3.0’, where you get the right content at the right time on the right device, like when you’re walking into a restaurant and want to see inspection scores,” says Stowe.</p>
<h2><b> On Being One of a Kind</b></h2>
<p>Evanston is part the growing trend of cities offering a 311 service, joining the ranks of bigger cities such as New York and Minneapolis. However, Evanston is one of only a handful of cities in the U.S. that has live 311 operators responding to a customer’s text message.</p>
<p>“As far as true, live texting with 311 services, I have only initially found New York City as the other comparable agency offering a similar service,” said Stowe.  Despite the rather open texting frontier (for now), Stowe thinks more cities will adopt texting going forward.</p>
<p>“I think in government, we have a responsibility to go where our residents are.  If they prefer to text, call, web chat, use social media or email — we will respond.”</p>
<p><i>Interested in text-enabling your own city? Visit </i><a href="http://onereach.com/"><i>onereach.com</i></a><i> to learn more.</i></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/can-you-text-your-city/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
