<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>artificial intelligence in business &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<atom:link href="https://onereach.ai/tag/artificial-intelligence-in-business/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<description>Intelligently Automate Your Company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 11:39:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/cropped-OR-ICON-GOLD-W-DOTS-Larger-Background-02-32x32.png</url>
	<title>artificial intelligence in business &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Weekly Review: 5/31 Edition</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/weekly-review-5-31-edition/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/weekly-review-5-31-edition/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence in business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer service]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/weekly-review-5-31-edition/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Happy Friday! Here’s our picks for the best customer service, customer experience, bot and mobile articles of the week, in no particular order.</p>
<h2><span id="more-7434"></span></h2>
<h2><a href="http://www.cmswire.com/customer-experience/combine-ai-and-the-human-touch-for-exceptional-customer-service/">Combine AI and the Human Touch for Exceptional Customer Service</a>&#8211;<strong> by <a href="https://twitter.com/Chris_HGS">Chris Lord</a></strong></h2>
<p>Customer service has evolved a lot in the past few decades. Support interactions used to be limited to just a phone call, but now customers can reach a company over email, social media and even text message. Self-service is an option to make customers’ lives easier, but it&#8217;s not a substitute for good customer service.</p>
<h2></h2>
<h2><strong>Au<a href="http://www.1to1media.com/view.aspx?docid=35796&amp;utm_content=title&amp;utm_source=1to1weekly&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=05232016">tomate or Humanize</a>&#8211; by <a href="http://twitter.com/JudithAquino">Judith Aquino</a> </strong></h2>
<p>As technology continues to advance, machines will be able to carry out a big number of tasks normally handled by humans. Businesses should really prioritize where robots are best used vs humans who have innovated solutions.</p>
<h2><strong><a href="https://www.b2bmarketing.net/resources/blog/why-sms-your-most-powerful-b2b-marketing-tool">Why SMS is your most Powerful B2B Marketing Tool</a> by Roxanne Abercrombie </strong></h2>
<p>It&#8217;s really pretty simple, SMS is the easiest and quickest way to get your information in front of your consumer. If you&#8217;re not using text messaging in your business you might be missing one of the most valuable tools in marketing.</p>
<h2></h2>
<h2 class="alpha tweet-title"><a href="http://Nearly 1 in 4 people abandon mobile apps after only one use">Nearly 1 in 4 people abandon mobile apps after only one use</a>&#8211; by <a href="https://twitter.com/sarahintampa">Sarah Perez </a></h2>
<p class="alpha tweet-title">At OneReach, we’ve worked with many consumers who are in high demand for customer service via text messaging. As reseach shows, apps are expensive to drive adoption, not used much and deleted after one time use.</p>
<h2><strong>To learn more about providing a great customer experience across channels, <a href="https://onereach.com/resources/omnichannel-seamless-experience">download our whitepaper here</a>. </strong></h2>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/weekly-review-5-31-edition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>If You Had Your Own J.A.R.V.I.S.: What Artificial Intelligence In Business Might Be Like</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/if-you-had-your-own-j-a-r-v-i-s-what-artificial-intelligence-in-business-might-be-like/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/if-you-had-your-own-j-a-r-v-i-s-what-artificial-intelligence-in-business-might-be-like/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Big Data & Analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Big Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence in business]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/if-you-had-your-own-j-a-r-v-i-s-what-artificial-intelligence-in-business-might-be-like/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What’s the coolest part of the </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Iron Man </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">movies? The elaborate fight scenes? The dream team-ups? Tony Stark’s acerbic wit?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At <a href="onereach.com">OneReach</a>, some of us think the coolest part of the </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Iron Man</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> movies is the artificial intelligence that helps power Tony Stark’s armor and business operations. That’s right—we’re talking about J.A.R.V.I.S., Tony’s occasionally sassy but always helpful personal assistant/user interface.</span></p>
<p><span id="more-7268"></span></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1869" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/artificial-intelligence-in-business.gif" alt="artificial intelligence in business" width="500" height="250" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Virtual assistant services like Magic and GoButler already exist, but requests are all managed by real people on the other end. And while there are services like My Second that incorporate artificial intelligence into their service offering, there’s nothing on the level of J.A.R.V.I.S.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yet.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Siri is probably the most ubiquitous example of artificially intelligent personal assistant, but she’s more of a recommendation engine than true AI. Similarly, Echo, Amazon’s sparkling new home automation assistant, can only respond to simple voice commands. However, Echo’s functionality is beefed up once you add in the fact that Echo can connect to other apps to access their capabilities.</span></p>
<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KkOCeAtKHIc" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But what happens when AI technology reaches the realms of sci-fi? It won’t just slightly change how we do things—it’ll dramatically transform the way we live and work.</span></p>
<h1><b>Artificial Intelligence in Daily Life</b></h1>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Having a digital personal assistant would make life so much easier. Small tasks would get taken care of without a thought, and big tasks would be aided with insightful input. We already connect to the Internet, but AI would integrate it into our daily lives.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For example, let’s say you have an AI like Echo that connects not just to other apps, but to the Internet of Things. After you go for a run, your FitBit would connect to your AI with your exercise statistics. You could then ask Echo what you should have for breakfast, and, after connecting to your smart fridge to see what food is available and reviewing your exercise statistics, would suggest an egg white omelet with tomatoes and mushrooms.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And, just like in the video, an AI digital assistant would make search queries easier than ever. AIs today can only answer simple search queries (ie “Find a restaurant near me”) but in the future, through the use of Natural Language Understanding (NLU) and other technologies, they’ll be able to answer complex, contextual questions. In fact, IBM Watson is already on its way there.</span></p>
<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/P18EdAKuC1U" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<h1><strong>Artificial Intelligence in Business</strong></h1>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Watson and Echo may not have J.A.R.V.I.S-level intelligence yet, but companies can still utilize AI technology in a meaningful way. In fact, companies are already using AI in the form of automation for call routing, automated replies, personalization, and more.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While humans can sometimes be biased and limited by their own knowledge, AI could compensate for human limitations by doing something that many of us can’t: taking a huge amount of information, analyzing it, and boiling it down to a few different options &#8211; quickly.</span></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1871" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/choices.gif" alt="choices" width="245" height="200" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But let’s put it into practice. For example, let’s say you added Echo’s capabilities to your call center tomorrow. If people text in and 80% of them select option 5, AIs like Echo can shift option 5 to the first option to better meet customer needs. AIs can also provide canned responses to agents so that they can not only respond to customer questions quickly, but also track agent-customer interactions.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Alternatively, if 80% of customers are calling in about outages, AI can pretty accurately guess what customers are calling in for. It can analyze input and responses quickly, then learn from that for future interactions.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But what would AI look like on J.A.R.V.I.S.’s level?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">AI would be able to pull customer information up in an instant, review past interactions, and determine that you’re probably calling because your printer’s lifetime warranty has expired and it’s no longer working. If that wasn’t the correct response, the AI digital assistant would observe and learn from agent interactions over a series of calls and track probable causes or anticipate trends. For example, if five people call about a broken printer, the AI could inform the agent that that’s what calls are most likely about and what the broken part is.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite all that AI is capable of, there will always be a need for human interaction, because some customers will prefer it. And while AI is very good at repeating information, there’s nothing like a human touch to get someone through a difficult conversation (although some people might prefer AI).</span></p>
<h1><b>Conclusion</b></h1>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">AI is a powerfully transformative tool that will be responsible for changing our personal and professional lives. It’s a somewhat frightening proposition, almost too fathom.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Luckily, we’ve got something to explain it to us.</span></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1870" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/ignore.gif" alt="ignore" width="245" height="191" /></p>
<p><strong>To learn more about providing a great, automated customer experience across channels, <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/omnichannel-seamless-experience">download our whitepaper here</a>.</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://pixshark.com/iron-man-interface.htm">Header image</a>, <a href="http://studyinstyle.tumblr.com/post/105386550258/my-ask-box-is-open-for-finals-week-and-christmas">Gif 1</a>, <a href="http://super--wolf.tumblr.com/post/116613821651/randomfandom-imagines-spencer-reid-tony-stark">Gif 2</a> and <a href="http://rebloggy.com/post/gifs-robert-downey-jr-tony-stark-iron-man-3-rdjgifs/67370843094">Gif 3</a> credit.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/if-you-had-your-own-j-a-r-v-i-s-what-artificial-intelligence-in-business-might-be-like/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
