<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>How To &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<atom:link href="https://onereach.ai/category/how-to/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<description>Intelligently Automate Your Company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 11:39:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/cropped-OR-ICON-GOLD-W-DOTS-Larger-Background-02-32x32.png</url>
	<title>How To &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How to Get Customers to Text Your Business</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/how-to-get-customers-to-text-your-business/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/how-to-get-customers-to-text-your-business/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/how-to-get-customers-to-text-your-business/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><b></b><span style="font-weight: 400;">You’ve heard all about the <a href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/5-benefits-of-business-texting/">benefits of text messaging for business</a>—</span><a href="http://digitalmarketingmagazine.co.uk/mobile-digital-marketing/7-key-statistics-for-sms-marketing/558"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">text has a 98% open rate compared to 20% for email</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">,</span><a href="http://www.tatango.com/blog/90-of-text-messages-are-read-within-3-minutes/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">90% of texts are read within three minutes</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, etc. In addition,</span><a href="http://onereach.com/resources/high-demand-for-text-message-2014-report"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">64% of customers want to text your business</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">All that’s great. You love it. But how do you actually do it?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’ll show you how.</span></p>
<h2><span id="more-7350"></span><b>How do I get a text-enabled number for my business?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s pretty easy to get a text-enabled number for your business—the real question here is whether or not you want a short code or a long code.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are two types of short codes: </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">dedicated</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which means you have full rights to use it; and </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">shared</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which means different companies can send and receive on the same short code (managed by keywords that the user has to text in).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For long codes, you can own a number which means that you can transfer it and hold on to it without the risk of it being revoked. All numbers are dedicated, which means you control all traffic. Businesses can add text messaging services to their existing phone numbers even if they haven’t used it previously.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Below is a breakdown of the benefits and drawbacks associated with short codes and long codes.</span></p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td><b>Short codes</b></td>
<td><b>Long codes</b></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><b>Traditional use</b></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Marketing</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Transactional messages</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><b>Cost</b></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">$1,200-$2,000/month</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">$1-$2/month (U.S.), up to $100/month (international)</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><b>Volume</b></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">No limitations on number per second, unless provider limits</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">1 message/second local, 3 messages/second toll-free</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><b>Vanity</b></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yes, 466453 spells “GOOGLE”</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yes, 1-800-336-8478 spells “1-800-DENTIST”</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><b>Voice</b></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">No</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yes</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><b>Ability to respond</b></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yes</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yes</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><b>Geography</b></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Restricted to country of origin (U.S. short codes can only be used in U.S.)</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">International use</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><b>Purposes</b></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Large-scale marketing campaigns or text notifications, pure automation</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">More conversational, but the use has expanded to automated, personalized responses like checking balances, resetting passwords, etc.</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><b>Regulation</b></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Regulated by boards in each country. In the U.S., the CTIA governs their use, including strict opt-in/opt-out rules. Failure to comply means your short code can be revoked.</span></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Long codes are not currently regulated, but mass marketing blasts are frowned upon by carriers and can be blocked. Staying with 1:1 conversations or automation keeps clear from breaking autodialer opt-in rules.</span></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Once you’ve decided on the type of number you want, the rest is fairly straightforward. All you have to do is reach out to a provider that can text-enable your current number, or a new number. There are several providers on the market, including but not limited to <a href="http://twilio.com">Twilio</a>, <a href="http://zipwhip.com">Zipwhip</a> and <a href="http://nexmo.com">Nexmo</a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So you’ve added the option for customers to text your business. Now what?</span></p>
<h2><b>How do I promote my text-enabled number?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">People know your brand is on Twitter. People don’t know your brand is on SMS. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After you’ve chosen your business texting number, you need to promote its existence to customers. This is where you can lean on your existing channels, like your website, social media, and IVR, and email. You can also go old school and print flyers or business cards with your text number on it. Alternatively, if you have the budget for it, you can promote your text-enabled number on TV or over the radio. If you’re trying to drive more text sign ups, you can also hold a contest or offer an incentive and promote it on all of your existing channels.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Whatever channels you decide to use will need to include the following to be compliant with</span><a href="http://www.mmaglobal.com/files/uploads/Consumer-Best-Practices.pdf"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">CTIA guidelines</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Product description</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Program name</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Product quantity</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Link to full terms and conditions containing privacy policy and help information</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">STOP instructions (in bold, for recurring only)</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Additional carrier costs disclosure (Message and data rates may apply)</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When a customer opts in to a text messaging program, the company must also meet the above conditions in their introductory text message. (For recurring and one-time messages, you don’t need to include STOP instructions or the “Message and data rates may apply” message).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Promoting your new text message channel is proven to get results and increase engagement. Shedd Aquarium drove </span><b><a href="http://www.mobilemarketer.com/cms/news/messaging/4299.html">325% more event sign ups</a></b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> with a text message CTA than a web CTA in television advertisements. </span></p>
<h2><b>What to do once you’ve got customers’ contact information</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Once you’ve got subscribers’ contact information, it’s time to break them down into segments. This could be by product, promotion, sign up date—any segment that you think of that would help you better serve your customers. One of the best ways to segment customers is to ask them what kind of content they’d like to receive. You can do this through surveys, interviews or focus groups. Text messaging is a great channel for surveys, however, garnering a <a href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/45-texting-statistics-that-prove-businesses-need-to-start-taking-sms-seriously/">45% response rate on average</a>. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Once you’ve segmented customers, you can then deliver targeted messages that are more likely to be engaged with. You can also draw from reports to see what messages/calls to action get the best response rates, then build off of those for increasingly targeted messaging.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ultimately,</span><a href="https://blog.udemy.com/benefits-of-market-segmentation/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">market segmentation</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is a great way to retain customers. And, considering it’s <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/tjmccue/2013/02/04/warning-is-your-new-customer-coming-back-4-steps-you-should-take-now/">6 to 7 times more expensive</a> to attract a new customer than to maintain an existing one, it’s also a great way to lower costs.</span></p>
<h2><b>Conclusion</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Getting a text-enabled number is easy, but getting a customer to actually </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">text</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> your business takes a little more effort. By taking advantage of existing channels to promote texting to new prospects, you’ll be able to drive more business, cut costs and increase engagement.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And who doesn’t want that?</span></p>
<p><strong>Want to learn more about business texting? D</strong><strong>ownload our 2014 Harris Poll report detailing why <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/high-demand-for-text-message-2014-report">64% of customers want to text your business</a>.</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://il7.picdn.net/shutterstock/videos/6510437/thumb/1.jpg?i10c=img.resize(height:160)">Photo credit</a>. Edited.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/how-to-get-customers-to-text-your-business/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Provide Great Customer Service Across the Globe</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/how-to-provide-great-customer-service-across-the-globe/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/how-to-provide-great-customer-service-across-the-globe/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Customer Experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Satisfaction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How To]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/how-to-provide-great-customer-service-across-the-globe/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There are 7.125 billion people in the world. Each person is a unique, complex individual with their own likes and dislikes. Unfortunately, less than 50% of global businesses offer personalized customer service, despite a desire from <a href="https://www.avaya.com/usa/documents/media-summary-for-avaya-cem-global-november-2014.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">70% of customers</a>. And while <a href="https://www.avaya.com/usa/documents/media-summary-for-avaya-cem-global-november-2014.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">69% of customers</a> expect businesses to link communication channels together in real time, only 38% of businesses offer that.</p>
<p>However, there’s an inherent danger in generalizing global customer service, partly because expectations vary from country to country. For example, in Japan, customers experience <em><a href="http://www.wsj.com/articles/SB10001424052702303456104579489824193262260" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">omotenashi</a></em>, or the absolute dedication of service to a customer and their needs. In South Africa, customer service employees are expected adhere to the principles of <a href="http://www.tourism.gov.za/AboutNDT/Publications/tourism%20report%20final%2028%20january%202011_22%20march.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Batho Pele</a> (People First), which include high levels of courtesy and service standards. But in Eastern Europe, customer service representatives view service as more of transaction than a relationship, <a href="http://www.berlitz.com.uy/SiteData/docs/BerlitzCul/691862a1aef0a178/Berlitz_Culture&amp;CustomerServiceExperience.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">putting customers on hold</a> without asking and addressing customers in a direct manner.</p>
<p>But meeting cultural expectations is just one of the many challenges of global customer service.</p>
<p><span id="more-7250"></span>Listed below are some of the common challenges global customers face, along with a solution to each of them.</p>
<h1>Challenge: Response time and resolution</h1>
<p>If there’s one universal customer service complaint, it’s waiting on hold. <a href="http://www.parature.com/2013-customer-expectations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Over 60% of global customers</a> are frustrated by waiting on hold for a long time, but what constitutes a long time will vary from country to country:</p>
<ul>
<li>Less than half of <a href="https://d16cvnquvjw7pr.cloudfront.net/resources/whitepapers/Omnichannel-Customer-Service-Gap.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">German customers</a> think response times are “good” or “excellent.”</li>
<li><a href="https://d16cvnquvjw7pr.cloudfront.net/resources/whitepapers/Omnichannel-Customer-Service-Gap.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">French customers </a>think their phone calls should be answered immediately. In fact, <a href="https://d16cvnquvjw7pr.cloudfront.net/resources/whitepapers/Omnichannel-Customer-Service-Gap.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">73% of French consumers</a> expect an immediate response on any channel, and they expect their problem to be solved then and there.</li>
<li><a href="https://d16cvnquvjw7pr.cloudfront.net/resources/whitepapers/Omnichannel-Customer-Service-Gap.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Brazilian customers</a> have high standards that appear to be met—81% think the speed of response is either “good” or “excellent,” and 82% rate resolution the same way.</li>
<li>Only 35% of British consumers are satisfied with the speed of response, and only 36% are satisfied with resolution</li>
<li><a href="http://www.itweb.co.za/index.php?option=com_content&amp;view=article&amp;id=67603" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">South African customers </a>expect an answer to their phone call in under three minutes.</li>
<li><a href="https://d16cvnquvjw7pr.cloudfront.net/resources/whitepapers/Omnichannel-Customer-Service-Gap.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Only 30% of Japanese customers</a> expect an answer right away, compared to a global average of 50%.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Solution: Automation and time-based routing to other agents</h2>
<p>As listed above, many global customers expect answers to their questions almost immediately. When they receive poor service, <a href="http://trendwatching.com/trends/future-customer-service/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">66% of global consumers</a> will stop doing business one brand and switch to another. However, agents are only available so many hours in a day, and not all calls may require human intervention. Automated time-based routing can immediately direct callers to other available agents. Alternatively, automation provides customers with the option to self-serve, which <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/stevenvanbelleghem/the-self-serving-economy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">40% of customers</a> would prefer. Either way, an automated communication solution ensures customers get the answers they need when they need it.</p>
<h1>Challenge: Channel preference</h1>
<p>You might think phone would be the preferred international communication channel, but that’s not the case.<a href="https://www.avaya.com/usa/documents/media-summary-for-avaya-cem-global-november-2014.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Over 35%</a> of European consumers think the phone delivers the worst customer experience, and about <a href="http://www.lithium.com/company/news-room/press-releases/2014/extreme-customer-expectations-have-gone-global" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">two-thirds of American</a>, British and Australian customers will only use the phone as a last resort. In fact, several other countries use other customer service channels:</p>
<ul>
<li>While most Australian customers (59%) use the phone, they also use <a href="https://d16cvnquvjw7pr.cloudfront.net/resources/whitepapers/Omnichannel-Customer-Service-Gap.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">alternative channels</a> like self-service (33%) and live chat (21%).</li>
<li><a href="https://d16cvnquvjw7pr.cloudfront.net/resources/whitepapers/Omnichannel-Customer-Service-Gap.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Over 60% of Brazilians</a> will try any channel available to get their problem solved quickly.</li>
<li><a href="https://d16cvnquvjw7pr.cloudfront.net/resources/whitepapers/Omnichannel-Customer-Service-Gap.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Over half of Japanese customers</a> would be willing to use self-service channels to solve their problem.</li>
<li><a href="http://graphics.eiu.com/upload/customerservice_DHL.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">81% of Asian consumers</a> like to resolve problems online.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.itweb.co.za/index.php?option=com_content&amp;view=article&amp;id=67603" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">South Africans</a> prefer phone calls when interacting with a contact center.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Solution: Engage with customers using SMS</h2>
<p>A study conducted by Harris Poll and commissioned by OneReach found that <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/high-demand-for-text-message-2014-report" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">64% of American consumers</a>would rather text than call for customer service. While the poll was strictly limited to the United States, the use of and preference for text message spans across the world. Over 75% of cell phone owners worldwide use text messaging, and for some of the poorest countries in the world, texting is the most used feature on their phone. Although global restrictions may vary, the high usage of SMS and the global preference for any channel other than phone make SMS a strong, affordable global customer service channel.</p>
<h1>Challenge: Consistency across channels and agents</h1>
<p>Another global service complaint is having to repeat problems. Over 65% of customers are frustrated by having to contact a company multiple times for the same reason, and 55% are frustrated by having to repeat their problem to multiple agents across multiple channels.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://d16cvnquvjw7pr.cloudfront.net/resources/whitepapers/Omnichannel-Customer-Service-Gap.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">German customers</a> expect a unified approach to customer service.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.itweb.co.za/index.php?option=com_content&amp;view=article&amp;id=67603" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Almost 90% of South Africans</a> are frustrated by being transferred multiple times (much higher than the global average of 66%), and 64% are frustrated by having to repeat themselves to multiple agents.</li>
<li><a href="https://d16cvnquvjw7pr.cloudfront.net/resources/whitepapers/Omnichannel-Customer-Service-Gap.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Nearly half of French customers</a> (48%) expect to be able to reach the same agent regardless of channel.</li>
<li><a href="https://d16cvnquvjw7pr.cloudfront.net/resources/whitepapers/Omnichannel-Customer-Service-Gap.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">80% of Britons</a> think companies are focused on selling across multiple channels than providing a seamless experience for customers.</li>
<li><a href="https://d16cvnquvjw7pr.cloudfront.net/resources/whitepapers/Omnichannel-Customer-Service-Gap.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Over 40% of Australian customers</a> think they should be able to contact the same agent regardless of channel.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Solution: Automatic updates.</h2>
<p><a href="https://d16cvnquvjw7pr.cloudfront.net/resources/whitepapers/Omnichannel-Customer-Service-Gap.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Almost 90% of global customers</a> think companies should provide an omnichannel experience, meaning that they should be able to switch between channels and agents without losing context. With a cloud-based communication platform that automatically updates, service agents will be able to see the person a customer last talked to and the last channel they used, then pick up the conversation where it left off.</p>
<h1>Challenge: Unfriendly service representatives</h1>
<p>Another universal customer service complaint is about service representatives, with <a href="http://www.parature.com/2013-customer-expectations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">60% of global customers</a> ranking it as a top frustration. Customer service agents sometimes lose their temper, which can lead to fractured customer relationships and massive media fallout. However, the gold standard across the world is to treat the customer in a friendly manner, though the method varies from country to country.</p>
<ul>
<li>In the United States, employees usually treat the customer in a <a href="http://www.parature.com/2013-customer-expectations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">genial manner</a> and try and work with customers to solve their problem.</li>
<li>In some <a href="http://www.parature.com/2013-customer-expectations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">northern European countries</a>, agents can be direct and use phrases like “Your idea is wrong” with customers.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.berlitz.com.uy/SiteData/docs/BerlitzCul/691862a1aef0a178/Berlitz_Culture&amp;CustomerServiceExperience.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Representatives in Asian countries</a> typically limit themselves to a small smile, but take personal responsibility in solving a customer’s problem.</li>
<li><a href="http://graphics.eiu.com/upload/customerservice_DHL.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Thai consumers</a> are pleased by courteous, knowledgeable staff more than Malaysian or South Korean customers.</li>
<li>In South Africa, <a href="http://www.tourism.gov.za/AboutNDT/Publications/tourism%20report%20final%2028%20january%202011_22%20march.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">good service</a> is built on personal and emotional connections. Emotionally detached agents lead to a bad service experience.</li>
<li>A 2015 customer service survey found that <a href="http://www.itnewsafrica.com/2015/04/nigeria-mobile-users-unimpressed-with-customer-service/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">almost 50% of mobile phone users</a> in South Africa, Nigeria, Germany, Spain, Poland, and Morocco were dissatisfied with the customer service agents they spoke to.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Solution: Training</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.parature.com/2013-customer-expectations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">One of the top six global customer service frustrations </a>is dealing with employees or self-service sites that can’t answer questions. Companies that train their agents to be knowledgeable, culturally sensitive and technologically savvy will reap the rewards&#8211;<a href="http://graphics.eiu.com/upload/customerservice_DHL.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">over 65% of companies in the Asia Pacific</a> region reported that staff training had the most impact on customer satisfaction. By training agents to be able to work on multiple channels or use a CRM, companies will be able to provide agents with a great customer experience the world over.</p>
<h1>Conclusion</h1>
<p>Providing great global customer service is a daunting task, as not staying attuned to global customers’ service preferences can have significant repercussions. Poor customer service costs companies <a href="http://www.parature.com/2013-customer-expectations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">$83 billion</a> every year, and companies without an omnichannel strategy lose an average of <a href="http://www.parature.com/2013-customer-expectations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">$22 million</a>. In addition, a <a href="http://trendwatching.com/trends/future-customer-service/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2013 Accenture Survey </a>found that 66% of global consumers stopped doing business one brand and switched to another due to poor customer service, while 82% say the company could have done something to stop them from switching.</p>
<p>Global customers are also not opposed to voicing their grievances after a bad service experience. <a href="ttps://d16cvnquvjw7pr.cloudfront.net/resources/whitepapers/Omnichannel-Customer-Service-Gap.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Over 40% of French customers</a> will tell friends and family about a bad service experience, impacting future purchase decisions. Similarly, <a href="https://d16cvnquvjw7pr.cloudfront.net/resources/whitepapers/Omnichannel-Customer-Service-Gap.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">over 40% of Australian customers</a> will share bad service experiences with friends and family, and 13% will go on social media.</p>
<p>However, global consumers will reward companies for a good experience. <a href="https://d16cvnquvjw7pr.cloudfront.net/resources/whitepapers/Omnichannel-Customer-Service-Gap.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Over 80% of Australian</a> customers will use a brand again if they have a good experience, and 41% will spend more money with that company. For more and more consumers, a good experience is an omnichannel one: <a href="https://www.avaya.com/usa/documents/media-summary-for-avaya-cem-global-november-2014.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">over 25% of global consumers</a> are using more channels to contact organizations. Companies that provide an omnichannel experience, <a href="https://www.avaya.com/usa/documents/media-summary-for-avaya-cem-global-november-2014.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">45% of global consumers will spend more money with them</a>.</p>
<p>Ultimately, it&#8217;s important to be able to communicate effectively to your customers no matter where they are. By familiarizing themselves with global customer preferences and multiple support channels, service representatives can make a world of difference.</p>
<p><strong>To learn how to provide a seamless, omnichannel experience for your customers, <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/omnichannel-seamless-experience">download our ebook here</a>.</strong></p>
<p><em><a href="http://www.icmi.com/Resources/Global-Service-Delivery/2015/08/Meeting-and-Exceeding-Global-Customers-Expectations">This post originally appeared on ICMI</a>.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://il5.picdn.net/shutterstock/videos/6116042/thumb/3.jpg">Photo credit</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/how-to-provide-great-customer-service-across-the-globe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>The ‘Magic’ Model &#8211; How To Instantly Build Your Own SMS Concierge Service</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/the-magic-model-how-to-instantly-build-your-own-sms-concierge-service/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/the-magic-model-how-to-instantly-build-your-own-sms-concierge-service/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Use Cases]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/the-magic-model-how-to-instantly-build-your-own-sms-concierge-service/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After graduating from <a href="http://www.ycombinator.com/">YCombinator</a> back in February, a startup called <a href="http://getmagicnow.com/">Magic</a>, an SMS concierge service,  went viral, wowing Americans with the prospect that they could order almost anything via text message and have it show up at their door &#8211; not to mention the $12 million investment they garnered from <a href="http://www.sequoiacap.com">Sequoia Capital</a>, with a $40 million valuation). After provisioning a<a href="http://www.wired.com/2015/02/magic-the-startup/"> Twilio number</a> and rolling the service out to a few friends, the service suddenly skyrocketed in popularity, thanks to some well-placed features on <a href="http://www.producthunt.com/tech/magic">Product Hunt</a> and <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=9087819">Hacker News</a> (and just good old word-of-mouth).</p>
<p>Investors and companies are now starting to see the value of SMS (finally!), and so are emerging Magic competitors. Entrepreneurs around the world have begun innovating on the “Magic” model, spanning from straight up copycats to various niche-specific spins on the model &#8211; for example, the SMS concierge service for travelling performers and staff in the music-touring business. If you have an existing or potential SMS concierge business in mind, you’ll be very glad to know just how easy it is to equip yourself with the right tools and services to make it happen.</p>
<h1><span id="more-7245"></span><b>How to Create Your Own SMS Service: What You&#8217;ll Need</b></h1>
<p>To make your own “Magic,” all you need is a phone number (any toll-free, short-code or 10-digit local number will do), a web-based or mobile-based chat tool that can manage text messages, and a payment processing system.</p>
<p>By creating a OneReach account, you’ll get these great features needed to make your own Magic SMS Service:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Provision a text-enabled number easily and cheaply.</strong> Magic uses a short code number (83489), which can cost <a href="https://www.twilio.com/HELP/faq/short-codes/how-much-does-a-short-code-cost">$1,000 a month</a> or more. We can set you up with a short code, as they can handle a larger volume of traffic, but if you’re just getting up and running, a long code will typically do just fine as it is far less expensive. These 10-digit numbers only cost <a href="https://www.twilio.com/voice/pricing">$1-2 a month</a>.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong><strong>Text chat and web chat in the same tool. </strong></strong><b></b>OneReach has a CTI integration, which is just a fancy way of saying that  we’ve created a seamless integration between SMS (text messaging) and web-chat &#8211; meaning, you can respond to SMS via a browser-based portal. Our Action Desk has the capability to handle both text chat and web chat and can manage multiple conversations at once. Although you’ll primarily be dealing with incoming text messages, you could create a field on your homepage so web visitors could input their number online and receive a text back from you to start the conversation.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Receiving requests anytime, anywhere, with our mobile app.</strong> You’re not always going to be able to stay at the desk all day, and that’s okay. If you’re out and about fulfilling a request and another one comes in, you can respond to it immediately or transfer it to someone else.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Assign agents to manage requests.</strong> As your business grows, you’re going to need a dedicated team of agents to field incoming requests. With OneReach, you can assign multiple agents to one number so that every incoming request gets answered. In addition, you can have agents claim an incoming text so that other agents know to move onto the next one.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Setting up business logic routing based on time, request type or any other parameter.</strong> You may not always be available (picking up orders, done for the day, etc.), which is where our business logic routing comes in. If someone specifically handles food requests, you can route all related requests to them. Similarly, if someone is off the clock, our system can route requests to a different agent based on their schedule.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Easily connecting or integrating with a payment system or food ordering system.</strong> We’re not 100% sure if Magic uses APIs (application programming interfaces) to fulfill all their requests, but APIs sure make things a lot easier. Our tool lets you integrate with the most popular systems out there, like <a href="http://stripe.com">Stripe</a> for payment or <a href="http://postmates.com">Postmates</a> and <a href="http://grubhub.com">GrubHub</a> for food ordering. All you’ll need is an API key to plug into our tool and you’re good to go.</li>
</ul>
<p>And the best part is you can get this all up and running in a matter of minutes.</p>
<p>Now let’s learn how to create your own SMS Service!</p>
<h1><b>How to Create Your Own SMS Service: Tutorial</b></h1>
<h2><b>Step 1: Sign up for OneReach</b></h2>
<p>To set up a OneReach account, visit our homepage, then<a href="http://onereach.com/pricing"> click on pricing</a>. There, you can pick the number you want and the pricing plan you want (or sign up for a 14-day trial). After you enter your credit card information, you’re set up with OneReach!</p>
<p><a href="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/screenshot2.png"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-1677 size-large" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/screenshot2-546x304.png" alt="screenshot2" width="546" height="304" /></a></p>
<h2><b>Step 2: Set up a payment system account</b></h2>
<p>In order to take payments, you’ll need to create an account for an online payment system. We suggest <a href="http://stripe.com">Stripe</a>, <a href="http://braintreepayments.com">Braintree</a> or <a href="http://dwolla.com">Dwolla</a>. They all have APIs so you can integrate with OneReach, link to a payment page and store payment information for future purchases.</p>
<p><a href="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/stripe2.png"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1678" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/stripe2-546x282.png" alt="stripe2" width="546" height="282" /></a></p>
<h2><b>Step 3: Log into OneReach’s </b><b><i>Action Desk</i></b></h2>
<p>Go to <a href="https://go.onereach.com/">go.onereach.com</a> to sign in to your new Action Desk and get familiar with it. This is where you’ll be fielding all your incoming texts.</p>
<p><a href="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/action-desk.png"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1679" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/action-desk-546x268.png" alt="action desk" width="546" height="268" /></a></p>
<p>That’s it! You now know how to create your own SMS service! Now all that’s left is to promote your new number and let the texts roll in! If you need to add more agents as demand increases, you can do that with OneReach. And if more messages start coming in, you can adjust your plan to compensate for that.</p>
<h2><b>Conclusion</b></h2>
<p>Magic has a pretty awesome concept—text in whatever you want and get it delivered to your door in no time. But there are already some pretty strong copycats out there, and you could be the next one since you know how to create your own SMS service. What’s really important now is how you’ll differentiate yourself from the pack. We found this quote from<a href="http://techcrunch.com/2015/04/01/go-butler/"> Magic competitor GoButler co-founder CEO Navin Hadzaad</a> pretty inspiring:</p>
<blockquote><p>Think of it this way: in 6 months, when you tell us ‘I want my favourite pizza now. I’m at home’ – we know what you’re favourite pizza is, we know where you live, we have your payment details. In the background, our integrated-API with our food delivery partner will trigger the order, the payment will automatically be processed and you’ll get a confirmation. Isn’t that convenient?</p></blockquote>
<p>With our tool, there’s no limit to what your OneReach-powered text service can do. Now, go make some magic happen.</p>
<p><b><i>If you need help with your new text service, shoot us an email at support@onereach.com. And don’t forget to download our whitepaper, </i></b><a href="http://onereach.com/resources/10-things-about-text"><b><i>10 Things Every Business Should Know About Text Messaging</i></b></a><b><i>.</i></b></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/the-magic-model-how-to-instantly-build-your-own-sms-concierge-service/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Questions You Need to Ask About Your Omnichannel Customer Experience</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/5-questions-you-need-to-ask-about-your-omnichannel-customer-experience/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/5-questions-you-need-to-ask-about-your-omnichannel-customer-experience/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Customer Experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OmniChannel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/5-questions-you-need-to-ask-about-your-omnichannel-customer-experience/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Whether we admit it or not, today’s <a class="topics-tag" href="http://uxmag.com/topics/customer-experience" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">customer experience</a> is all about omnichannel. People are reaching out to companies on the phone, via text message, through emails and webforms—you name it, someone’s using it. When customers reach out to customer service, they most often use <a href="http://www.icmi.com/Resources/Global-Service-Delivery/2014/06/Look-Whos-Talking-Now-Voice-in-Todays-Contact-Center" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">three or more channels</a>, and most businesses offer <a href="http://blog.vpi-corp.com/blog/performance-optimization-2/40-stats-shaping-the-future-of-contact-centers" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">multiple service channels</a> to answer customer questions.</p>
<p>But an <a class="topics-tag" href="http://uxmag.com/topics/ubiquitous-computing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">omnichannel experience</a> isn’t just about having multiple channels: it’s about making sure those channels all work together. The idea behind omnichannel is that it all the service channels are connected, integrated, and consistent. When customers call your company, they don’t view your support channels separately; to them, everything is managed as a whole, not a bunch of different departments. And they’re not wrong to view the customer experience this way—91% of customers want to <a href="http://blogs.aspect.com/2014/01/29/infographic-omni-channel-service-doesnt-measure-up-customers-are-tired-of-playing-games/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">pick up where they left off</a>when they switch between channels.</p>
<p><span id="more-7244"></span>Unfortunately, 80% of companies <a href="http://blogs.forrester.com/kate_leggett/12-06-25-transform_the_contact_center_forresters_playbook_for_customer_service_excellence" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">haven’t integrated their communication across channels</a>, meaning there’s a massive disconnect between supply and demand for omnichannel experiences. For anyone looking to integrate their communication channels, or maybe even just tweak them, here are five questions to address when creating an omnichannel customer experience.</p>
<h2><strong>1. Do You Have a Variety of Support Channels That Customers Use and Want?</strong></h2>
<p>This may seem like a simple question, but it’s actually pretty important. As mentioned above, most customers use three or more channels to contact companies, and most companies offer a variety of service channels. Still, a lot of companies have yet to get up to speed with the channels customers use most in their daily lives, like text and social media.</p>
<p>Think about it: pretty much every business offers phone support, but the average American only makes <a href="http://www.pewinternet.org/2010/09/02/cell-phones-and-american-adults/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">one to five calls a day</a>. Conversely, <a href="http://www.dimensiondata.com/Global/Global-Microsites/CCBenchmarking" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">fewer than 40% of businesses</a> offer text support, but the average American sends and receives <a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/chart-of-the-day-number-of-texts-sent-2013-3" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">60 texts a day</a>. On a global scale, people send <a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=4&amp;cad=rja&amp;uact=8&amp;sqi=2&amp;ved=0CCwQFjAD&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fabout.twitter.com%2Fcompany&amp;ei=fXIDVYDYKcnuoATy_IHIDQ&amp;usg=AFQjCNGN5ft_wihQCzYKc-pyc6BuWkF2jg&amp;bvm=bv.88198703,d.cGU" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">500 million tweets a day</a> and over <a href="http://www.cnn.com/2012/12/03/tech/mobile/sms-text-message-20/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">23 billion texts a day</a>. These channels are increasingly popular, and their only real barrier is the widespread, accepted usage of voice for customer service.</p>
<p>Maybe you’re apprehensive about adding new channels because of <a class="topics-tag" href="http://uxmag.com/topics/business-value-and-roi" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">cost or executive buy-in</a>, but relax—you don’t have to offer every single channel. However, you should definitely have the channels that prospects and customers use most, or consider adding alternative and inexpensive channels that are <a href="http://blogs.forrester.com/kate_leggett/13-03-15-communication_channel_preferences_for_customer_service_are_rapidly_changing_do_you_know_what_your_cus" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">on the rise</a> (self-service, SMS, etc.) Omnichannel strategies will vary from company to company, and that’s okay. Just make sure you promote your new channels across your existing ones to increase awareness and use.</p>
<h2><strong>2. Do You Store Customer Data in One Central Location?</strong></h2>
<p>Most of the time, customer data collected in different departments stays in different departments. This can end up creating a fractured customer experience. <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/fred.zimny/accenture-global-consumer-pulse-research-study-2013-key-findings" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Studies have found that 91% of customers are frustrated by calling in for the same problem, and 89% are frustrated by having to repeat their problem to multiple service reps</a>.</p>
<p>When crafting an omnichannel customer experience, companies should store data in a central location like the cloud. That way, it doesn’t matter what department a customer calls or who they talk to—everyone can access the same information and can pick up the conversation where it left off. It also doesn’t matter what channel the customer uses—if they do have to switch between channels, channel-use records can be stored in the cloud.</p>
<p>And those aren’t the only benefits of centralized communication: solutions like the cloud are quick to deploy (most providers offer a free trial to get started), are updated automatically, and can also scale to suit any organization.</p>
<h2><strong>3. Are Your Channels Integrated?</strong></h2>
<p>A key part of omnichannel is integration and making sure all the channels are connected. Customers today are demanding a seamless experience that recognizes them on any device or channel. The bad thing is that <a href="http://blogs.aspect.com/2014/01/29/infographic-omni-channel-service-doesnt-measure-up-customers-are-tired-of-playing-games/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">61% have had a hard time</a> switching from one channel to another when interacting with customer service.</p>
<p>By integrating channels, companies can deliver the seamless experience that customers want. With integration, customers can continue a conversation with different channels or agents without losing context. Omnichannel communication platforms can keep track of where, why and how customers interacted with the company. Companies can also personalize service with integration, using records of customers’ past interactions to better inform the present one.</p>
<p>Finally, integrating channels lets customers use the channel best suited to the situation. For example, text might be best for quick answers to questions, so companies with integrated channels could prompt customers to switch from text to voice with a “channel pivot” option. This option makes it quicker and easier for customers to get things done.</p>
<p>One great example of omnichannel integration is American Express’ fraud detection program. When they pick up suspicious activity, the system calls the customer and asks what type of phone they have (smartphone, feature phone, etc.) It then sends them a text message with a link to review their charges online, with the account already logged in. The key takeaway here is that everything is quick, seamless and uses the best channel for each task.</p>
<h2><strong>4. Do You Offer Automation?</strong></h2>
<p>Gartner predicts that by 2020, 85% of customer interactions will be conducted without a human-to-human interaction. This makes sense: customers can get frustrated by <a href="http://www.parature.com/2013-customer-expectations/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">long wait times</a> and <a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/7/15/5901057/comcast-call-cancel-service-ryan-block" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">live agents</a> in general, and the best agent can only manage so many responses before they get overwhelmed.</p>
<p>With automated self-service, businesses can deliver a faster, cheaper, smarter experience. A call handled by a live agent <a href="http://www.oracle.com/us/corporate/analystreports/enterprise-application/forrester-tei-atg-359304.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">typically costs between $6-20</a>, where a call managed by IVR only costs 25 cents (automated texts costs the same). Automation also delivers an answer immediately, which addresses the patience problem but more importantly, helps customers get their problem solved faster. Companies can go above and beyond by adding an AI component that analyzes past customer input to deliver more personalized service in the future.</p>
<p>For example, let’s say Dan calls in every month to check his credit card balance. Instead of making him go through the entire IVR, a good omnichannel solution would adapt to give Dan “check account balance” as the first option.</p>
<h2><strong>5. If You Don&#8217;t Have All of These, Do You Have an Action Plan?</strong></h2>
<p>Omnichannel is a relatively straightforward concept, but implementing it is decidedly less so. To provide the best omnichannel customer experience, make sure you’ve hit the following points:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>First</strong>, figure out what channels are most used by your customers, or the channels they most want to use. This will require some research and potential surveying to make sure you’re delivering on the channels customers want.</li>
<li><strong>Second</strong>, find a cloud hosting platform that can support the number of customer records you have. Most cloud platforms are scalable and priced for different usage levels, so you should be able to find a solution that works for you.</li>
<li><strong>Third</strong>, find a communication platform like <a href="file://localhost/C/%5CUsers%5CGigi%5CDownloads%5Conereach.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">OneReach</a> that offers multiple channels and lets you switch between them. Standout solutions will offer automation and integration between channels, as well as API integration.</li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>Conclusion</strong></h2>
<p>It’s important to consider what kind of experiences customers want, and the answer is pretty clear: they want all of them. With <a href="http://www.dimensiondata.com/Global/Downloadable%20Documents/2015%20Global%20Contact%20Centre%20Benchmarking%20Summary%20Report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">74% of businesses eager to differentiate themselves based on customer experience</a>, having an omnichannel strategy is what will make one company’s customer experience stand out from the crowd.</p>
<p><em><strong>To learn more about providing a seamless omnichannel experience for your customers, <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/omnichannel-seamless-experience">download our new eBook here.</a></strong></em></p>
<p><em>This article originally appeared in <a href="http://uxmag.com/articles/are-you-ready-to-give-your-customers-an-omni-channel-experience">UX Magazine</a>.</em></p>
<p>Image credit: <a href="https://www.demacmedia.com/ecommerce-strategy/what-is-omni-channel-commerce/">Demac Media</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/5-questions-you-need-to-ask-about-your-omnichannel-customer-experience/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Voice and Text Can Increase Your Mobile App Downloads</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/how-voice-and-text-can-increase-your-mobile-app-downloads/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/how-voice-and-text-can-increase-your-mobile-app-downloads/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/how-voice-and-text-can-increase-your-mobile-app-downloads/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Many of today’s top businesses offer a mobile app, and all of them are looking for downloads in an increasingly prevalent mobile market. There were an estimated<a href="http://www.statista.com/statistics/266488/forecast-of-mobile-app-downloads/"> 138 billion global app downloads</a> in 2014, and that number is set to double to 270 billion in 2017. With over half of American consumers downloading around<a href="http://www.flurry.com/blog/flurry-insights/app-install-addiction-shows-no-signs-stopping#.VPXvNfnF9TY"> four apps a month</a>, how can your business tap into the booming mobile app market and increase downloads?</p>
<p dir="ltr">Answer: promote downloads through text message and voice, the two most common activities done on a mobile device.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><span id="more-7213"></span>Even though landline call traffic<a href="http://www.telecompetitor.com/fcc-landline-voice-lines-decline-4-7-in-six-months-voip-growth-slows/"> is on the decline</a>, voice is still one of the most widely used and ubiquitous channels in the world. And according to Pew Research,<a href="http://www.pewinternet.org/2013/09/19/cell-phone-activities-2013/"> 81% of Americans</a> use their cell phone to send or receive text messages, while 50% use it to download apps.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Companies that use text and voice to boost their mobile app strategy will not only see increased downloads, but increased customer engagement.</p>
<h2 dir="ltr">Adding text and voice to your mobile app strategy</h2>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="https://info.dynatrace.com/rs/compuware/images/Mobile_App_Survey_Report.pdf">Over 85% of mobile device users</a> prefer mobile apps over mobile websites, largely because they’re more convenient, faster and easier to browse. In addition,<a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/04/01/mobile-app-usage-increases-in-2014-as-mobile-web-surfing-declines/"> 86% of time spent on the mobile web</a> is spent on apps, compared just 14% for mobile web browsers.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img style="border: 0pt none; float: center; padding-right: 10px; padding-bottom: 10px;" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/eCQMUW60JMiWMprnyMlDGc7bKq56Kbe3ZiBCeeNV3LJNvat5e4sd6Eenl7YbkMaXSZ8_4CXFm4uA2yLg9yalMSt7FOFxEwBB4ekUfCueA_qGiM-7o7C1KABOlBAQ4ZqI74SY7vI" alt="" width="395" height="344" /></p>
<p dir="ltr">A true omnichannel communication strategy will leverage existing channels (e.g. phone calls) to drive adoption and usage of other channels. That means that customer data collected across channels should be used to deliver a personalized experience, no matter what channel the customer uses. Similarly, if a customer decides to switch between channels, the conversation and context should be maintained (<a href="http://blogs.aspect.com/2014/01/29/infographic-omni-channel-service-doesnt-measure-up-customers-are-tired-of-playing-games/">something over 90% of customers expect</a>).</p>
<p dir="ltr">An omnichannel solution can help you track whether or not a customer has downloaded a mobile app and adapt accordingly. <strong>For example, if a customer calls into your company, your IVR should know if the caller has downloaded the app.</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">An omnichannel solution like OneReach can make an API call to your existing customer database to see if customers have created an account or downloaded an app. If they haven’t, create a separate branch within the IVR that encourages users to download the app. It’s as simple as letting a caller “press 1” to receive a text message with a link to download the app.</p>
<p dir="ltr">An omnichannel solution can also switch customers between channels based on which one best suits a specific task. During the call, offer to send a download link via text message by prompting the caller to press 1 (far easier than reciting the URL over voice). No matter what the customer is calling in for (mobile payment, rescheduling, etc.), your IVR flow should promote the idea that they can perform any of these activities within your mobile app (and subsequently provide a link to download it). Once customers have downloaded an app,  update the customer database programatically. If customers aren’t downloading the app, consider moving the CTA to another part of the voice or text flow.</p>
<h2 dir="ltr">Taking it further with texting</h2>
<p dir="ltr">Businesses aren’t just limited to dropping a link via SMS. Businesses should also consider offering the ability to receive a text from their website, like Hotwire does:</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img style="border: 0pt none; float: center; padding-right: 10px; padding-bottom: 10px;" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/VcJuoU9xcEQblTPV0l-g2ZqIoc9zlNGTE_ppxqO-L2UACntMdBQTid_t7qUUSbRAhK0LiPXvNK6tC3l9IkLUqVi83qzMEp3jYoxB--uoHeB-6wHf4vpptWi_PxEqQzkdFNHkOm4" alt="" width="439" height="305" /></p>
<p dir="ltr">Businesses can take it even further by changing the copy of the text message based on any number of things: seasonality, what they know about the user (based on the phone number entered), current marketing campaigns, etc.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>The best part is that the marketing department can update the copy anytime without having to ask developers to change the API.</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">However, it’s important to note that capturing a potential customer’s attention with a deal or incentive to encourage a download is only one piece of the puzzle. Maintaining a relationship past the app download and engaging customers is equally important. While it may not be fiscally feasible to offer provide discounts to app users every time they use an app, there are alternatives. To increase mobile app engagement, businesses can:</p>
<ul>
<li>Track how users use their app</li>
<li>Establish loyalty programs and points systems</li>
<li>Personalize messages and push notifications</li>
<li>Invite users to leave a review in the app store</li>
<li>Create a sense of urgency by reminding users of deal deadlines (include a link within the notification directing them to the specific page within the app)</li>
</ul>
<h2 dir="ltr">Conclusion</h2>
<p dir="ltr">An app is only useful when downloaded. By using the existing communication channels that your customers are already using, you can increase the number of app downloads and offer an enhanced customer experience.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>To learn more about your customers&#8217; desire to incorporate text into customer service, <a href="http://onereachcontactcenter.com/high-demand-for-customer-service-via-text-message/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">download the 2014 Harris Report here</a>.</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Image from <a href="http://pixabay.com/en/iphone-smartphone-apps-apple-inc-410311/">JE Shoots</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/how-voice-and-text-can-increase-your-mobile-app-downloads/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Text Tech Support Can Cut Back On Costs</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/how-text-tech-support-can-cut-back-on-costs/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/how-text-tech-support-can-cut-back-on-costs/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech Support]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/how-text-tech-support-can-cut-back-on-costs/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Companies generally provide tech support through phone or email, so when some companies began providing it through text messages, there was some anxiety. According to <a href="http://www.practicalecommerce.com/articles/4139-Text-Messaging-Effective-for-Retailers-">practicalecommerce.com</a>, there are 4.3 billion people carrying SMS-enabled devices, and of those, 96% send text messages on a regular basis. Those who have used text-based tech support as opposed to the phone-based alternative typically prefer texting. <a href="http://onereachcontactcenter.com/high-demand-for-customer-service-via-text-message/">A Harris Poll study</a> found that 64% of customers who text prefer SMS to phone for customer service.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><span id="more-7207"></span>A lot of this has to do with the fact that customers can receive support in a loud or crowded place and not worry about being able to hear their technician. A technician can help multiple people at once through this particular type of support using a text chat interface. It would be impossible for one agent to simultaneously help out more than one customer over the phone at the same time.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Due to increasingly complex products and services being offered to consumers, tech support demand is only increasing. The quality of tech support being delivered by text has become so advanced that it is possible to gradually evaluate the issue the customer in question is attempting to address. A few simple questions being answered by the customer will allow the tech support professional to determine what sort of issue they are having and how they might go about solving it. With the necessary information in hand, a tech support professional can then begin to thoroughly research the issue.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Customers submitting information via <a href="http://www.onereach.com/">text</a> as opposed to over the phone is a much more expedient option, freeing up more time for technicians and increasing productivity. With the existing technology that is out there, it is possible to navigate through a tech support system via texting very quickly. A tiered or tree system will allow a consumer to navigate the system and provide information about their problem quickly, making it both faster and simpler for the technician to address the customer&#8217;s questions.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The cost of implementing this customer service option could involve the use of additional technology at the workplace, but the learning curve therein will be vastly outdone by the expedience and accuracy of support being delivered. During the initial phase of creating a text-based tech support system, it is important to still allow customers to call in. This wa,y they can still receive support the way they are used to. It is also worth considering that the average response time to an email is 90 minutes, while the average response time to a text message is <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AyV7ll85MqU&amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;t=36s">90 seconds</a>.</p>
<p dir="ltr">As customers become aware of this new system and try it out, they will use it more than the traditional alternative (phone). By providing tech support over text messaging, companies will be able to get customers the help they need on a channel they use, and all in a time frame that works for them.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em><strong>To learn more about your customers&#8217; channel preferences, download the <a href="http://onereachcontactcenter.com/high-demand-for-customer-service-via-text-message/">2014 Harris Report here</a>.</strong></em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Photo by <a href="http://pixabay.com/en/blogger-cellphone-office-business-336371/">Unsplash</a>. Edited.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/how-text-tech-support-can-cut-back-on-costs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 Tips for Creating a 21st Century Contact Center</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/3-tips-for-creating-a-21st-century-contact-center/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/3-tips-for-creating-a-21st-century-contact-center/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Contact Center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How To]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/3-tips-for-creating-a-21st-century-contact-center/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">No matter what industry your business is operating in, it can undoubtedly benefit from multiple channels of communication. By contacting customers in real-time, your business can make sure they are receiving the attention that they need, when they need it.</p>
<p dir="ltr">It&#8217;s time to take your contact center into the 21st century with SMS.</p>
<h2 dir="ltr"><span id="more-7161"></span><strong>How Will A New Channel Benefit Your Customers?</strong></h2>
<p dir="ltr">SMS of the past enhanced customer service by contacting customers on a channel they used all the time. From special promotions to providing valuable contact information, these businesses majorly benefited from this one-way form of communication. But one-way unquestionably limits the potential of what true communication should be, and that&#8217;s why new technology is changing the SMS texting platform. With platforms like OneReach, not only can businesses text their customers, but their customers can text them back.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Contact centers should also incorporate intelligent automation. When a customer calls in, the customer service representative should be provided with an easy-to-navigate interface that showed all of the customers&#8217; previous interactions with the company. From previous purchases to returns, these details could be used to optimize the service the representative provides. With newer technology, this is exactly what businesses get.</p>
<h2 dir="ltr">Using New Technology: Understanding the Costs</h2>
<p dir="ltr">With <a href="https://econsultancy.com/blog/63871-omnichannel-customer-service-stats-and-infographics#i.hx43yf3qfdv8qt">78 percent of consumers</a> stating that they base their purchasing decisions on the customer service reputation of a company, it becomes clear to see just how imperative it is that you revamp your customer experience policies to the max. And this of course means providing them with a multitude of convenient lines of communication. It’s not necessarily that certain channels are better than others. Rather, it’s about providing customers with the option to choose the experience they want.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Technology lets customers to text your business via 1-800 numbers. Moreso, live agent interaction gets smoothly connected with automation, making it a very cost-efficient form of customer service to implement.  Overall, you&#8217;ll enjoy not only happier call center employees, but more importantly, satisfied customers.</p>
<p dir="ltr">But what about the cost of implementing this new type of technology? If it exceeds your overall budget for providing customer service, then you will of course need to find a regimen that stays in-line with the monies you have to meet the needs of your customers. Do keep in mind that you may need to re-orchestrate your funds so that budget constraints do not limit your ability to take advantage of an all-in-one customer service experience. However, depending on your size and needs, there are many cost-friendly options.</p>
<h2 dir="ltr">Easy to Implement, Easy to Use</h2>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.retailtouchpoints.com/features/executive-viewpoints/engaged-employees-drive-the-omnichannel-experience">40 percent of employees</a> state that they have no idea what programs are going to be implemented until after they have already been rolled out. Don&#8217;t let your employees fall into this category. By taking advantage of new call center technology, seamless training and integration within your overall business operation is possible. Fully customizable integrations mean that you can save on training, as new channels will simply build upon your current software.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Gone are the days of having to keep your customers on hold. Gone are the days of one-way SMS messaging. With today&#8217;s technological advancements on your side, a new horizon is taking shape, and it&#8217;s up to you to soar above it.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em>To learn more about text-enabling your contact center, professionally designed or do-it-yourself, visit <a href="onereach.com">onereach.com</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/3-tips-for-creating-a-21st-century-contact-center/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
