<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Big Ideas &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<atom:link href="https://onereach.ai/category/big-ideas/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<description>Intelligently Automate Your Company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 11:39:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/cropped-OR-ICON-GOLD-W-DOTS-Larger-Background-02-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Big Ideas &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>You Don&#8217;t Need An App for That</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/you-dont-need-an-app-for-that/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/you-dont-need-an-app-for-that/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Benefits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Big Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Communication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ITR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/you-dont-need-an-app-for-that/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In July of 2013 Toby Shapshak, the South African speaker, strategist and editor of Stuff Magazine, did a TED talk called </span><a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/toby_shapshak_you_don_t_need_an_app_for_that?language=en"><span style="font-weight: 400;">You Don’t Need An App For That</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Business leaders, innovators and experience designers would soon realize how profound this TED talk was to the rest of the world. Shapshak’s astute observations and message to the rest of the world was years ahead of a revolution that Forbes would call </span><a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/parmyolson/2016/02/23/chat-bots-facebook-telegram-wechat/#5c9ad9142633"><span style="font-weight: 400;">“the new way we’ll be interacting with computers.”</span></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Toby’s 2013 Ted talk touted that “while the rest of the world is updating statuses and playing games on smartphones, Africa is developing useful SMS-based solutions to everyday needs”. Since 2013 his TED talk has been viewed 1,438,046 times as of July 19, 2016.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fast forward a couple of years and we see more apps than anyone knows what to do with, as well as a notable decrease in</span><a href="http://onereach.com/blog/infographic-mobile-apps-vs-text-messaging/"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> usage and app-downloads</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. This has businesses confused and frustrated. Meanwhile, around the world, messaging (SMS and the ever-encroaching uptake of IP messaging &#8211; Facebook Messenger, Spark, Slack, Kik, SnapChat, etc) is by far the most used function or app on mobile phones &#8211; smart phone or not.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">2016 brought a wave of new businesses and products that fall into the category of </span><a href="http://onereach.com/blog/why-your-business-needs-a-bot/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">bots</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">; chat bots, messaging-bots, </span><a href="http://uxmag.com/articles/humans-ai-and-the-user-interface-of-the-future"><span style="font-weight: 400;">conversational-bots</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, “invisible apps” or &#8220;conversational commerce”. Messaging-bots are popping up for everything, increasingly displacing mobile-apps. New bots are being brought to life daily by startups and household brands alike. Whether the experiences are where they need to be or not, bots existing today which allow you to order a </span><a href="http://onereach.com/blog/i-tried-ordering-dominos-over-text-message-and-it-was-a-total-disaster/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">pizza</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, make a payment, read the </span><a href="http://money.cnn.com/2016/08/04/media/new-york-times-text-message/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">news</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, be reminded of an appointment or even make an appointment. Even </span><a href="http://onereach.com/blog/cities-offer-text-311/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">city and county municipalities</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> are seeing the value, for example, Washington DC uses a </span><a href="https://onereach.com/bots/#dc"><span style="font-weight: 400;">bot for their 311</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">-public services hotline. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Silicon Valley and other capital ventures hubs around the world have already backed several startups that leverage, if not rely entirely on, bots. Benedict Evans, Partner at the Venture Capital Firm, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Andreessen Horowitz (&#8216;</span><a href="http://www.a16z.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">a16z</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8216;) </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">tweeted &#8220;I genuinely can&#8217;t remember the last time a concept blew up as quickly as bots&#8221;.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For years, I’ve been part of a business that, like Toby Shapshak, was ahead of the “bot” curve that’s now consuming the business and customer experience worlds. Expedia, Bosch, DHL, Unilever, Stella Artois, HomeAdvisor, The National Domestic Violence Hotline, Red Cross and many others use </span><a href="http://t.yesware.com/tt/40cc1fc6e25c0e6b6c473b6e5d7078c28afa0f2a/489eb37184cda59ba3c43d567cdd0d3e/ac7788ed6176abd000e4ebc066e9c752/l.gbtrck.com/1ab15380-e2b7-425a-9ad9-959cef88b9b1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">OneReach</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to create (and manage) self-service messaging bots and live communications with their customers. The most popular use-cases include live and automated customer support, proactive order status notifications or order updates, payments/purchasing and text or chat-enabled IVRs (now called chat-bots). Who’d have thought that a bot could reduce 40% of a major brand’s customer support costs, increase revenue by 30% or boost NPS scores?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Toby Shapshak seems to have been the oracle that foretold one of the most prolific changes in how consumers and businesses communicate and do commerce. He suggested that bots are “effectively an intersection of the most basic and sophisticated communication. It&#8217;s remarkable that the very rich (in the developed world) and poor (in the developing world) have effectively ended up in the same place (both using bots)”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Years have past since his Ted Talk and we thought it would be valuable to see what Toby thinks of today’s climate and where things go from here. </span></p>
<h2><b>Our interview with Toby Shapshak</b></h2>
<p><b>Elias: </b><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Messenger Bots are impacting the everyday life and habits of consumers &#8211; in commerce, purchasing, managing one’s time, getting news and so on. You’ve been watching the impact of messenger bots in Africa for sometime. With this in mind, what perspective would you offer to business leaders and experience-designers on the impact that messenger bots have on consumer habits &#8211; in commerce and purchasing or donations, customer support, managing one’s time, getting news and so on?</span></i></p>
<p><b>Toby:</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Business leaders and UX designers should be aware of how chatbots can have an impact on consumer habits; both positively and negatively.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For the youth of the world, who have grown up using chat, it&#8217;s a logical extension to communicate through this channel, ask questions, even make purchases. Pew Research found that American teenagers were only using email to communicate with &#8220;authority figures&#8221; &#8211; adults, parents and teachers. Now chatting is so dominant that WhatsApp has over a 1 billion users and Facebook Messenger has some 800 million users and 50 million businesses. WeChat has some 800 million users, mostly in China, and has been using bots in a very sophisticated way for a lot longer. Wechat is the future of chatting mingled with commerce. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The great thing about SMS &#8211; which is arguably the greatest communication medium the world has ever seen; and the most expensive &#8211; is that it works on every single cellphone, no matter how sophisticated. The other key thing is SMS has a 100% read rate &#8211; even the spam.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In this context, doing new things like search or shopping via messaging/chat seems obvious to a generation of youngsters that prefer chat to email or anything else. Chat is cheaper and it&#8217;s a paradigm that people understand. It also doesn&#8217;t have a learning curve, the way that conventional apps do. </span></p>
<p><b>Elias: </b><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2013 you commented that &#8220;while the rest of the world is updating statuses and playing games on smartphones, Africa is developing useful SMS-based solutions to everyday needs”. Is the current wave of messenger bots solving real problems or this just the new version of &#8220;updating statuses and playing games on smartphones”?</span></i></p>
<p><b>Toby: </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Right now, a lot of chatbots seem like a nice-to-have. Give them some maturity and we&#8217;ll see if they are a flash-in-the-pan hype or something that will be continuingly useful.</span></p>
<p><b>Elias: </b><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Is the rest of the world catching up or is Africa still ahead and in what ways? What has the rest of the world yet to learn still from African innovation?</span></i></p>
<p><b>Toby: </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Africa is forced to innovate the way it does because there are no other alternatives. it&#8217;s the purest form of innovation out of necessity. More people in Africa have access to a cellphone than to electricity. Because of this there are brilliant power solutions, including solar-power systems like M-Kopa. If you have a pressing problem, it&#8217;s the best incentive in the world to solve it. If you have electricity, what are you likely to do? Watch TV or YouTube. it&#8217;s sadly that simple.</span></p>
<p><b>Elias: </b><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">What are your predictions for where messaging and bots go next, in Africa and elsewhere?</span></i></p>
<p><b>Toby: </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">The sky really is the limit, isn&#8217;t it. Text-based services are revolutionary in Africa, offering everything from Google search via SMS to important health information via South Africa&#8217;s mHealth initiatives. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kevin Kelly, the founding executive editor of Wired magazine, said some very interesting things at SXSW this year about how artificial intelligence will become part of our lives. Right now, he says, “it&#8217;s like the early days of cloud computing, but it will ultimately be as sophisticated a service as cloud-based offerings are now”. He called it &#8220;intelligence as a services&#8221;. “Like electricity, which you now buy in what we now call an on-demand model”, Kelly says &#8220;you won’t have to make your AI, you will just purchase it. It will flow like electricity from the grid to wherever you want it. &#8221; He says: &#8220;Artificial intelligence will soon be a commodity&#8221;. AI services at low cost will spur the chatbot industry and make offerings increasingly sophisticated. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There is also the network effect to consider. Part of the reason Google&#8217;s search algorithms are so fast &#8211; and can predict or suggest answers so quickly &#8211; is because of the volume of search queries it has already performed. This inventory of queries and searches mean there is a greater volume of info to reference. As the volume of chatbot data increases, they will also become more effective.</span></p>
<h2><b>Reflection &amp; Looking Forward</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In reflecting on Toby Shapshak’s 2013 Ted Talk it’s evident that he saw something revolutionary emerging amidst the noise in the world of experience design, business and technology. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Similar to the concept of hindsight being 20/20, until 2016 the business world largely ignored the opportunity to leverage the most ubiquitous communication channels in the world (text messaging and IP messaging) for customer support. </span></p>
<p><a href="http://www.edn.com/electronics-blogs/edn-moments/4402146/1st-text-message-is-sent--December-3--1992"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The first text message was sent in 1992</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Text_messaging"><span style="font-weight: 400;">by 2007 </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">74% of all mobile phone users worldwide</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> used text messaging</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. It took the western business world roughly another 10 years to accept the notion that just maybe they should consider communicating with their customers over the single most prefered communication channel in the world &#8211; SMS. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For the last 6 years at </span><a href="http://www.onereach.com"><span style="font-weight: 400;">OneReach,</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> I’ve been lucky enough to see startups and huge international brands alike use our tools to easily create and iterate on fully reportable and integrated bots. It’s been 3 years since Toby Shapshak’s TED talk and it’s great to finally see so many companies designing for the channels consumers actually prefer (messaging). </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now that we’re here, let’s not be foolish enough to think that leveraging chat bots to drive business impact is any easier because the interface is an ‘old’ technology. The businesses world learned that building any old mobile app really isn’t all that hard. Similar to mobile apps, the success of a today’s chat bots will not be defined by whether or not your company offers chatbots. Success will rest on whether or not your chatbot experiences achieve desired outcomes for your business while being meaningful to your customer.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/you-dont-need-an-app-for-that/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Your CEO and Customers Don&#8217;t See Eye to Eye on Customer Experience</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/why-your-ceo-and-customers-dont-see-eye-to-eye-on-customer-experience/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/why-your-ceo-and-customers-dont-see-eye-to-eye-on-customer-experience/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Big Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/why-your-ceo-and-customers-dont-see-eye-to-eye-on-customer-experience/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This guest post is written by Jen Diaz, Program Manager at <a href="http://irrevo.com">Irrevo</a>.</em></p>
<p>Stories of outrageously amazing customer service catch a lot of attention, whether or not they’re actually true. Everyone has heard the legend of the fellow who returned a snow tire to Nordstrom, even though the story that’s passed around is missing some context. If some <a href="https://consumerist.com/2011/12/02/home-depot-staff-makes-8-hour-trip-to-find-me-a-snow-blower/">Home Depot</a> employees drive four hours each way to find you a snowblower, you’d be a happy snowbird. But studies show that customers and business owners don’t always see eye-to-eye on the definition of good customer service.</p>
<p><span id="more-7428"></span>Research conducted by Bain &amp; Company found that 80% of CEOs believe they deliver a superior customer experience, while only 8% of their customers agree. This huge disconnect in perception holds companies back from providing truly “wow”-worthy customer service. However, there’s one question that can close that gap…</p>
<p><strong>Ask your customers “How?” </strong></p>
<p>Good customer service has to be measured using customer feedback. The CEO’s perception of the service his/her company provides matters little. Stakeholders may know that their offer or experience is the best in the industry, but if customers don’t perceive it as such, the end result is dissatisfaction.</p>
<p>For example, Company A offers long-term customers a free product from their new line when their old one breaks, while their competitors do not. Company A’s leadership can quantify that they are going above and beyond what’s required, or even expected. In this case, leadership has made two assumptions:</p>
<ul>
<li>Best in class is best for the customer</li>
<li>Free things = good customer service</li>
</ul>
<p>Countless studies have shown that customers value service over cost. One oft-quoted statistic: 7 in 10 customers would pay more to receive better service. Company A is providing what looks like a great customer experience, but if their stakeholders included the voice of the customer in their decision-making process, they may come to a different conclusion.</p>
<p>What does lead to customer satisfaction? That magic question isn’t answered in the boardroom or on a blog. The voice of the customer speaks in words and phrases, not in 1-5 ratings.</p>
<ul>
<li>How can we resolve your issue?</li>
<li>How can we improve our service?</li>
<li>How did we miss the chance to knock your socks off?</li>
</ul>
<p>Traditional CSAT surveys ignore these questions, or include them as optional, once a customer has provided a 1-10 rating of their satisfaction. Without having specific answers to the How questions above, customer service teams are left to guess at what drives performance. “Is there anything else you’d like to tell us about your experience?” should never be an afterthought.</p>
<h2><strong>About the Author</strong></h2>
<p><img class="alignleft wp-image-2622 size-thumbnail" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/jen-diaz-150x150.jpg" alt="jen-diaz" width="150" height="150" />Jen Diaz lives at the intersection of knowledge management and customer experience. As a Program Manager with <a href="http://irrevo.com">Irrevo</a>, she shares her decade of experience in the customer support industry with a team of strategists, knowledge engineers, and content creators who design and implement comprehensive knowledge ecosystems for top companies.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Image of <a href="https://stocksnap.io/photo/3H21KUXVT4">businessman reading newspaper</a> courtesy of StockSnap. CC0 License.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/why-your-ceo-and-customers-dont-see-eye-to-eye-on-customer-experience/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bots Gone Bad: What We Can Learn From Microsoft’s Tay Malfunction</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/bots-gone-bad-what-we-can-learn-from-microsofts-tay-malfunction/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/bots-gone-bad-what-we-can-learn-from-microsofts-tay-malfunction/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Big Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Use Cases]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/bots-gone-bad-what-we-can-learn-from-microsofts-tay-malfunction/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By now you’ve probably heard the story of Tay, the AI-powered chat bot Microsoft debuted last Wednesday. Things started off innocently enough before Tay went completely off the rails, going on racist rants and tweeting her support of Adolf Hitler before Microsoft pulled the plug.</p>
<p><span id="more-7410"></span>But let’s start back at the beginning. Tay was created by “mining relevant public data and by using AI and editorial developed by a staff including improvisational comedians,” according to <a href="https://www.tay.ai/#about">Microsoft’s Tay website</a>. Tay was programmed to talk like a millennial and targeted at millennials (which apparently means lots of CAPS LOCK and poor grammar, but that’s a discussion for another time).</p>
<p>Unfortunately for Microsoft, people other than millennials found Tay easy enough to manipulate, goading her into spouting racist and sexist rhetoric through a “<a href="http://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2016/03/tay-the-neo-nazi-millennial-chatbot-gets-autopsied/">repeat after me</a>” feature. However, as <a href="http://fusion.net/story/284537/tay-and-you-microsoft-racism/">Fusion</a> reports, “some of the tweets were clearly generated by the bot itself.”</p>
<p>Twitter user @geraldmellor captured some of her incendiary tweets, seen below:</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">&#8220;Tay&#8221; went from &#8220;humans are super cool&#8221; to full nazi in &lt;24 hrs and I&#8217;m not at all concerned about the future of AI <a href="https://t.co/xuGi1u9S1A">pic.twitter.com/xuGi1u9S1A</a></p>
<p>— Gerry (@geraldmellor) <a href="https://twitter.com/geraldmellor/status/712880710328139776">March 24, 2016</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" async="" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p>Tay’s racist makeover didn’t go unnoticed, and Microsoft turned her off before things got more out of hand. But in <a href="http://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2016/03/25/learning-tays-introduction/">Microsoft’s blog post</a> commenting on what happened with Tay, Corporate VP of Microsoft Research Peter Lee pointed out this wasn’t their first foray into AI—Xiaolce, a chat bot Microsoft rolled out in 2014, hasn’t had any major issues. Lee also explained they stress-tested Tay and conducted user studies before her public debut.</p>
<p>Still, the very public meltdown of Microsoft’s AI chat bots left some people like @geraldmellor to wonder what exactly the future of AI might be like if bots go bad. But, looking at it from another perspective, what can bot designers do help ensure bots stay good?</p>
<p>First, you need to remember that bots just might get exposed to negative comments, as Tay was. As Microsoft’s Lee <a href="http://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2016/03/25/learning-tays-introduction/">explains</a>, &#8220;AI systems feed off of both positive and negative interactions with people. In that sense, the challenges are just as much social as they are technical.”</p>
<p>Second, in accordance with Lee’s suggestion, you need to test the bots with large groups of people, and to do it often. But perhaps last and most importantly, you need to make sure they know how to understand language.</p>
<p>Caroline Sinders, an interaction designer at IBM Watson, put it this way in her <a href="https://medium.com/@carolinesinders/microsoft-s-tay-is-an-example-of-bad-design-d4e65bb2569f#.r6iv4kpv6">Medium post</a> about Tay:</p>
<blockquote><p>“These AIs have to be trained. Tay didn’t understand “Holocaust” as the Holocaust, it understood it as a blank word or an event. And the things before it as negative, so thus if asked “Do you think the Holocaust is real?” and then being told “Yes, it’s not real” or repeat after me “BLANK PERSON is a f—ing jerk,” it teaches the corpus those phrases and reinforces them as appropriate responses.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Whenever Microsoft does decide to rerelease Tay, they’ll need to keep in mind positive and negative interactions, large amounts of user testing and language comprehension.</p>
<p>Image of Microsoft store courtesy of <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/jeepersmedia/15966273430/in/photolist-qjTjQo-qjTkkG-owZ4o4-8ooubZ-qjSEJm-pErGVu-qzaaz9-qzaafw-qBgzEK-qBntWQ-ovee7S-rcddSo-qjZEuF-pErGbU-pEF2Sk-pEF26k-6EX2CH-qjSDNy-qza9PG-pErGTA-pErGqm-pEF2Cc-pErGiY-qza9yw-qBnsMA-qjSEow-rcjTrK-rtFhW7-AHzD1-4tCp8M-dGyrX-f7sz-5D68f7-68rzD-9mtDtV-jQSMKQ-9mwJgj-4s9mqe-4pq2tD-4pqj1g-8qm3fE-7Hi4KT-4rajfL-y2SQX-85V8X6-vfHoyy-L9aqg-L8VDW-L8VNC-b7wBV">Mike Mozart</a> / Flickr. CC2.0 License. Edited.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/bots-gone-bad-what-we-can-learn-from-microsofts-tay-malfunction/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Perfect Tool(s) for Joining the SMS Bot Gold Rush</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/the-perfect-tools-for-joining-the-sms-bot-gold-rush/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/the-perfect-tools-for-joining-the-sms-bot-gold-rush/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Big Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/the-perfect-tools-for-joining-the-sms-bot-gold-rush/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Through the history of the Internet, we’ve seen a bots of all flavors (scrapers, viruses, worms), all often giving bots a bad name. They’re small bits of code that can carry out a host of malicious actions&#8211;stealing web content, screwing up web analytics, and encouraging click fraud.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This all sounds pretty dire, but more recently, the concept of bots has been harnessed for more and more good. And one of its new and improved forms is  conversational SMS bots.</span><span id="more-7406"></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But what precipitated their rise? Well, there’s a whole movement spawning from the concept that “You don’t need an app for that.”  Back in 2013, South African technology writer and TED speaker Toby Shapshak </span><a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/toby_shapshak_you_don_t_need_an_app_for_that?language=en"><span style="font-weight: 400;">gave a talk</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> extolling the virtues of mobile, calling it “the gold of today,” and highlighting how Africans are using SMS in particular to innovate and solve problems. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Want to learn how to get the most milk from your cow? Join iCow’s texting program. Want to use SMS for mobile commerce? Try M-PESA. It’s so powerful, in fact, that as Shapshak explains:</span></p>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400;">“Something like 25 million dollars a day is transacted through M-Pesa. Forty percent of Kenya&#8217;s GDP moves through M-Pesa using [feature phones].”</span></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It seems like now the U.S. is finally catching up with Africa on the use of SMS for business, putting its own Silicon Valley, bot-powered spin on things. </span><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2016/01/06/assist-bot/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">TechCrunch</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> even cited 2016 as the year of the chat bot, citing conversational SMS bot </span><a href="http://www.assi.st/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Assist</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Assist lets you text in for a variety of different tasks&#8211;getting a ride, sending flowers, ordering food, etc. It seems simple enough, but this company has taken Silicon Valley by storm, drawing in over </span><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2016/01/06/assist-bot/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">$5.5 million</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in seed funding.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So, similar to during the great American gold rush, if you’re going jump on this wave and contribute an awesome conversational SMS bot to the business world or to consumers, you’ll need the right tools. Maybe you can code and have time, or maybe you can code but don’t have time. More likely, you’re part of the majority that can’t code and doesn’t have time. Either way, here’s an off-the shelf tool that will make your SMS-bot-dreams suddenly more real. </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wait, “SMS bot-dreams”? Did we just make up a new term?</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">OneReach has  created the perfect tool for this important moment, wherein the world is harnessing bots for good &#8211; conversational bots that help businesses and consumers to get what they need.</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">We’ve created software that makes it easy, fast and affordable for anyone to create conversational phone or SMS bots that can do almost anything &#8211; it all comes down to what you program them to do. And the best part is that no coding is required and it’s all automatically reportable (sounds like a lie, I know). So when I say anyone can create their own conversational SMS or voice app, I really mean it. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bots are hot and they’re  where the communication conversation is heading this year. Whether you’re replacing a mobile app with clever automated SMS, or putting automated (or live) SMS concierge service in place for a boutique hotel, OneReach just made it way easier to create your SMS bot.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’ve got “SMS bot dreams” &#8211; simple or complex &#8211; I’d love to take on the challenge of seeing how easy OneReach makes it to bring your vision to life.</span></p>
<p><strong>To learn more about adding texting to your business, <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/10-things-about-text">download our whitepaper here</a>.</strong></p>
<p>Image of gold iPhone courtesy of <a href="https://picjumbo.com/iphone-5s-backside/">Picjumbo</a>. CC0 License. Edited</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/the-perfect-tools-for-joining-the-sms-bot-gold-rush/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Your Business Needs a Bot</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/why-your-business-needs-a-bot/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/why-your-business-needs-a-bot/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Big Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Self-Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/why-your-business-needs-a-bot/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Both technological capabilities and consumer preferences are evolving faster than ever before, which amplifies the challenge organizations have as they attempt to establish and maintain competitive advantage. It is not surprising, then, that organizations of all sizes are struggling to adopt artificial intelligence and weave it into a comprehensive consumer engagement strategy.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The promise of artificial intelligence (AI) is compelling; a world where humans can interact with intelligent computers to perform tasks more efficiently. While 2016 may not be the year the promise of AI is fully realized, it is certainly the year that it becomes an integral part of  communication strategies for leading organizations. In fact, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">these emerging capabilities are increasingly being applied to business.</span></p>
<p><span id="more-7396"></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">IBM Watson, for example, is incorporating its machine learning offerings into healthcare, finance and education. With a conversational nature and vast knowledge base, AI is a natural fit for business. It’s such a good fit, in fact, that it’s slowly rendering the apps businesses have focused on over the past few years obsolete.</span></p>
<h2><b>An interface out of place</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For the past few years, businesses have relied on mobile apps to interact with their customers, and it’s not hard to see why. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But mobile apps aren’t always going to be the best channel to engage with customers. Getting your customers to download your </span><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2016/1/6/10718282/internet-bots-messaging-slack-facebook-m"><span style="font-weight: 400;">application</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is expensive (averaging $4.73 per installation). In addition, getting your customers to keep your mobile application on their phone is difficult: Despite the fact that every day over 50 million mobile apps are downloaded, </span><a href="http://www.nuance.com/ucmprod/groups/enterprise/@web-enus/documents/collateral/nc_020218.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">95% are abandoned</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> within a month. Finally, getting your customers to use your mobile application more than once is difficult: </span><a href="https://info.dynatrace.com/rs/compuware/images/Mobile_App_Survey_Report.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">79% of consumers</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> will only retry an app once or twice before abandoning it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With most apps touting different user interfaces and functions, it’s no surprise that messaging apps have surged to the forefront of the app market. Their simplicity and ease of conversation, not to mention free or low cost communication, attracts users the world over (six out of 10 of the top global mobile apps are </span><a href="http://www.slideshare.net/kleinerperkins/internet-trends-v1/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">messaging apps</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">). But keep in mind that native text messaging (SMS) lays claim as the most adopted and frequently used feature on a phone, according to <a href="http://www.pewinternet.org/2015/04/01/us-smartphone-use-in-2015/#smartphones">Pew Research</a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Given the landscape outline above, some key questions emerge. Where does artificial intelligence come into play? What are the best channels to introduce AI? Why is it that mobile applications and websites aren’t enough anymore to have a complete mobile strategy?</span></p>
<h2><b>Enter the age of the chat bot.</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now you might be asking yourself, &#8220;What is a bot?&#8221; Truthfully, there are many definitions. Many will wait to see what </span><a href="https://www.facebook.com/zuck/posts/10102577175875681"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mark Zuckerberg</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> comes up with. But for the sake of this article we’ll focus on chatbots,  an evolution beyond the traditional virtual assistant. A chat bot is an automated communication tool that can process natural language via text message (SMS, Facebook Message, etc.) and </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">actually transact. </span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">2016 is the beginning of the post-graphical, pre-voice UI era (more on this to come), where text-based messaging is all you need to book a flight, make dinner reservations, or check to see if your local coffee shop has any of that espresso that you really like. And best of all, the messaging experience can be powered by artificially intelligent chat bots that can process natural language inputs and actually transact.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But this brings a  few key questions come to mind:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">What if you could engage with your customers on an application they </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">already have?</span></i></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">What if you could engage with your customers on the application </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">they use the most?</span></i></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">What if you could engage with your customers on a channel where artificial intelligence is </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">real</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">accessible to you today?</span></i></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can, and you can do it through text messaging. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to Pew Research, texting is the most-used “app” on a smartphone, with 97% of respondents reporting that they used it at least once a day. From a business standpoint, texting platforms can also leverage integrations, such as those of artificial intelligence, to provide a personalized, more intelligent customer experiences. Texting is the first natural step for companies seeking to add AI to their business communications and be the proprietors of an intelligently automated customer experience.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is extremely important, because currently, companies like </span><a href="http://getmagicnow.com"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Magic</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> are making it possible for </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">your customers</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> give their business to who Magic thinks is best. </span><a href="http://www.wired.com/2015/08/facebook-launches-m-new-kind-virtual-assistant/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Facebook M</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is allowing </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">your customers</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to conduct commerce over Facebook Messenger. As a business owner, you should be asking, </span><b>“What role does my company play in these transactions?”</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><b>“How can I let my customers engage with us in the same way, </b><b><i>or better</i></b><b>?&#8221;</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Why rely on third-party solutions that allow customers to communicate with them over their channel of choice (messaging), when you could let your customers communicate in the same way directly with you? This is why your company needs a chat bot; so your customers can communicate and transact with you the way they want to without having to go through a third-party.</span></p>
<h2><b>&#8220;This sounds really complicated.&#8221;</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Think of building a chat bot as an exercise in composition, rather than development. Your company likely has many APIs that are already being used to power your mobile applications and internal tools. By using these existing APIs (both your internal ones and the ones offered by your existing software partners such as Salesforce, Stripe, etc.) in conjunction with powerful artificial intelligence services (such as IBM Watson), you have the technological bases covered. Think of SMS (or any messaging app) as just another interface to many of the features that you’ve already made available through other applications. Often times this ‘conversational UI’ is simply allowing you to get more value from the APIs that you’ve already built. </span></p>
<h2><b>Conclusion</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s not hard to get started with a chat bot&#8211;far from it. To get going, combine those various services you’ll need (AI, payment, communication) using a platform that allows you to iterate and pilot rapidly&#8211;preferably with a visual design tool. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The timing for chat bots is now. Businesses are just starting to realize their value, and the technology has been around long enough to reduce risk.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The only question that remains is:</span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">“What are you waiting for?”</span></em></p>
<p><strong>To learn more about providing a great customer experience through text messaging, <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/mobile-strategy">download our whitepaper here</a>.</strong></p>
<p>Image of <a href="https://pixabay.com/en/woman-artificial-intelligence-506322/">woman artificial intelligence</a> courtesy of Pixabay. CC0 License.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/why-your-business-needs-a-bot/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 Things to Consider When Building Your Own Communication Solution</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/3-things-to-consider-when-building-your-own-communication-solution/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/3-things-to-consider-when-building-your-own-communication-solution/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Big Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Communication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Operations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech Support]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/3-things-to-consider-when-building-your-own-communication-solution/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Empowerment. That is the word that comes to mind when one considers how recent technological changes have affected a business’ ability to create compelling communication experiences. Despite the fact that the basic tools for making a phone call haven’t changed much in the last 150 years (even your smartphone still offers you a standard numeric keypad, not so different from the rotary phones of old), we are entering an age of innovation around communications such that the world has never seen before. And best of all, many of these technologies don’t require heavy-lifting from IT teams.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Unlike the monolithic incumbents in the enterprise communication space that require multi-million dollar upfront investments and multi-year deployment schedules, the future of communication lies in software. Developers are now able to leverage communication APIs to build proofs of concept in hours or days that they can share with their business partners. Similarly, business analysts can leverage drag-and-drop user interfaces to build communication solutions in minutes, without having to request development resources. Never before have both technical people and non-technical people had so much ability to create meaningful solutions.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, there are real risks and process challenges to account for when trying to build your own communication solution. There are both technological and experiential conditions that you must account for.</span></p>
<h2><span id="more-7386"></span><b>Getting company-wide buy-in</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Getting company-wide buy-in is crucial for any project’s success, and it is not always easy to ascertain. One of the leading causes of project failure is lack of collaboration; </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">over 85% of employees and executives cite lack of</span><a href="http://work.com/blog/2012/08/is-poor-collaboration-killing-your-company-infographic/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">collaboration</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> as leading to a project’s failure</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Furthermore, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">75% of business and</span><a href="http://www.geneca.com/75-business-executives-anticipate-software-projects-fail/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">IT executives</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> think their IT projects are doomed from the start, and project managers say executives ultimately determine what the fate of the project will be</span><a href="http://reports.informationweek.com/abstract/83/12175/IT-Business-Strategy/research-2014-enterprise-project-management-survey.html"><span style="font-weight: 400;"> 63% of the time</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, be it elimination or deferment. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">By taking a new approach (either building a POC on top of a communication API or a Software-as-a-Service application), the “go/no go” discussions will be far more productive. Think of it this way&#8211;in less time than it would take a business analyst to document requirements and engage with their technical counterparts to scope out level of effort, that same person could build a proof of concept and share a working example of a proposed solution to spark more productive conversations with the stakeholders. This makes it easier to achieve a shared vision and more buy-in.</span></p>
<h2><b>Lack of user experience expertise</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Communication solutions are usually customer facing, thus amplifying the risk associated with introducing a new experience. Creating an ‘on-brand’ customer experience is no small feat, and requires rapid cycles of design, build, test, repeat. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Leaving experience design in the hands of a developer (or skipping the experience design process altogether) is risky; customers have expectations that you’ll likely want to meet and understand.  If they’re not trained in UX design, your developers may end up creating an experience that isn’t on brand and doesn’t improve the relationship with your customers. Furthermore, custom programming a solution may inhibit the ability to iterate rapidly and improve the experience over time. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For example, building a text-messaging notification solution using a communication API provider is quite simple, but developers often neglect the fact that recipients will reply to those text messages and therefore don’t have any response strategy. In addition, if you develop your own solution, you will also have to build a user experience report in order to know where and how the solution can be improved. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Conversely, using a SaaS application that has productized many features that protect the ability to iterate rapidly based on real data allows for the experience to be improved over time, and without having to request developer resources every time a change is requested. The pace of improvement is therefore instant.</span></p>
<h2><b>Cost of development and maintenance</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Developers love to build things, but they don’t enjoy the ongoing care and feeding that enterprise communication solutions require. And the ugly truth is that developing a custom solution, rather than configuring it through an existing software application, requires much more investment than you might think. Developing against third-party communication APIs removes nearly all of the complexity surrounding the complicated telephony network, but the normal software costs are still required, including:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Application monitoring</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Infrastructure monitoring</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Load balancing</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Database management</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Quality assurance testing</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Infrastructure maintenance</span></li>
</ul>
<h2><b>Benefits of using SaaS applications</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As outlined above, developing your own cloud communication solution can come with some big risks. However, creating it through a SaaS platform offers several key benefits:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><b><b>Time to market. </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Even if you have a very clear vision for the ideal solution, it can take time to get your solution to where you want it to be and constant change requests burden the development team. With a hosted cloud communication solution, you can get any changes or updates deployed in no time.</span></b></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><b>Built-in features. </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Most cloud communication platforms will come with built-in features to eliminate the complexity of custom development. By productizing certain features, including integrations, users can leverage best practices and benefit from features that would otherwise be left in the ‘nice to have’ column and never be developed.. </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><b>Flexibility. </b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Hosted cloud solutions come with a lot of flexibility, from custom design for communication flows to integrations to even custom skins that reflect your brand.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><b>Built-in support team. </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">If something were to go wrong with your own solution, you’d have to devote your own resources to troubleshoot and fix it. With a hosted cloud communication solution, you have a dedicated support team on hand that will diagnose and correct any issues without you having to do a thing.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><b>Business continuity. </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Instead of having to custom develop integrations with CRMs or other systems you might use, a hosted cloud solution will usually come with built-in integrations with the most popular CRMs. This way, you can ensure the right data is being passed between your cloud system and CRM. And if you’re using proprietary systems, it is easier to configure a custom integration than it is to develop one.</span></li>
</ul>
<h2><b>Conclusion</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Developing your own cloud communication solution comes with inherent risks and pitfalls. By investing in an existing cloud platform, you’ll save money in the process and be able to provide your customers with a professional, well-designed customer experience.</span></p>
<p><strong>To learn more about designing a great customer experience, <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/omnichannel-seamless-experience">download our whitepaper here</a>.</strong></p>
<p>Image by Unsplash via <a href="https://pixabay.com/en/work-typing-computer-notebook-731198/">Pixabay</a>. CC0 License. Edited.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/3-things-to-consider-when-building-your-own-communication-solution/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Year End Review: Customer Service Trends in 2015 and Beyond</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/year-end-review-customer-service-trends-in-2015-and-beyond/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/year-end-review-customer-service-trends-in-2015-and-beyond/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Big Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Communication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Contact Center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Self-Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trends]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/year-end-review-customer-service-trends-in-2015-and-beyond/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As we look back on 2015, it’s tempting to refer to that age-old adage: “The more things change, the more things stay the same.”</p>
<p>This year, that couldn’t be further from the truth.</p>
<p>That’s because 2015 was the year the technology really made its presence known in customer service. Automation, artificial intelligence, social media, CRM integrations, texting&#8211;all were major customer service trends in 2015.</p>
<h2><span id="more-7370"></span><strong>Customer Service Trends in 2015</strong></h2>
<p>2015 was the year that:</p>
<p><strong>Customer service got smart.</strong> This year, artificial intelligence wasn’t just limited to the realms of science fiction a la Age of Ultron—it was also slowly incorporated into different companies’ service offerings. Amazon made its entry into the home automation market with Alexa, a virtual assistant that can field questions ranging from the time of day to traffic predictions to good restaurants nearby. On the enterprise-level side, IBM continued to expand the capabilities of Jeopardy-winning Watson, adding self-service into varied industries like healthcare, education and finance, among others.</p>
<p><strong>Customer service got automated.</strong> Over <a href="http://www.dimensiondata.com/Global/Downloadable%20Documents/2015%20Global%20Contact%20Centre%20Benchmarking%20Summary%20Report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">55% of customers</a> would like a self-service experience, which provides businesses with the unique opportunity to speed up the customer experience while decreasing costs. In the restaurant industry, established chains like Outback Steakhouse and Olive Garden let customers <a href="http://www.csmonitor.com/Business/Saving-Money/2015/0514/Restaurant-table-tablets-A-gimmick-or-actually-helpful" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">order via tablets</a>, while market newcomer <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2015/09/09/upshot/restaurant-of-the-future-service-with-an-impersonal-touch.html?_r=2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Eatsa</a> automated the bulk of the food delivery process. Automated self-service also extended to digital channels—companies like <a href="http://www.toistersolutions.com/blog/2015/10/28/automation-fail-how-attcares-stumbled-into-a-tweet-chat" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">AT&amp;T</a> automated social media responses (not always with the best outcome), while <a href="https://www.twilio.com/customers/stories/uber" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Uber</a>, Snooze and more texted customers about the status of their ride or table.</p>
<p><strong>Customer service got focused.</strong> Over 80% of companies want to use <a href="https://fonolo.com/blog/2013/09/17-important-customer-experience-statistics-for-the-call-center/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">customer service</a> as a way to differentiate themselves from their competition. But what defines a good customer service experience? In 2015, we interviewed over 60 industry influencers and found that the best way to <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/customer-service-report-2015" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">improve customer service</a> was to focus on the employee experience. By focusing on employees and treating them with respect, companies can ensure that they pass that goodwill onto customers. Case in point: <a href="https://jobs.zappos.com/why-zappos" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Zappos</a> or <a href="http://www.google.com/about/careers/lifeatgoogle/benefits/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Google</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Customer service got diversified.</strong> In 2015, companies made an effort to diversify their service offerings, providing support on established and emerging channels.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Mobile.</strong> In 2015, companies increasingly relied on mobile to interact with their customers. This year saw the official launch of Apple Pay, Starbucks’ continued success with mobile app <a href="http://www.nfcworld.com/2015/07/24/336798/one-in-five-starbucks-sales-in-the-us-made-with-mobile-payments/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">payments</a> (more than $9 million in orders processed per week) and Magic’s simple but powerful text concierge service. As mentioned above, more and more companies saw the value of adding texting to their support strategy, making it easier for customers to contact them on a channel they prefer. However, not every attempt to implement mobile customer service was successful—Domino’s unfortunately disappointed some customers with the rollout of its text-to-order service.</p>
<p><strong>Video.</strong> Audiovisual communication has been popular among consumers for years, but 2015 was the year when video really started to gain a foothold in B2C interactions. Amazon’s Mayday is probably the most well-known example, but <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2015/01/28/this-is-webrtcs-yearor-is-it/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">American Express</a> and other companies helped customers solve their problems over video. WebRTC’s open source nature also made it easier for any company to incorporate video into their service offering.</p>
<p><strong>Social.</strong> 2015 was the year social platforms got serious about customer service interactions. <a href="https://twitter.app.box.com/customer-service-on-twitter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Twitter</a>released a customer service playbook outlining the benefits of using social for customer service, as well as how to apply it to an organization. <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2015/06/15/facebook-pages-can-now-show-how-quickly-they-respond-to-customers-messages/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Facebook</a> also launched a new feature that keeps track of how long it takes company pages to respond to customer messages, giving customers better insight into the responsiveness of an organization. This is especially important, given the fact that over 40% of customers expect a response on <a href="http://www.convinceandconvert.com/social-media-research/42-percent-of-consumers-complaining-in-social-media-expect-60-minute-response-time/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">social</a> in 60 minutes or less.</p>
<p><strong>Voice.</strong> Voice is still king in contact center service interactions, but times are changing. Research from<a href="http://www.dimensiondata.com/Global/Downloadable%20Documents/2015%20Global%20Contact%20Centre%20Benchmarking%20Summary%20Report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Dimension Data</a> found that while voice accounts for 65% of all contact center interactions, digital interactions will surpass voice by the end of 2017. And with <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/07/07/technology/tech-companies-leave-phone-calls-behind.html?_r=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Internet-based companies</a> making a concerted attempt to direct customers towards digital, with other companies ditching corporate <a href="http://www.inc.com/associated-press/jpmorgan-chase-getting-rid-of-voicemail-for-some-employees.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">voicemail</a>, it became very clear in that businesses couldn’t just rely on voice for communication.</p>
<p><strong>Web chat</strong>. Over 70% of contact centers will offer web chat by the end of 2016, up from just 33% in 2015. There are several reasons why companies would want to invest in web chat—it’s cheaper than voice, agents can handle multiple conversations at once and respond in real-time, etc. And there’s a reason companies from Nordstrom to Nike are using web chat to interact with customers—while 91% of customers are happy with web chat’s ability to solve customer support issues, 62% of customers are more inclined to buy a product if live chat is available.</p></blockquote>
<h2><strong>Looking ahead to 2016</strong></h2>
<p>2015 was an exciting year for customer service, with lots of progress made in digital interactions and automation. 2016 is set to be an equally exciting year, if not more so, as companies continue to build on the advances made in 2015. We can’t say for sure what will happen in customer service in 2016, but we’ve got a few ideas.</p>
<p>Below are our customer service predictions for 2016.</p>
<p><strong>Continued rise in cloud computing</strong>. In 2016, businesses will continue to migrate to the <a href="http://www.icmi.com/Resources/Technology/2014/05/Is-the-Cloud-Contact-Center-Passing-You-By" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">cloud</a> for its accessibility, storage, simplicity, and security, among other benefits. In fact, 88% of businesses are currently using the <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/benkepes/2015/03/04/new-stats-from-the-state-of-cloud-report/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">public cloud</a>. In addition, <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/louiscolumbus/2015/09/27/roundup-of-cloud-computing-forecasts-and-market-estimates-q3-update-2015/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gartner</a> predicts that by 2020, roughly 25% of organizations will use cloud-based CRMs. Cloud-based software-as-a-service, or <a href="http://www.pwc.com/gx/en/industries/technology/publications/global-software-100-leaders/saas-trends.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SaaS</a>, will also become more prevalent, growing at a rate of 21.3% per year and making up 14.2% of software spending. <a href="http://www.statista.com/statistics/273642/worldwide-software-as-a-service-revenue-forecast/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SaaS revenue</a> is predicted to hit $32.8 billion in revenue in 2016, up 17% from 2015.</p>
<p><strong>Delivering on the omnichannel promise. </strong>In 2013, <a href="https://d16cvnquvjw7pr.cloudfront.net/resources/whitepapers/Omnichannel-Customer-Service-Gap.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Zendesk </a>research found that over 85% of customers thought companies needed to do a better job of providing a seamless experience. In 2015, companies were on the right track but weren’t quite there yet—nearly 50% of contact centers named integration of Web, contact center and CRM systems as their top challenge, with <a href="http://www.dimensiondata.com/Global/Downloadable%20Documents/2015%20Global%20Contact%20Centre%20Benchmarking%20Summary%20Report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">integration</a> of systems to enable channel hopping close behind (41%). We predict that in 2016, companies will continue to take steps toward providing an omnichannel experience. Companies will find and use service platforms that manage and can integrate with multiple service channels/CRMs and similar systems.</p>
<p><strong>Personalization.</strong> This trend is a combination of the previous two trends—cloud services will enable companies to provide a personalized experience across channels. We predict that the ability to integrate customer data into service interactions will become increasingly mainstream in 2016, both in response to <a href="http://venturebeat.com/2015/07/14/consumers-want-privacy-yet-demand-personalization/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">consumer demand</a> and a desire to differentiate on great <a href="https://fonolo.com/blog/2013/09/17-important-customer-experience-statistics-for-the-call-center/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">customer experiences</a>. The SaaS pricing model of most cloud services will also make it easy for businesses of any size to provide great customer service.</p>
<p><strong>Proactive customer service.</strong> <a href="http://www.wired.com/insights/2014/11/the-internet-of-things-bigger/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Internet of Things</a> is rapidly changing our personal and professional lives. IoT-based companies, but other businesses as well, will leverage customer data to provide a proactive service experience. Although IoT is primarily focused on the B2C experience (think FitBit or any smartfridge), other organizations can learn from IoT innovations. Take, for example, the proactive service experience industry pundits anticipate will take shape in the IoT industry: <a href="http://www.destinationcrm.com/Articles/Web-Exclusives/Viewpoints/Revolutionizing-Customer-Service-with-the-Internet-of-Things-105722.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gartner</a> predicts that by 2018, five percent of IoT devices will automatically trigger service cases.</p>
<p><strong>More artificial intelligence.</strong> In 2016, AI will continue to get smarter, and its presence in business will continue to grow. This is evidenced by the amount of <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/article/artificial-intelligence-in-business-the-state-of-play-and-future-prospects/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">venture capital</a> being put toward AI-centered businesses, which grew from $75 million in 2013 to $300 million in 2014. And while <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/article/artificial-intelligence-in-business-the-state-of-play-and-future-prospects/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">artificial intelligence</a> is primarily being used for voice recognition and response, <a href="http://www.destinationcrm.com/Articles/Editorial/Magazine-Features/The-2015-CRM-Rising-Stars-IBMs-Watson-Brings-Cognitive-Computing-to-Customer-Support-102108.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gartner</a> predicts that 10% of computers will be able to learn from past interactions by 2017. At OneReach, we’re helping to make this possible through the use of AI in IVRs or self-service.</p>
<p><strong>Moving towards a mobile-first future.</strong> Our world is becoming increasingly mobilized—nearly two billion global citizens now own a <a href="http://www.emarketer.com/Article/2-Billion-Consumers-Worldwide-Smartphones-by-2016/1011694" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">smartphone</a>. This mobile change extends to customer service, where 62% of companies think <a href="http://www.icmi.com/About-ICMI/Press-Room/2013-Mobile-Customer-Service-Strategy-Results-Released" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">mobile service</a> is a competitive differentiator and 64% of customers would prefer to text customer service. Texting is poised to make a big gain in the customer service field, with more than 60% of <a href="http://www.dimensiondata.com/Global/Downloadable%20Documents/2015%20Global%20Contact%20Centre%20Benchmarking%20Summary%20Report.pdf/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">contact centers</a>offering it by 2017. In 2016, we predict that companies will continue to provide customer service on mobile devices, whether it’s via text message, mobile applications, mobile websites, or other channels.</p>
<p><strong>More digital/emerging channels.</strong> As mentioned above, customer service interactions will shift to focus on emerging digital channels, both in response to consumer preference and cost savings. Take, for instance, the increased use emerging channels: One in four contact centers will offer <a href="http://www.dimensiondata.com/Global/Downloadable%20Documents/2015%20Global%20Contact%20Centre%20Benchmarking%20Summary%20Report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">video</a> by the end of 2017, one in two contact centers will offer a smartphone app by the end of 2017, and three out of five contact centers will offer texting/IM by the end of 2017.</p>
<h2><strong>Conclusion</strong></h2>
<p>2015 was a big year for customer service, and 2016 is set to be an even bigger one. We predict that new applications of technology like artificial intelligence and automation will define customer service in the coming years, as they already have today. Companies and contact centers that embrace the customer service trends in 2015 and beyond are poised to make an impact on the market that will be felt for years to come.</p>
<p><strong>For more on how to improve your customer service in 2016, <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/customer-service-report-2015">download our influencer report</a> with insights from more than 60 customer service pros.</strong></p>
<p><em>This post originally appeared on <a href="http://www.icmi.com/Resources/Customer-Experience/2016/01/Customer-Service-Trends-in-2015-and-What-They-Mean-for-2016">ICMI</a> and has been republished with permission. </em></p>
<p>Image credit: <a href="https://pixabay.com/en/man-guy-smoking-cigarettes-bench-691422/">Unsplash</a>. CC0 License. Edited.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/year-end-review-customer-service-trends-in-2015-and-beyond/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>OneReach Helps Power City of Evanston&#8217;s Restaurant Inspection Text Messages</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/onereach-helps-power-city-of-evanstons-restaurant-inspection-text-messages/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/onereach-helps-power-city-of-evanstons-restaurant-inspection-text-messages/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Big Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ITR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Use Cases]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/onereach-helps-power-city-of-evanstons-restaurant-inspection-text-messages/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The city of Evanston, Ill. has worked with OneReach to provide residents with the ability to check the health inspection scores of local restaurants over text.</p>
<p><span id="more-7369"></span>Diners can text the keyword &#8220;food&#8221; to the city&#8217;s 311 number, and then text the name of the restaurant to see the health inspection score, as well as the date the inspection took place.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.govtech.com/health/Texting-Helps-in-Fight-Against-Foodborne-Illnesses-in-Evanston-Ill.html">Government Technology</a> points out that the use of texting makes getting restaurant scores a lot easier for consumers:</p>
<blockquote><p>It’s simple and much easier than Yelp’s mobile app, which compels users to tap and swipe their way to a restaurant’s “More Info” tab and deep dive through a list of miscellaneous information.</p></blockquote>
<p>The food safety text initiative follows the city&#8217;s initiative to local restaurant inspection scores onto Yelp.</p>
<p><strong>Check out the full article on <a href="http://www.govtech.com/health/Texting-Helps-in-Fight-Against-Foodborne-Illnesses-in-Evanston-Ill.html">Government Technology</a>, and don&#8217;t forget to <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/high-demand-for-text-message-2014-report">download our report</a> on why 64% of customers would rather text than call your business. </strong></p>
<p>Image credit: <a href="https://pixabay.com/en/iphone-5s-cafe-office-apple-hand-1114403/">dangquocbuu</a>. CC0 license. Edited.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/onereach-helps-power-city-of-evanstons-restaurant-inspection-text-messages/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>7 Lessons Star Wars Can Teach You about Customer Service</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/7-lessons-star-wars-can-teach-you-about-customer-service/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/7-lessons-star-wars-can-teach-you-about-customer-service/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Big Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/7-lessons-star-wars-can-teach-you-about-customer-service/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With <em>Star Wars: Episode VII – The Force Awakens</em> set to debut in just a few days’ time, we couldn’t be more excited. The decades-old space saga is sure to send us on a new, fantastical adventure, complete with lessons on friendship, family and the Force (and of course, lightsaber duels).</p>
<p>In the midst of all this excitement, we realized that there were a few things we could learn from Star Wars about customer service. So now, we’re bringing insights from a galaxy far, far away a little closer to home.</p>
<h2><span id="more-7364"></span><strong>“Do. Or do not. There is no try.” – Yoda</strong></h2>
<p>Yoda gives Luke this advice when he’s training in the swampland of Dagobah, but you don’t need to be in a galaxy far, far away to learn from these insights. That’s because in customer service, your job is to do, and do not. Do whatever is in your power to solve the customer’s problem. Don’t leave them with a bad experience. You can’t just attempt to do something, you need to follow through and be consistent. Then be able to provide good customer service you will.</p>
<h2><strong>“Help me Obi-Wan Kenobi, you’re my only hope.” – Princess Leia</strong></h2>
<p>When a customer comes to you, they may have tried using a variety of different channels to get help and might be at their breaking point. They really are counting on you to help solve their problems. In fact, a <a href="http://cdn.zendesk.com/resources/whitepapers/Omnichannel-Customer-Service-Gap.pdf">Zendesk</a> study found that 88% of customers said problem resolution was important to them (89% said speed of resolution was important as well). Take a look at past customer interactions to help inform your current interaction, increasingly the likelihood that you’ll be able to solve their problem, or at least direct them to a person who can.</p>
<h2><strong>“Great, kid. Don’t get cocky.” – Han Solo</strong></h2>
<p>Being able to solve a customer’s problem quickly and effectively is a wonderful feeling. However, one good experience doesn’t define them all. As customer service Jedi <a href="http://hyken.com/customer-loyalty/customer-service-tool-consistency/">Shep Hyken</a> states, you need to provide a consistently great experience: “Confidence comes when the customer knows what to expect, and gets it every time.” One great experience can help build the foundation of a great relationship between company and customer, but only consistency can ensure that that bond stays strong.</p>
<h2><strong>“I find your lack of faith disturbing.” – Darth Vader</strong></h2>
<p>Customers have lost faith in customer service agents’ ability to help them—just look at the <a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/7/15/5901057/comcast-call-cancel-service-ryan-block">Comcast cancellation call</a> and the fallout that followed. Perhaps this is because customer expectations are pretty high. Research has found that over <a href="http://www.parature.com/2013-customer-expectations/">60% of customers</a> expect agents to be more knowledgeable, and 37% expect to be able to contact the same <a href="http://cdn.zendesk.com/resources/whitepapers/Omnichannel-Customer-Service-Gap.pdf">service representative</a> regardless of the channel they use. But don’t lose faith—most customer service agents do a great job of meeting customer needs. In fact, in response to a demand for omnichannel customer service, 35% of agents are now multiskilled across various communication.</p>
<h2><strong>“These aren’t the droids you’re looking for.” – Obi-Wan Kenobi</strong></h2>
<p>In customer service, it can be easy to get distracted and solely rely on metrics to gauge your performance: CSAT, NPS, etc. However, while these numbers are a good benchmark, each interaction is unique and deserves to be treated as such. The average handle time might be under three minutes, but if a customer will need more help than can fit into that timeframe, you have to set the numbers aside for a moment and recognize that good service can’t always be quantified.</p>
<h2><strong>“You have that power too. In time you&#8217;ll learn to use it as I have.” – Luke Skywalker</strong></h2>
<p>Just as a padawan needs training before he’s ready to become a Jedi, so do customer service agents need training to provide great service to customers. Over 30% of agents think training would increase their <a href="http://2020workforce.com/2014/12/08/what-benefits-increase-employee-loyalty-and-engagement/">engagement</a> and loyalty. In addition, 29% of employees believe the ability to learn and get <a href="http://blog.accessdevelopment.com/index.php/2014/08/employee-engagement-loyalty-statistics-the-ultimate-collection">trained quickly</a> is an attribute that is important to their employer. By taking time to focus on the employee experience and develop their skills, companies can empower agents to empower customers through regular training, one-on-one support sessions and more. It’s a win-win!</p>
<h2><strong>“Judge me by my size, do you?” – Yoda</strong></h2>
<p>With the rise of cloud-based products and SaaS model pricing, companies of any size can now provide great customer service. For small, growing companies, establishing a close working relationship and providing great service is crucial, as that will be how you maintain and grow your customer base. For bigger companies with a larger customer base, it’s still important that you don’t let great customer service fall by the wayside. Even if you’re dealing with a high volume of customers and working against preset metrics, make sure each interaction still has that human touch.</p>
<h2><strong>“No, I am your father.” – Darth Vader </strong></h2>
<p>You didn’t think we wouldn’t include this one, did you? <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/12.0.0-1/72x72/1f609.png" alt="😉" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>Agree with our quotes, or think we missed an important one? Let us know in the comments, and may the Force be with you!</p>
<p><strong>Looking to provide a mobile customer experience that’s out of this world? <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/mobile-strategy">Download our new whitepaper</a> to find out why texting is an essential part of your mobile strategy.</strong></p>
<p>Images via Lucasfilm/Disney. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crux#/media/File:Crux_(Southern_Cross)_from_Hobart,_Tasmania.jpg">Space background</a> from Wikipedia. <a href="http://www.fsbgames.ru/load/arhiv/mods/star_wars_interregnum/1-1-0-41">Darth Vader image</a> from FSB Games (edited). <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lightsaber">Lightsaber image</a> from Wikipedia (edited). <a href="http://darksidetoy.com/Stormtroopers-Sixth-Scale-1-6-Figure-Set-Movie-Masterpiece-Series-by-Hot-Toys">Stormtrooper image</a> from Dark Side Toy (edited). <a href="http://gamasutra.com/blogs/RaphKoster/20150417/241406/A_Jedi_Saga.php">Yoda image</a> from Gamasutra (edited). <a href="http://starwars.wikia.com/wiki/29_BBY">Han Solo image</a> from Star Wars Wiki. <a href="http://wookiee.ru/encyclopedia/princessleia">Princess Leia image</a> from Wookiee (edited). <a href="http://s1003.photobucket.com/user/NinjaBOB9000/media/Obi-WanKenobi_zpsbeabb7be.png.html">Obi-Wan image</a> from Photobucket (edited). <a href="http://animaljam.wikia.com/wiki/File:Luke-skywalker_starwars-1-.png">Luke image</a> from Animal Jam (edited).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/7-lessons-star-wars-can-teach-you-about-customer-service/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>What the U.S. Can Learn from Mobile Payments in Africa</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/what-the-u-s-can-learn-from-mobile-payments-in-africa/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/what-the-u-s-can-learn-from-mobile-payments-in-africa/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Big Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/what-the-u-s-can-learn-from-mobile-payments-in-africa/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mobile payments have exploded in popularity just within the past year—40% of U.S. consumers have used mobile payments in 2015, compared to just 8% in 2014. In fact,</span><a href="http://www.statista.com/statistics/226530/mobile-payment-transaction-volume-forecast/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">mobile transactions</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> are expected to surpass half a trillion dollars ($560 billion) in 2016, and Gartner predicts that</span><a href="http://www.gartner.com/newsroom/id/2971917"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">mobile commerce</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> will make of 50% of all U.S. digital commerce by 2017.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So why the startling change?</span></p>
<p><span id="more-7361"></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Part of this mobile payment boom can be attributed to the popularity of Near Field Communications (NFC), which uses a specialized receiver to read a chip in customer’s phone. The most well-known examples of NFC are</span><a href="http://www.statista.com/statistics/323422/starbucks-mobile-app-transactions-weekly/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Starbucks’ mobile payment app</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, which manages more than 8 million transactions a week, and ApplePay, whose October 2014 debut even reignited interest in</span><a href="http://www.creditcards.com/credit-card-news/mobile-payment-statistics-1276.php"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">competing mobile pay platforms</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> like Google Wallet.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, mobile payments in the U.S. haven’t seen the success these numbers might lead you to believe.</span><a href="http://www.pymnts.com/in-depth/2015/apple-pay-adoption-improving-but-still-a-long-way-to-go/#.VRFxzu6sVXp"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Over 80% of iPhone users</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> still haven’t tried Apple Pay, and although Starbucks manages millions of transactions a week, they’re just a fraction of the mobile payment market. Mobile money has gained predominance out of circumstance rather than convenience’s sake outside of the U.S., and they’ve seen great success.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It turns out the most successful mobile payment company has eschewed mobile apps altogether in favor of something far simpler: the text message.</span></p>
<h2><b>Mobile payments in Africa and the rise of M-Pesa</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Companies like Magic have already proved that</span><a href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/magic-model-instantly-build-sms-concierge-service/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">texting is a great way to pay for things</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, but they weren’t the first ones to pioneer this concept. Vodafone had already thought of it first.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Launched in 2007, M-Pesa (M for mobile, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">pesa</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the Swahili word for money) was created by Vodafone for Safaricom and Vodacom as way to</span><a href="http://www.cck.go.ke/news/2012/sector_statistics.html"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">transfer money over mobile phones</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, as well to serve as a microfinancing service. The service lets users send, receive and deposit money into their accounts, all of which is managed through text messages secured by PIN numbers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">M-Pesa has grown to become Africa’s mobile payment giant, boasting more than</span><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/10/28/the-sleeping-giants-of-african-mobile-payments/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">15 million users</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and handling US $21 million in transactions every day.</span><a href="http://www.safaricom.co.ke/personal/m-pesa/m-pesa-services"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">M-Pesa users</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> can</span><a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/business-28061813"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">use the service</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Make bulk payments</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Buy Safaricom airtime</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Deposit cash into their account</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Manage their account</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pay bills</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Send (transfer) money</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Withdraw money</span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Pay for goods like solar lighting, water, and groceries</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But why the reliance on mobile and text messaging for payments? As Vanessa Clark points out in</span><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/10/28/the-sleeping-giants-of-african-mobile-payments/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">her Techcrunch article</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, there are three factors that have driven the use of mobile money in Africa:</span></p>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Firstly…there were fewer than two million mobile phones users in Africa in 1998. This number grew to more than 400 million by 2009…Secondly, there are a large number of unbanked, and underbanked, people in Africa. A 2009 World Bank report puts this figure at as high as 70% of Africans…Finally, much of the continent’s population lives in rural areas, with very little access to banking infrastructure.</span></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The proliferation of mobile payments over text message in Africa can’t be understated.</span><a href="http://www.pewglobal.org/2015/04/15/cell-phones-in-africa-communication-lifeline/"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Over 80% of Africans</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> use their cell phones to text, and 30% use their phone to make and receive payments. This last number more than doubles in Kenya (where M-Pesa originated), with 61% of Kenyans using their phone for mobile payments. In contrast, only 2% of Africans have a working landline phone, further accentuating the prevalence and importance of mobile there.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">All of which raises the question: If texting to pay is so successful in Africa, who’s to say it won’t see the same success here?</span></p>
<h2><b>Why Companies Need to Offer Text to Pay</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the U.S., mobile is also a part of everyday life, but mobile payments haven’t seen nearly the same amount of success as they have in Kenya. And while the most common ways to</span><a href="http://www.creditcards.com/credit-card-news/mobile-payment-statistics-1276.php"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">make mobile payments</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> include mobile wallets (which rely on NFC for transactions), mobile browsers and payment applications, all of these payments are predicated on the fact that customers have a reliable internet connection, or a specific chip in their phone. It’s a lot to expect of a customer, especially when internet use (which is needed for mobile payments in the U.S.) isn’t even</span><a href="http://www.pewinternet.org/2015/04/01/chapter-three-a-week-in-the-life-analysis-of-smartphone-users"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">the most popular feature on a smartphone</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That honor goes to text messaging.</span></p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-2295 aligncenter" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/mobile-pay.png" alt="mobile pay in africa" width="294" height="224" /></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="http://www.pewinternet.org/2015/04/01/chapter-three-a-week-in-the-life-analysis-of-smartphone-users">Image credit Pew Research</a></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now imagine if businesses applied the same excitement that they did for mobile apps to text messaging. </span><b>They could make mobile payments more accessible to a larger percentage of their client base. </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">Not everyone has a smartphone or access to an internet connection, so businesses that don’t offer texting might be shutting potential customers out. For customers that do have a smartphone, they won’t always want to download an app for each specific store or chain they visit, so businesses could make sure they were still reaching all of their customers with text messaging.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Texting is also a secure way to pay—all businesses would have to do is direct customers to a secured webpage where they can enter their payment details. Customers also don’t have to be in the same location as their purchase to make a mobile payment, and they can still get the details of their purchase with pictures and descriptions of the items they’re interested in.</span></p>
<h2><b>Conclusion</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There’s nothing wrong with the way mobile payments are currently being processed in the U.S. NFC, online payments and applications all have a role to play in how we pay. But imagine what we could learn from mobile payments in Africa, if we opened up accessibility to more customers with texting.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The payoff would be huge.</span></p>
<p><strong>To learn more about the benefits of adding texting to your mobile strategy, <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/mobile-strategy">download our whitepaper here</a>.</strong></p>
<p>Image from <a href="http://afritorial.com/2013-africa-innovation-prize/">Afritorial</a>. Edited.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/what-the-u-s-can-learn-from-mobile-payments-in-africa/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
