<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>journal-recent &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<atom:link href="https://onereach.ai/tag/journal-recent/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<description>Intelligently Automate Your Company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 14:51:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/cropped-OR-ICON-GOLD-W-DOTS-Larger-Background-02-32x32.png</url>
	<title>journal-recent &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Mary Meeker&#8217;s Internet Trends Draft</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/mary-meekers-internet-trends/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 16:11:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[data room]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OmniChannel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-recent]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://onereach.ai/?p=6538</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The protection of proliferation of user data were two big themes repeatedly touched up on by Bond Capital’s Mary Meeker at Code Conference 2019 earlier in June.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meeker’s Internet Trends slide deck covered the gamut of trends dominating the industry, pulling back the layers of Internet use at home, abroad, and for personal and business use. </span></p>
<p><strong>Key findings included: </strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8211; For the first time in history, Americans are spending more time on their mobile devices than watching TV. A 2019 estimate reports that adults spent an average of 3 hours and 46 minutes on their phones per day compared to 3 hours and 36 minutes watching TV. By comparison, in 2009, TV reigned with 4 hours and 26 minutes per day while mobile use clocked in at just 20 minutes.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8211; An increasing number of people are using images to communicate: More than 50% of all tweets now include images. Platforms such as Instagram are amplifying this relatively new style of digital communication. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8211; About 25% of people consider themselves always online. Among the 18-to-29 year-old demographic, that number jumps to 39%, according to Pew Research cited in Meeker’s report.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8211; According to Nielsen, most television viewers are multi-platform multitaskers, with 88% of viewers saying they use a second digital device while watching TV, and 71% saying they look up content related to what they’re watching mid-show.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8211; Messaging platforms offering automatic or optional end-to-end encryption are rapidly rising in popularity, with secured services like Telegram and WhatsApp outpacing the growth of non-encrypted messaging services like Twitter and China’s WeChat. At the start of this year, 87% of web traffic was encrypted, compared to just 53% in 2016.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8211; When used properly, data and AI can improve customer satisfaction. In a survey of retail customers, 91% said they prefer brands that provide personalized offers and recommendations; 83% said they are willing to passively share data for personalized experiences; and 74% said they are willing to actively share data for personalized experiences.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8211; Seven of the ten most valuable companies in the world are now tech firms, led by #1 Microsoft, #2 Amazon, #3 Apple, #4 Alphabet, #6 Facebook, #7 Alibaba, and  #8 Tencent.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8211; Americans spent 6.3 hours per day using digital media in 2018, a rise of 6.8% from 2017 and nearly double the time spent (3.2 hours) in 2010.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8211; Cloud deployment represented 22% of all American workflows, double the amount from 2010.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8211; 59% of everyday transactions in 2018 were done digitally, with 41% done in stores.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8211; In 2018, 51% of humanity had Internet access, up from 24% in 2009.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8211; Cyber-security continued to improve, with the average attack-to-detection dwell time down to 78 days in 2018 from 416 days in 2011.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A look at the full presentation can be </span><a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/2019/6/11/18651010/mary-meeker-internet-trends-report-slides-2019" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">found here.</span></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>These Jobs are Most Likely to Be Taken Over by Bots</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/jobs-taken-by-bots/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 16:05:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Learning about AI and Bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-recent]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://onereach.ai/?p=6593</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Jobs that are highly repeatable and performed in predictable environments, such as fast-food restaurants or basic data processing tasks, are the most likely to be replaced in the near future by robots, according to a report released by hedge fund Bridgewater Associates.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These tasks require a minimum of interpersonal communication and would see more efficient robots and software solutions replacing humans who are more prone to error and slower.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The report used data from the US Department of Labor, focusing on how much time workers in various industries spend doing an assortment of tasks. The industries with the least-likely chance of being replaced with automated workers in the near future are healthcare and education.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="https://www.weforum.org/agenda/2019/04/these-are-the-industries-most-likely-to-be-taken-over-by-robots/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Read More</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Webinar Recording &#124; MuleSoft + OneReach.ai</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/conversational_ai_webinar_mulesoft/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 20:58:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Examples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Learning about AI and Bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-recent]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://onereach.ai/?p=6440</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Conversational AI: Go Beyond Chatbots with Intelligent Customer and Employee Experiences</strong></p>
<p>In this webinar we attempt to go around the chatbot hype. With conversational AI, your customers and employees get the answers they need fast. It’s more than simple “if-then” logic; it incorporates natural language to make human-to-machine conversations more like human-to-human ones. The result? Increased customer engagement, continued trust and reliability in your business, and the ability to free up your best thinkers and doers to become more productive than ever before.</p>
<p><strong>Watch webinar recording to learn how to:</strong><br />
&#8211; Automatically parse data, intent, and tasks from customer interactions using the power of Anypoint Platform combined with no-code/low-code conversational AI solutions from <a href="https://onereach.ai">OneReach.ai</a><br />
&#8211; Build task-specific, channel-agnostic experiences by integrating data from systems and channels like Slack, SMS, Voice, WhatsApp, and Facebook Messenger.<br />
&#8211; Retool your team for operational efficiency by automating the known, handing off the unknown, and more.</p>
<p><strong>Presented by:</strong><br />
Kevin Fredrick, Managing Partner, <a href="https://onereach.ai/">OneReach.ai</a><br />
Gagan Kanwar, Director of Business Development, <a href="https://www.mulesoft.com/">MuleSoft</a><br />
Vishnu Samavedula, Senior Solution Engineer, <a href="https://www.mulesoft.com/">MuleSoft</a></p>
<p><strong><a href="https://www.mulesoft.com/webinars/api/conversational-ai-assistant" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Register now</a> to watch the webinar!</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Harvard Business Review: Building the AI Powered Organization</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/building_ai_powered_organization/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 17:35:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Examples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Learning about AI and Bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-recent]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://onereach.ai/?p=6393</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Artificial intelligence is reshaping business—though not at the blistering pace many assume. True, AI is now guiding decisions on everything from crop harvests to bank loans, and once pie-in-the-sky prospects such as totally automated customer service are on the horizon. The technologies that enable AI, like development platforms and vast processing power and data storage, are advancing rapidly and becoming increasingly affordable. The time seems ripe for companies to capitalize on AI. Indeed, we estimate that AI will add $13 trillion to the global economy over the next decade.</p>
<p>Yet, despite the promise of AI, many organizations’ efforts with it are falling short. We’ve surveyed thousands of executives about how their companies use and organize for AI and advanced analytics, and our <a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/business-functions/mckinsey-analytics/our-insights/breaking-away-the-secrets-to-scaling-analytics" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">data shows</a> that only 8% of firms engage in core practices that support widespread adoption. Most firms have run only <a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/featured-insights/artificial-intelligence/ai-adoption-advances-but-foundational-barriers-remain" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ad hoc pilots</a> or are applying AI in just a single business process.</p>
<p>Why the slow prog­ress? At the highest level, it’s a reflection of a failure to rewire the organization. In our surveys and our work with hundreds of clients, we’ve seen that AI initiatives face formidable cultural and organizational barriers. But we’ve also seen that leaders who at the outset take steps to break down those barriers can effectively capture AI’s opportunities.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="https://hbr.org/2019/07/building-the-ai-powered-organization?" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Read More</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Harvard Business Review: Does your Company Really Need a Chatbot?</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/does_your_company_need_chatbot-2/</link>
				<pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 17:24:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Examples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Learning about AI and Bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-recent]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://onereach.ai/?p=6380</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Chatbots — automated conversation systems — have become increasingly sophisticated. Should you design and deploy one that can interact with your customers? If you’re an executive making that decision right now, you may feel caught between A.I. hype on the one hand, and the fear that machines might not treat your customers right on the other.</p>
<p>Chatbots are a broad category that includes everything from Amazon Alexa smart speakers to automated text chat on a company’s customer service page. The most powerful chatbots — and the ones that can actually make an impact on customers’ experience and company bottom lines — are virtual agents. These are chatbots powered by an artificial intelligence that can understand and answer a wide variety of customer questions.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="https://hbr.org/2019/05/does-your-company-really-need-a-chatbot" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Read More</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>WE&#8217;RE GOING TO MARS</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/remars/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 18:32:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Examples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Learning about AI and Bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-recent]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://onereach.ai/?p=6356</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span id="ember2813" class="ember-view">Innovative minds from academia, start-ups, and Fortune 100 companies gather to learn, share, and further imagine how Machine learning, Automation, Robotics, and Space will shape the future. </span></p>
<p><span id="ember2813" class="ember-view">You’ll find us in the showcase, kitty corner to Nasa Rover, beside the Robotics exhibit. </span></p>
<p>We can&#8217;t wait to hear from this year&#8217;s <a href="https://remars.amazon.com/learn/featured_speakers">featured speakers</a>, including Jeff Bezos, founder and CEO of Amazon, Robert Downey Jr., actor and producer, and many other leaders in the industry.</p>
<p><a id="ember2817" class="feed-shared-text-view__hyperlink ember-view" href="https://marsconference.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://marsconference.com</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>6 Design Principles for AI in Digital Business</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/6_design_principles_for_ai/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 17:49:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Examples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Learning about AI and Bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-recent]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://onereach.ai/?p=6360</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Artificial intelligence (AI) can augment or automate decisions and tasks today performed by humans, making it indispensable for digital business transformation. With AI, organizations can reduce labor costs, generate new business models, and improve processes or customer service. However, most AI technologies remain immature.</p>
<p>“To overcome this hurdle, CIOs must ensure that applications intended to serve a strategic business purpose, such as increasing revenue or scaling services, are designed for strategic plans,” says <a href="https://www.gartner.com/analyst/20865" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Jorge Lopez</a>, Distinguished Vice President Analyst, Gartner.</p>
<h5>&#8220;AI generates insights that lead directly to business execution.&#8221;</h5>
<p>Lopez outlines six design principles that will help CIOs and organizations evaluate all proposed AI applications with strategic intent — that is, applications intended to help achieve business results, not just operational improvements. Applications do not have to follow all six principles; however, designs that show two or fewer principles should be reconsidered&#8230;&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="https://www.gartner.com/smarterwithgartner/6-design-principles-for-artificial-intelligence-in-digital-business/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Read More</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Forbes &#8211; The Future Of Recruiting In The Age of Automation And AI</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/forbes-future-of-recuriting-ai/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 18:12:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Examples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Learning about AI and Bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-recent]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://onereach.ai/?p=6347</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Despite working in the human resources for over eight years for some of the top organizations in Canada, I have been somewhat blind to the future of work being driven by automation and artificial intelligence (AI). That is, until I read the <a href="http://www3.weforum.org/docs/WEF_Future_of_Jobs_2018.pdf" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" data-ga-track="ExternalLink:http://www3.weforum.org/docs/WEF_Future_of_Jobs_2018.pdf">2018 Future of Jobs report</a> by World Economic Forum.</p>
<p>According to that report, 50% of companies expect that by 2022, their full-time workforce will be somewhat reduced by automation. It is alarming to note that nearly a quarter of these companies are undecided or unlikely to retrain their existing employees and two-thirds expect workers to retrain themselves. This expectation raises an important question of how employees could know which new jobs they should retrain for when these jobs have not yet been created.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/forbeshumanresourcescouncil/2019/01/04/the-future-of-recruiting-in-the-age-of-automation-and-artificial-intelligence/#29a9e4ef1830" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Read More</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Forbes &#8211; 7+ Amazing Examples Of Online Chatbots &#038; Virtual Digital Assistants In Practice</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/forbes-7-amazing-examples-of-online-chatbots-virtual-digital-assistants-in-practice/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 18:18:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Examples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Learning about AI and Bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-recent]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://onereach.ai/?p=6122</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two of the most influential tech innovations that rocketed into our daily lives in the last several years are virtual digital assistants and online chatbots. These <a href="https://www.bernardmarr.com/default.asp?contentID=963" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" data-ga-track="ExternalLink:https://www.bernardmarr.com/default.asp?contentID=963">AI-driven</a> tools are already impacting the way people live and how companies interact with their customers in just about every industry. It is expected that the market for digital assistants and chatbots will reach more than <u><a href="https://voicebot.ai/2018/02/01/virtual-digital-assistant-software-reach-7-7-billion-1-billion-users-2025/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" data-ga-track="ExternalLink:https://voicebot.ai/2018/02/01/virtual-digital-assistant-software-reach-7-7-billion-1-billion-users-2025/">$7.7 billion by 2025 with 1 billion active users</a></u>.</p>
<p><strong>This article goes on to explore the following:</strong></p>
<p>What are virtual digital assistants?</p>
<p>What are online chatbots?</p>
<p>Many uses of chatbots</p>
<p><strong>Read more <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/bernardmarr/2019/02/11/7-amazing-examples-of-online-chatbots-and-virtual-digital-assistants-in-practice/#1d3c929e533e" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Forrester: 10% of U.S. jobs will be lost to automation in 2019</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/forrester_jobs/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 17:56:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Learning about AI and Bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OmniChannel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Phone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-popular]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-recent]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://onereach.ai/?p=5249</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Raconteur explores how bots are changing the role of Chief Financial Officers (CFO) and their corresponding departments [...]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">VentureBeat’s recent article on Forrester’s latest report on artificial intelligence brings up some interesting points. There is often talk of the gloom and doom that AI will bring on, especially in terms of eliminating key jobs through automation. There is no doubt that AI is going to have a massive impact on the way businesses operate, but what does this new future look like?</span></p>
<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-4588 size-large" src="https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-1024x725.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="725" srcset="https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-1024x725.jpg 1024w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-300x212.jpg 300w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-768x543.jpg 768w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-150x106.jpg 150w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-600x425.jpg 600w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-900x637.jpg 900w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-20x13.jpg 20w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-340x240.jpg 340w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p><b>The rise of digital workers</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Firstly, companies and startups alike are going to see an increase in digital workers created by robotic process automation (RPA) and AI. An increasing number of businesses are looking to scale at faster levels than before, and are going to be searching for solutions that can automate and optimize tasks traditionally done by humans. </span></p>
<p><b>Automation is all about giving and taking</b></p>
<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-2433 size-large" src="https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-1024x463.png" alt="" width="1024" height="463" srcset="https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-1024x463.png 1024w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-768x348.png 768w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-300x136.png 300w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-1200x544.png 1200w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-20x9.png 20w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-150x68.png 150w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-600x272.png 600w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-900x407.png 900w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai.png 1202w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Automation tends to be associated with loss of jobs, and while this holds true in Forrester’s findings, that is not the whole story. 2019 will see roughly 10% of US jobs eliminated due to automation, but that same automation will also </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">create</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> about 3% of today’s jobs.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, this new increase in automation has bigger implications down the line. As companies begin to fully scale operations to keep up with the rest, it means the marketplace for AI solutions is going to be fiercely competitive. A Deloitte survey currently posits the annual global growth rate for AI-as-a-serve at 48.2%, with no signs of slowing down. This ripple effect then bleeds into other business areas, such as recruitment for AI talent, as businesses look for ways to retain their edge. Forrester’s survey posits that this search for talent will lead to “unprecedented job match success rates.”</span></p>
<p><b>Use cases you need to know about</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Forrester’s research points to four use cases wherein businesses see a real return on investment: </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Analytics that solve platform issues</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chatbots integrated with RPA bots</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Internet-of-things (IoT) events that trigger “digital workers”</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Text analytics that organize unstructured data into “clean files” for RPA software.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Spot some commonalities? These use cases all point towards the future of AI &#8212; intelligent automation. Rather than strip away necessary jobs, AI is being used to free up employee time from rote tasks, and increase overall job satisfaction. These solutions are able to bridge the gap between menial tasks and human expertise, rather than limit the personal touch. According to the report, ML’s [machine learning] strength is data. Knowledge engineering’s strength is human wisdom. Used together, enterprises can dramatically accelerate the development of AI applications.</span><b>”</b></p>
<p>Read the full article <a href="https://venturebeat.com/2018/11/06/forrester-10-of-u-s-jobs-will-be-lost-to-automation-in-2019/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
