<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>OmniChannel &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<atom:link href="https://onereach.ai/category/omnichannel/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<description>Intelligently Automate Your Company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 11:39:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/cropped-OR-ICON-GOLD-W-DOTS-Larger-Background-02-32x32.png</url>
	<title>OmniChannel &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Mary Meeker&#8217;s Internet Trends Draft</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/mary-meekers-internet-trends/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 16:11:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[data room]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OmniChannel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-recent]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://onereach.ai/?p=6538</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The protection of proliferation of user data were two big themes repeatedly touched up on by Bond Capital’s Mary Meeker at Code Conference 2019 earlier in June.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meeker’s Internet Trends slide deck covered the gamut of trends dominating the industry, pulling back the layers of Internet use at home, abroad, and for personal and business use. </span></p>
<p><strong>Key findings included: </strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8211; For the first time in history, Americans are spending more time on their mobile devices than watching TV. A 2019 estimate reports that adults spent an average of 3 hours and 46 minutes on their phones per day compared to 3 hours and 36 minutes watching TV. By comparison, in 2009, TV reigned with 4 hours and 26 minutes per day while mobile use clocked in at just 20 minutes.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8211; An increasing number of people are using images to communicate: More than 50% of all tweets now include images. Platforms such as Instagram are amplifying this relatively new style of digital communication. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8211; About 25% of people consider themselves always online. Among the 18-to-29 year-old demographic, that number jumps to 39%, according to Pew Research cited in Meeker’s report.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8211; According to Nielsen, most television viewers are multi-platform multitaskers, with 88% of viewers saying they use a second digital device while watching TV, and 71% saying they look up content related to what they’re watching mid-show.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8211; Messaging platforms offering automatic or optional end-to-end encryption are rapidly rising in popularity, with secured services like Telegram and WhatsApp outpacing the growth of non-encrypted messaging services like Twitter and China’s WeChat. At the start of this year, 87% of web traffic was encrypted, compared to just 53% in 2016.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8211; When used properly, data and AI can improve customer satisfaction. In a survey of retail customers, 91% said they prefer brands that provide personalized offers and recommendations; 83% said they are willing to passively share data for personalized experiences; and 74% said they are willing to actively share data for personalized experiences.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8211; Seven of the ten most valuable companies in the world are now tech firms, led by #1 Microsoft, #2 Amazon, #3 Apple, #4 Alphabet, #6 Facebook, #7 Alibaba, and  #8 Tencent.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8211; Americans spent 6.3 hours per day using digital media in 2018, a rise of 6.8% from 2017 and nearly double the time spent (3.2 hours) in 2010.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8211; Cloud deployment represented 22% of all American workflows, double the amount from 2010.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8211; 59% of everyday transactions in 2018 were done digitally, with 41% done in stores.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8211; In 2018, 51% of humanity had Internet access, up from 24% in 2009.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> &#8211; Cyber-security continued to improve, with the average attack-to-detection dwell time down to 78 days in 2018 from 416 days in 2011.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A look at the full presentation can be </span><a href="https://www.vox.com/recode/2019/6/11/18651010/mary-meeker-internet-trends-report-slides-2019" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">found here.</span></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Forrester: 10% of U.S. jobs will be lost to automation in 2019</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/forrester_jobs/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 17:56:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Learning about AI and Bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OmniChannel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Phone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-popular]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-recent]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://onereach.ai/?p=5249</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Raconteur explores how bots are changing the role of Chief Financial Officers (CFO) and their corresponding departments [...]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">VentureBeat’s recent article on Forrester’s latest report on artificial intelligence brings up some interesting points. There is often talk of the gloom and doom that AI will bring on, especially in terms of eliminating key jobs through automation. There is no doubt that AI is going to have a massive impact on the way businesses operate, but what does this new future look like?</span></p>
<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-4588 size-large" src="https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-1024x725.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="725" srcset="https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-1024x725.jpg 1024w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-300x212.jpg 300w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-768x543.jpg 768w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-150x106.jpg 150w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-600x425.jpg 600w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-900x637.jpg 900w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-20x13.jpg 20w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-340x240.jpg 340w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p><b>The rise of digital workers</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Firstly, companies and startups alike are going to see an increase in digital workers created by robotic process automation (RPA) and AI. An increasing number of businesses are looking to scale at faster levels than before, and are going to be searching for solutions that can automate and optimize tasks traditionally done by humans. </span></p>
<p><b>Automation is all about giving and taking</b></p>
<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-2433 size-large" src="https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-1024x463.png" alt="" width="1024" height="463" srcset="https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-1024x463.png 1024w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-768x348.png 768w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-300x136.png 300w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-1200x544.png 1200w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-20x9.png 20w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-150x68.png 150w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-600x272.png 600w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-900x407.png 900w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai.png 1202w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Automation tends to be associated with loss of jobs, and while this holds true in Forrester’s findings, that is not the whole story. 2019 will see roughly 10% of US jobs eliminated due to automation, but that same automation will also </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">create</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> about 3% of today’s jobs.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, this new increase in automation has bigger implications down the line. As companies begin to fully scale operations to keep up with the rest, it means the marketplace for AI solutions is going to be fiercely competitive. A Deloitte survey currently posits the annual global growth rate for AI-as-a-serve at 48.2%, with no signs of slowing down. This ripple effect then bleeds into other business areas, such as recruitment for AI talent, as businesses look for ways to retain their edge. Forrester’s survey posits that this search for talent will lead to “unprecedented job match success rates.”</span></p>
<p><b>Use cases you need to know about</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Forrester’s research points to four use cases wherein businesses see a real return on investment: </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Analytics that solve platform issues</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chatbots integrated with RPA bots</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Internet-of-things (IoT) events that trigger “digital workers”</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Text analytics that organize unstructured data into “clean files” for RPA software.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Spot some commonalities? These use cases all point towards the future of AI &#8212; intelligent automation. Rather than strip away necessary jobs, AI is being used to free up employee time from rote tasks, and increase overall job satisfaction. These solutions are able to bridge the gap between menial tasks and human expertise, rather than limit the personal touch. According to the report, ML’s [machine learning] strength is data. Knowledge engineering’s strength is human wisdom. Used together, enterprises can dramatically accelerate the development of AI applications.</span><b>”</b></p>
<p>Read the full article <a href="https://venturebeat.com/2018/11/06/forrester-10-of-u-s-jobs-will-be-lost-to-automation-in-2019/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>People Want to Text Your Business</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/64perc-want-to-text/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 01:05:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Robb]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OmniChannel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://onereach.ai/?p=1508</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Wow, 64% of texters prefer it over </strong>phone<strong> for customer support. This graphic shows many more stats on the effects of a business using text messaging to interact with customers.</strong></p>
<p><img class="wp-image-1509 size-full aligncenter" src="https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/People_Want_to_Text_Your_Business.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="3200" srcset="https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/People_Want_to_Text_Your_Business.jpg 800w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/People_Want_to_Text_Your_Business-768x3072.jpg 768w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/People_Want_to_Text_Your_Business-300x1200.jpg 300w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/People_Want_to_Text_Your_Business-150x600.jpg 150w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/People_Want_to_Text_Your_Business-600x2400.jpg 600w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/People_Want_to_Text_Your_Business-20x80.jpg 20w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/People_Want_to_Text_Your_Business-75x300.jpg 75w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/People_Want_to_Text_Your_Business-256x1024.jpg 256w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></p>
<div class="grammarly-disable-indicator"></div>
<div class="grammarly-disable-indicator"></div>
<div class="grammarly-disable-indicator"></div>
<div class="grammarly-disable-indicator"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Software 2.0 &#8211; Reinterpreting Software</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/software-2-0-reinterpreting-software/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:57:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Robb]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OmniChannel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Phone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SMS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Strategy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-popular]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-recent]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://onereach.ai/?p=4829</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><b><i>“If you think of neural networks as a software stack and not just a pretty good classifier, it becomes quickly apparent that they have a huge number of advantages and a lot of potential for transforming software in general.”</i></b></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Reinterpreting the way you understand neural networks will completely change the way you think of software. And, according to Andrej Karpathy, the Director of AI at Tesla, it’s for the best. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Coined “Software 2.0”, which is written by neural network weights rather than humans, these weights will not replace Software 1.0 (much to the relief of today’s coders). Instead, Software 2.0 will help to lighten the load, taking on tedious tasks involved in creating the software behind visual and speech recognition, speech synthesis, machine translation, robotics, and games. Karpathy’s argument for the numerous benefits of porting complex programs into Software 2.0, despite its recognized limitations, should be enough to convince any coder to accept this new age transition.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Read more <span style="color: #ff0000;"><a style="color: #ff0000;" href="https://medium.com/@karpathy/software-2-0-a64152b37c35" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a></span>.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amplifying Management With AI Implementation &#8211; PWC</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/amplifying-management-with-ai-implementation-pwc/</link>
				<pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 14:41:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Robb]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OmniChannel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Strategy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-popular]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-recent]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://onereach.ai/?p=4823</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>72% of business execs believe AI will be the business advantage of the future.</strong></p>
<p>Technology is great at interrupting the everyday norm, especially when it comes to business. But perhaps no other sector of business is in greater need of reinvention than management, which is tasked with the bulk of a company’s work.</p>
<p>In order to keep up with the demand, management teams are finding creative ways to implement AI, optimizing processes and making better use of their limited time. And, according to a Digital IQ survey done recently, it’s not just some management teams strategizing with AI, it’s more than half.</p>
<p>54% of business executives making “substantial investments” in AI today, and that number is only predicted to continue its rapid growth trend.</p>
<p>Among the AI innovations these execs are most excited to take advantage of are:</p>
<p>The ability to have full-time virtual personal assistants (31%)<br />
Automating data analysis (29%)<br />
Automating email communication and utilizing chatbots (28%)</p>
<p>By freeing up their time by allowing AI to take care of the most repetitive tasks, management executives can focus more on big ideas, helping their companies grow more rapidly and efficiently.</p>
<p>Read the full article <span style="color: #ff0000;"><a style="color: #ff0000;" href="http://pwcartificialintelligence.com/#amplifying-management" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a></span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>10 Questions Every Org. Must Consider If In The Race</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/10-questions-every-organization-should-consider-when-competing-in-the-race-to-ai-adoption/</link>
				<pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 12:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Robb]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OmniChannel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SMS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Strategy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-popular]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://onereach.ai/?p=4678</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[In order to understand the importance of chatbots and voice bots in today’s business world, you first have to note the context [...]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In order to understand the importance of chatbots and voice bots in today’s business world, you first have to note the context in which they are being created. Despite the illusion of complexity, both types of bots are just software operating on an interface. And that interface also isn’t anything new; it’s actually the first interfaced used by humans: language. Built in to our cognitive development as humans, language is very much a part of who we are. Bots, then, aren’t creating something new. Instead, they’re simply finding a new way to do what we as humans have done for millenniums.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At the heart of the chatbot and voice bot revolution is the desire (and capacity) for using language to communicate with computers. The ability to do this means that we can actually train computers to not just understand, but also create, language, giving them the ability to tap into the interface we know so well.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In order for future bot experiences to be successful, they must be well-versed in the human language.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">How do they acquire these skills?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Through the training we give to them.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While it would be plausible for the opposite to take place (us training ourselves to talk to computers, aka coding), it’s a much better user experience for computers to learn to speak to us via our language.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This, then, brings us to the 10 business, design and technology questions that everyone should explore before setting out to build bots or create other AI solutions. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You’re already past questions like “how do bots and AI work?”, “what can they do for my organization?” and “should my organization make a bot?”. You already know that stuff, and likely the last thing you need is more marketing and sales pitches peddling bots and AI as the magic answer. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Whether you’re looking to make your existing stuff more awesome or you&#8217;re just getting started on your first AI and bot-stuffs, we think that you’ll be glad for the questions and answers our customers came across through many years of bot-building and AI problem solving.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/10-Questions-To-Consider-About-Your-AI-1.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-4685 size-full" src="https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/10-Questions-To-Consider-About-Your-AI-1.jpg" alt="" width="2081" height="1166" srcset="https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/10-Questions-To-Consider-About-Your-AI-1.jpg 2081w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/10-Questions-To-Consider-About-Your-AI-1-300x168.jpg 300w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/10-Questions-To-Consider-About-Your-AI-1-768x430.jpg 768w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/10-Questions-To-Consider-About-Your-AI-1-1024x574.jpg 1024w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/10-Questions-To-Consider-About-Your-AI-1-20x11.jpg 20w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/10-Questions-To-Consider-About-Your-AI-1-150x84.jpg 150w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/10-Questions-To-Consider-About-Your-AI-1-600x336.jpg 600w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/10-Questions-To-Consider-About-Your-AI-1-900x504.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 2081px) 100vw, 2081px" /></a></span></p>
<p><strong>Here are 10 questions that everyone should explore before/during building bots and AI solutions.</strong></p>
<ol>
<li><b>How can I future-proof my bot’s design, development and management? <i><span style="font-weight: 200;">Now this may seem like an advanced question, and it is, but in order to save yourself and your organization lots of painful time and money, we’re going to get you thinking about it early. There’s no better way to get thinking about it than to get some important questions stuck in the back of your head &#8211; try your best to keep running through them as you’re working through building great bot experiences. </span></i></b>
<ul>
<li><b>How c</b><b>an I avoid betting early on AI platforms without missing early payouts or stifling progress?</b> <i><span style="font-weight: 200;">Wow &#8211; that’s a doozy. There’s a lot of action in the AI space right now and a lot of money getting poured into it by all sorts of companies that want you to bet on them. If you’re like us, you might feel a bit like it’s too early to bet on investing in one particular platform like a Watson, Google’s API.ai, Luis, etc, etc. Pick one? Seems like a tough bet. So we subscribe to not picking one &#8211; instead AB test them all and see which one is best for each pieces of the puzzle, knowing that they’ll all continue to change.</span></i></li>
<li><b>What do I need to know in order to avoid super-gluing myself to platforms, providers and languages that might not be future-proof? <i><span style="font-weight: 200;">We’ve learned how important this question becomes to all of our customers by seeing how painful it can be to change platforms, providers and languages mid-flight &#8211; maybe your SMS provider gets too expensive or your understandably weary of building a solution on a proprietary language that’s only usable on one platform &#8211; like Twilio or Nexmo, etc. </span></i></b></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<ol>
<li style="list-style-type: none;">
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 200;"><span style="font-weight: 200;">How could reporting hold my bot back from it’s class, and how can I break the shackles early or avoid them altogether?</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li style="font-weight: 200;"><strong>Do I just want AI, or do I need AI?</strong></li>
<li style="font-weight: 200;"><strong>What’s the right channel(s) for my bot, and how can I build my bot to be as scalable as possible to other channels?</strong></li>
<li style="font-weight: 200;"><strong>Is my bot trained to do the right things and report on the right things, in the right ways for the right people? &#8211; What’s the scope and for who?</strong></li>
<li style="font-weight: 200;"><strong>What should my bot say if it doesn’t understand somebody’s intent and why does that question matter so much?</strong></li>
<li style="font-weight: 200;"><strong>What am I doing to make sure my bot’s integrations and 3rd party connectivity scalable and interchangeable?</strong></li>
<li style="font-weight: 200;"><strong>What’s appropriate for bots and what’s not, and where does my bot fall on the line? </strong></li>
<li style="font-weight: 200;"><strong>What do I need to consider when designing hand-offs from my bot to a human?</strong></li>
<li style="font-weight: 200;"><strong>How can I be sure I’m incorporating graceful failure into the experience my bot offers?</strong></li>
<li style="font-weight: 200;"><strong>What can I do to ensure my bot is developed in ways that don’t eternally hand-cuff me to it’s management, iterations and reporting?</strong></li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 Global CFO’s Say Goodbye &#8211; Bots &#038; Blockchain Take-Over</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/science_behind_hold-2/</link>
				<pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 00:15:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Robb]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OmniChannel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Phone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-recent]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://onereach.ai/?p=1959</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Raconteur explores how bots are changing the role of Chief Financial Officers (CFO) and their corresponding departments [...]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Technology is developing at speeds that were previously unheard of, and as a result artificial intelligence (AI) is changing the face of business.</strong> </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In <a href="https://www.raconteur.net/finance/goodbye-cfo-bots-and-blockchain-are-taking-over-soon">a recent Raconteur article by Jon Card</a>, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Goodbye CFO? Bots and blockchain are taking over soon </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Card explores how bots are changing the role of Chief Financial Officer (CFO) and their corresponding departments. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tim Briant (Airswift), Sankar Narayan (Xero), and Todd Ford (Coupa) shared what has changed within their companies, and what changes they expect to see in the future. From complete automation lacking a human touch, to changing the way companies analyze information, AI looks to have a significant impact on how companies will operate in the future. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tim Briant is not at all conservative in how he anticipates AI impacting business. Card wrote that Briant believes that AI is going to replace people completely. Briant cites his previous employment (as CFO at Adecco) as an example for how businesses will automate in the future. At Adecco many processes are already automated. At Airswift they are planning on implementing their own changes, by investing in bots. In a similar way to which humans learn, bots can do so as well. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>This ability to learn is what puts future accounting jobs at risk for humans.</strong> With the cost of technology dropping, it may one day become cheaper to have bots (who are able to learn from their mistakes) that are able to do the work (24 hours a day) than it would be to have humans doing the same work 8 hours a day.  According to Card, Briant believes that between AI technology and blockchain (a system that stores data in a public and accessible way – making it impossible for hackers to hack) there will not be a need for companies to retain a Chief Financial Officer in the future. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Card found an alternate point of view while interviewing Sankar Narayan of Xero. Narayan does not necessarily have the same doom and gloom type attitude that Briant has. Instead, Narayan seems exceptionally optimistic by what technology is able to offer, especially in terms of what it is doing for his current business.  </span></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-4557" src="https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/chris-liverani-552652-unsplash-1024x768.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="768" srcset="https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/chris-liverani-552652-unsplash-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/chris-liverani-552652-unsplash-300x225.jpg 300w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/chris-liverani-552652-unsplash-768x576.jpg 768w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/chris-liverani-552652-unsplash-150x112.jpg 150w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/chris-liverani-552652-unsplash-600x450.jpg 600w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/chris-liverani-552652-unsplash-900x675.jpg 900w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/chris-liverani-552652-unsplash-20x16.jpg 20w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Narayan has found that the role of CFO is taking on a more analytical position than it has in the past, but that is because of the massive amounts of data that they have at their fingertips</strong>. Boasting that he essentially knows exactly how much growth his company has experienced over any given time, Narayan seems to embrace what technology offers his company. However, Narayan wasn’t always this easy going in terms of AI. He’s been a CFO for over 17 years, which means he has had to see his position grown and change in order to stay relevant. Narayan believes that using artificial intelligence in business will be about more than efficiency in the future, and will instead help determine what decisions will make the company more profitable. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Todd Ford, of Coupa, is another CFO doomsayer. According to Card, Ford recognizes that with the advances in AI, the role of CFO may become obsolete.</strong> Though not necessarily as unforgiving as Briant, Ford recognizes that things have already changed significantly in the field. Humans are now competing with bots. Ford’s solution is to become more than just an accountant, he is also skilled in sales and marketing. This enables him to combine his two knowledge bases, and makes him more valuable. Card states that Mr. Ford sees the CFO position as one that consists of both chief accounting officer, as well as chief operations officer. It is Ford’s assumption that the CFO position will disappear in favor of a chief accounting officer and a chief operations officer, as those two skillsets don’t always coincide. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These three men are at the top of their field, and area already starting to see changes in terms of how AI has changed their business. With this constantly evolving landscape, it offers a plethora of opportunity, especially to businesses. However, accountants in the field will need to find a way to ensure that they stay relevant despite changes in the future. For some, this raises more questions than it does provide answers. Even so, bots offer many benefits that human counterparts cannot: longer work hours, reduced risk of human error, and the ability to provide analysis almost instantaneously. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These reasons alone make AI development worth a risk. </span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekly Review: 07/18</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/weekly-review-07-18/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/weekly-review-07-18/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Satisfaction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Infographic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OmniChannel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/weekly-review-07-18/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Happy Friday! Here’s our picks for the best customer service, customer experience, bot and mobile articles of the week, in no particular order.</p>
<h2><span id="more-7441"></span></h2>
<h2><span style="font-size: x-large;"><a href="http://www.mycustomer.com/service/channels/four-ways-to-leverage-omnichannel-to-drive-customer-loyalty">Four Way to Leverage Omnichannel to Drive Customer Loyalty</a> &#8211;<a href="http://@Taylor_Reach"> by Colin Taylor </a></span></h2>
<p>Everyone knows that the experience the customer has when interacting with a company, impacts their opinions, views and perceptions of the brand. With omnichannel, you can distinguish customers based on their segment across all channels including: voice calls, chat, emails, social and IVR. Find out why omnichannel plans support the overall corporate priorities with customer experience being the most important.</p>
<h2><span style="font-size: x-large;"><a href="http://venturebeat.com/2016/07/18/why-pokemon-go-could-be-a-groundbreaking-model-for-chatbots/">Why Pokemon Go Could Be A Groundbreaking Model For Bots-</a> <a href="http://@robotsNpencils">by Ryley Moskal </a></span></h2>
<p><span style="font-size: medium;">This has been the year of bots and most definitely the month for Pokemon! This article</span> talks about a real opportunity that exists to combine augmented reality (AR) and bots to alter businesses and heighten experiences in incomparable ways.</p>
<h2><a href="http://www.business2community.com/marketing/6-reasons-sms-marketing-powerful-investment-01597222#zyDA3T38QU0URJH0.97">6 Reasons SMS Marketing is Such a Powerful Investment</a>&#8211;<a href="http://@B2Community">by Siphon Chhay </a></h2>
<p>SMS is such a powerful tool for many reasons, one of those is this: 80% of people are now using text messaging for business in some form or fashion. SMS marketing allows for your audience to tap the screen to connect with you. Read on to find out the 6 reasons SMS marketing should be your next business investment.</p>
<h2><span style="color: #000000;"><a href="http://www.mycustomer.com/experience/engagement/infographic-how-to-better-engage-with-customers">How to Better Engage with Customers (Infographic)</a>&#8211; <a href="http://@neilcdavey">by Neil Davey </a></span></h2>
<p>Today customer service is so important that it actually could cost you more to lose a customer. Each stage in the customer journey so important because it is an opportunity to use all the right channels to engage them and build customer loyalty.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>To learn more about providing a great customer experience across channels, <a href="https://onereach.com/resources/omnichannel-seamless-experience">download our whitepaper here</a>.</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/weekly-review-07-18/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekly Review: 06/19</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/weekly-review-06-19/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/weekly-review-06-19/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Communication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Satisfaction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OmniChannel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Self-Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best way to improve customer service]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/weekly-review-06-19/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Happy Friday! Here’s our picks for the best customer service, customer experience, bot and mobile articles of the week, in no particular order.</p>
<h2><span id="more-7438"></span></h2>
<h2><span style="font-size: x-large;"><a href="http://customerthink.com/customer-centricity-is-more-than-promotional-hype/">Customer-Centricity is more than Promotional Hype</a> &#8211; by Mitchell Goozé</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-size: medium;">How do companies drive emotional engagement and guarantee they are fully committed to the needs of the customer? According to this article, centricity is key. Providing better customer service will ultimately end up in more profit, which is almost always the end goal for companies. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-size: x-large;"><a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/ibm/2016/06/20/how-to-architect-a-cognitive-future-for-business/#305197e0b173">How to Architect a Cognitive Future for Business </a> &#8211; by <a href="http://@TomRosamilia">Tom Rosamilia</a></span></h2>
<p>Many businesses are looking at the wide-spread possibilities of artificial intelligence to redefine their industries, businesses and customers. Business leaders are embracing artificial intelligence because consumers are using cognitive applications through phones and in their cars, creating better customer engagement.</p>
<h2><span style="font-size: x-large;"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/06/21/the-hidden-risks-of-the-bot-explosion/">The Hidden Risks of the Bot Explosion</a>&#8211; by <a href="http://@JenniferLSnell">Jennifer Snell</a> </span></h2>
<p>Whenever something new is introduced people are naturally skeptical about jumping into it. Building trust between humans and machines is very important and, like any relationship, takes time. People will only trust their bots if they trust the makers of their bots. At OneReach we want to make sure customers trust that we’re acting responsibly behind the curtain, and that we value the significance of their customer experience.</p>
<h2><span style="font-size: x-large;"><a href="http://customerthink.com/you-machines-and-the-future-of-customer-service/">You, Machines, and the Future of Customer Service</a>&#8211; by <a href="http://@jtwatkin">Jeremy Watkin </a></span></h2>
<p>The newest technologies have an amazing capacity to make customer service more effective. Knowing that 40% of customers prefer to handle issues on their own, technology can reduce the effort put forth in order to get their issues resolved.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>To learn more about providing a great customer experience across channels, <a href="https://onereach.com/resources/omnichannel-seamless-experience">download our whitepaper here</a>.</strong></p>
<h2></h2>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/weekly-review-06-19/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekly Review: 4/1 Edition</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/weekly-review-4-1-edition/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/weekly-review-4-1-edition/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[OmniChannel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/weekly-review-4-1-edition/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Happy Friday! Here’s our picks for the best customer service, customer experience and mobile articles of the week, in no particular order.</p>
<h2><span id="more-7412"></span><strong><a href="mailto:http://www.business2community.com/customer-experience/ode-canned-responses-channel-resolution-01495023%239T4BU35Q4cSJykAh.97">Ode to Canned Responses and Out-of-Channel Resolution</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/tamarush">Tamar Frumkin</a></strong></h2>
<p>Being bounced from channel to channel without any resolution makes for a bad customer experience. What makes it worse is having to start your conversation all over again. Perhaps that’s why over 85% of customers today demand an omnichannel experience from businesses. Unfortunately, some companies aren’t delivering on that expectation. In her article for Business 2 Community, marketing expert Tamar Frumkin explains her understandable frustration with one fitness clothing company’s customer experience, sending her from channel to channel without ever getting a decent response. Here’s hoping that that company learns to resolve issues within the channel they’re contacted on, or at least track the interactions across channels so customers don’t have to start over.</p>
<h2><strong><a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/forbesinsights/2016/03/29/l-l-bean-amazon-and-nordstrom-are-customer-service-champions-according-to-consumers/#2aba19b7bc26">L.L.Bean, Amazon And Nordstrom Are Customer Service Champions</a> by <a href="http://twitter.com/pjgoodfellow">Pam Goodfellow</a></strong></h2>
<p>There are some companies that you just associate with the phrase “good customer service”: Amazon, Nordstrom, L.L. Bean, etc. They’re willing to go above and beyond for their customers, whether they’re offering free shipping, exclusive member perks, or just a great ambiance. In addition, as consumer analyst Pam Goodfellow points out in her list of top 10 brands, business don’t necessarily need to have a physical storefront to provide a great experience for customers.</p>
<h2><strong><a href="http://www.brandembassy.com/blog/how-to-build-or-break-the-customer-experience-with-relationship-routing">How to Build or Break the Customer Experience with Relationship Routing</a> by <a href="http://www.brandembassy.com/blog/how-to-build-or-break-the-customer-experience-with-relationship-routing">Carly Burdova</a></strong></h2>
<p>In the digital world, it can be a little trickier to provide customers with a great, personalized experience. There’s no one there to greet you at the door or make friendly conversation as they scan your items. There’s also no one there that remembers the last time you came in and what you purchased. That’s where omnichannel service comes in. As Brand Embassy’s Carly Burdova points out in her excellent blog post, by continuing a conversation you’ve already started with a customer (ie their purchase history or Twitter interactions), you can build a relationship with them. Maybe it’s not so tricky after all.</p>
<h2><strong><a href="http://www.mycustomer.com/service/contact-centres/how-to-ensure-your-omnichannel-strategy-doesnt-become-an-omnishambles">How to ensure your omnichannel strategy doesn&#8217;t become an omnishambles</a> by Nicola Millard</strong></h2>
<p>When customers contact you, they don’t think about the fact that different channels are often managed by different departments. To them, your business is one unified entity—whatever channel they contact you on, they should be able to get the help they need. But as Nicola Millard points out in her MyCustomer post, businesses often think in terms of silos and don’t realize the impact this has on the customer experience. To get around this, she recommends making sure channels are integrated, all while letting customers choose what information they let companies have access to.</p>
<p><strong>To learn more about providing customers with a seamless omnichannel experience, <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/omnichannel-seamless-experience">download the whitepaper here</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/weekly-review-4-1-edition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
