<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Statistics &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<atom:link href="https://onereach.ai/category/statistics/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<description>Intelligently Automate Your Company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 11:39:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/cropped-OR-ICON-GOLD-W-DOTS-Larger-Background-02-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Statistics &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>45 Texting Statistics That Prove Businesses Need to Take SMS Seriously</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/45-texting-statistics-that-prove-businesses-need-to-take-sms-seriously/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/45-texting-statistics-that-prove-businesses-need-to-take-sms-seriously/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Statistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[texting statistics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/45-texting-statistics-that-prove-businesses-need-to-take-sms-seriously/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Texting has been around for over 20 years, but it’s only now just hitting its stride when it comes to business. Formerly just a way to send silly photos and emoticons (and to some extent, it still is), text messaging is now being viewed as a powerful way for businesses to connect with their customers.</p>
<p>For example, it’s widespread, affordable, real-time and flexible. It’s also brief, preferred, and can be used in any industry to satisfy customers.</p>
<p>What’s not to like?</p>
<p><span id="more-7265"></span>At OneReach, we&#8217;re not shy about singing text messaging’s praises—it’s a great way to interact with friends, family and customers alike. However, we know it’s important to back up our opinion with some cold hard facts, so that’s why we’ve compiled 45 texting statistics on why text messaging is such a powerful business tool. Check them out below, then let us know what you think of texting for business in the comments.</span></p>
<h1><strong>General Texting Statistics</strong></h1>
<ol>
<li>Texting is the most widely-used and frequently used app on a smartphone, with 97% of Americans using it at least once a day. (<a href="http://www.pewinternet.org/2015/04/01/us-smartphone-use-in-2015/">Pew Internet</a>)</li>
<li>People worldwide will send 8.3 trillion text messages in just this year alone. That’s almost 23 billion messages per day, or almost 16 million messages per minute. (<a href="http://www.portioresearch.com/en/blog/2013/17-incredible-facts-about-mobile-messaging-that-you-should-know.aspx">Portio Research</a>)</li>
<li>Over 6 billion text messages are sent in the U.S. each day. (<a href="http://blogs.forrester.com/michael_ogrady/12-06-19-sms_usage_remains_strong_in_the_us_6_billion_sms_messages_are_sent_each_day">Forrester</a>)</li>
<li>Over 80% of American adults text, making it the most common cell phone activity. (<a href="http://www.pewinternet.org/2013/09/19/cell-phone-activities-2013/">Pew Internet</a>)</li>
<li>Text messages have a 98% open rate, while email has only a 20% open rate. (<a href="http://mobilemarketingwatch.com/sms-marketing-wallops-email-with-98-open-rate-and-only-1-spam-43866/">Mobile Marketing Watch</a>)</li>
<li>Text messaging has a 45% response rate, while email only has a 6% response rate. (<a href="https://www.marketingtechblog.com/text-messaging/">Velocify</a>)</li>
<li>Texting takes up 14.1% of cell phone users’ time. (<a href="http://www.marketingcharts.com/wp/online/10-of-mobile-time-devoted-to-social-networking-20-to-messaging-26022/">Nielsen</a>)</li>
<li>90% of all text messages are read in under 3 minutes. (<a href="http://connectmogul.com/2013/03/texting-statistics/">Connect Mogul</a>)</li>
<li>Text messages are read on average in under five seconds. (<a href="http://www.slicktext.com/blog/2014/02/text-message-marketing-the-new-kid-on-the-block-infographic/">SlickText</a>)</li>
<li>75% of phones worldwide (4.5 billion) are text-enabled (<a href="http://duocallcommunications.wordpress.com/2013/09/19/sms-marketing-statistics/">DuoCall Communications</a>)</li>
<li>96% of smartphone users text. (<a href="http://duocallcommunications.wordpress.com/2013/09/19/sms-marketing-statistics/">Acision</a>)</li>
<li>Americans sent 69,000 texts every second in 2012 (<a href="http://www.ctia.org/resource-library/facts-and-infographics/archive/americans-texts-2012-infographic">CTIA</a>)</li>
<li>The average adult spends a total of 23 hours a week texting (<a href="http://www.usatoday.com/experience/weekend/lifestyle/michael-wolff-how-media-usage-is-taking-over-our-lives/12487581/">USA Today</a>)</li>
<li>The average Millennial exchanges an average of 67 text messages per day (<a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/chart-of-the-day-number-of-texts-sent-2013-3">Business Insider</a>)</li>
<li>On average, Americans exchange twice as many texts as they do calls (<a href="http://www.mosio.com/mobileanswers/facts-and-figures-mobile-text-message-usage-in-the-u-s-its-massive/">Nielsen</a>)</li>
<li>Only 43% of smartphone owners use their phone to make calls, but over 70% of smartphone users text (<a href="http://connectmogul.com/2013/03/texting-statistics/">Connect Mogul</a>)</li>
<li>55% of heavy text message users (50+ texts per day) say they would prefer to receive a text over a phone call (<a href="http://www.pewinternet.org/2011/09/19/americans-and-text-messaging/">Pew Research Center</a>)</li>
<li>In 2011, 31% of Americans said they preferred text messages to phone calls (<a href="http://www.pewinternet.org/2011/09/19/americans-and-text-messaging/">Pew Research Center</a>)</li>
<li>It takes the average person 90 minutes to respond to email, but only 90 seconds to respond to a text message. (<a href="http://blog.hubspot.com/blog/tabid/6307/bid/24082/9-Amazing-Mobile-Marketing-Statistics-Every-Marketer-Should-Know.aspx">CTIA</a>)</li>
<li>American women text 14% more than men. (<a href="http://www.nielsen.com/us/en/insights/news/2013/10-things-to-know-about-todays-female-consumer.html">Nielsen</a>)</li>
</ol>
<h1><strong>Business Texting Statistics</strong></h1>
<ol start="21">
<li>79% of companies believe customers want SMS/text support. (<a href="http://www.icmi.com/Resources/Mobile/2014/04/Im-Excited-to-Enable-SMS-in-My-Contact-Center-But-Should-it-Integrate-with-Other-Channels">ICMI</a>)</li>
<li>38% of contact centers currently offer SMS, and 23% have plans to add it in the next 12 months. That means 61% of contact centers will offer SMS support in 2016. (<a href="http://www.dimensiondata.com/Global/Downloadable%20Documents/2015%20Global%20Contact%20Centre%20Benchmarking%20Summary%20Report.pdf">Dimension Data</a>)</li>
<li>80% of people are currently using texting for business. (<a href="http://www.eweek.com/small-business/businesses-texting-grows-more-widespread.html">eWeek</a>)</li>
<li>One in five consumers is just as likely to prefer a text message from a business to a phone call. (<a href="http://www.icmi.com/Resources/Mobile/2014/03/Texting-to-Surpass-Phone-Calls-for-Business-Communication">ICMI</a>)</li>
<li>The activities people with text capabilities would most prefer to do via text are: check order status (38%) schedule or change appointments (32%) and make or confirm reservations (31%). (Harris poll; link below)</li>
<li>Over half of customers said they would be likely to text with a customer support agent. Similarly, 52 percent would prefer texting customer support over their current preferred form of communication. (<a href="http://www.eweek.com/networking/consumers-like-using-text-messages-to-solve-customer-service-issues.html">eWeek</a>)</li>
<li>A 2012 study found that text was the highest rated contact method for customer satisfaction out of all other customer communication channels. Text earned 90 out of 100 points, while phone earned 77 out of 100 and Facebook earned 66. (<a href="http://www.cfigroup.com/downloads/CCSI_2012.pdf">CFI Group</a>)</li>
<li>Millenials prefer automated text messaging over IVR, including speech-based solutions (<a href="http://www.frost.com/c/10107/blog/blog-display.do?id=3415568&amp;bdata=aHR0cDovL3d3dy5mcm9zdC5jb20vYy8xMDEwNy9ibG9nL2luZGV4LmRvP3BhZ2VTaXplPTcmcGFnZT01QH5AQmxvZ0B%2BQDE0MDI2MTU0OTg0NTE%3D">Frost &amp; Sullivan</a>)</li>
<li>Over one-third of business professionals say they can’t go 10 minutes without responding to a text. (<a href="http://www.eweek.com/small-business/businesses-texting-grows-more-widespread.html">eWeek</a>)</li>
<li>SMS text chat converts a $6-$20 call to a chat that costs pennies per session. (<a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;source=web&amp;cd=1&amp;cad=rja&amp;uact=8&amp;ved=0CB4QFjAAahUKEwjy3qah_uzHAhXEOIgKHX8-BZk&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.oracle.com%2Fus%2Fcorporate%2Fanalystreports%2Fenterprise-application%2Fforrester-tei-atg-359304.pdf&amp;usg=AFQjCNGb1D5dHiwxoozprCghfsZPs2ibfA&amp;bvm=bv.102022582,d.cGU">Forrester</a> &amp; <a href="http://www.mosio.com/mobileanswers/the-competitive-advantages-of-mobile-text-messaging-stats-facts-and-figures/">ContactBabel</a>)</li>
<li>At least five types of social media channels are used in more than 50% of call centers, including SMS/texting (<a href="http://www.voip-info.org/wiki/view/Call+Center+Statistics">VoIP Info</a>)</li>
<li>Sales prospects who are sent text messages convert at a rate 40% higher than those who are not sent any text messages. (<a href="http://pages.velocify.com/rs/leads360/images/Text-Messaging-for-Better-Sales-Conversion.pdf?mkt_tok=3RkMMJWWfF9wsRonuKvBZKXonjHpfsX97uouXa%2Bg38431UFwdcjKPmjr1YIHTcZ0aPyQAgobGp5I5FENSLLYWKpst6cJWA%3D%3D">Velocify</a>)</li>
<li>Over 80% of people use text messaging for business, and 15% said that more than half their messages are for business purposes. (<a href="http://www.eweek.com/small-business/businesses-texting-grows-more-widespread.html">eWeek</a>)</li>
<li>Almost 25% of marketers are currently using text messaging. Over 65% of them report SMS as being “very effective.” (<a href="http://www.exacttarget.com/blog/we-surveyed-5000-marketers-heres-what-they-said-about-marketing-in-2015/">ExactTarget</a>)</li>
<li>70% of U.S. consumers appreciate getting texts or emails from healthcare providers. (<a href="http://loyalty360.org/resources/article/healthcare-providers-real-time-customer-engagement">Loyalty 360</a>)</li>
<li>75% of people would like to have offers sent to them via SMS. (<a href="http://digitalmarketingmagazine.co.uk/mobile-digital-marketing/7-key-statistics-for-sms-marketing/558">Digital Marketing Magazine</a>)</li>
<li>Over 80% of people would only like to receive a maximum of two marketing messages per month. (<a href="http://digitalmarketingmagazine.co.uk/mobile-digital-marketing/7-key-statistics-for-sms-marketing/558">Digital Marketing Magazine</a>)</li>
<li>44% of consumers with texting capabilities would prefer to press a button to initiate a text conversation immediately, rather than waiting on hold to speak with an agent. (Harris Poll; link below)</li>
<li>Texting in the sales process can lead to conversion gains of more than 100%. However, sending text messages before establishing contact with a prospect can adversely affect both contact and conversion rates. (<a href="http://pages.velocify.com/rs/leads360/images/Text-Messaging-for-Better-Sales-Conversion.pdf?mkt_tok=3RkMMJWWfF9wsRonuKvBZKXonjHpfsX97uouXa%2Bg38431UFwdcjKPmjr1YIHTcZ0aPyQAgobGp5I5FENSLLYWKpst6cJWA%3D%3D">Velocify</a>)</li>
<li>20% of financial services companies use mobile messaging to ensure business continuity and add to their multichannel capabilities. (<a href="http://loyalty360.org/resources/article/mobile-customer-engagement-for-financial-services-industry">Loyalty 360</a>)</li>
<li>77% of consumers with texting capabilities aged 18-34 are likely to have a positive perception of a company that offers text capability. (Harris Poll; link below)</li>
<li>44% of consumers would rather receive product details and other marketing messages through text over any other channel. (<a href="http://www.mosio.com/mobileanswers/the-competitive-advantages-of-mobile-text-messaging-stats-facts-and-figures/">Direct Marketing Association</a>)</li>
<li>72% of business professionals prefer texting to messaging apps. (<a href="http://www.eweek.com/small-business/businesses-texting-grows-more-widespread.html">eWeek</a>)</li>
<li>Nearly 70% of employees think their organization should use text messaging to communicate with employees, and 86% say it should not be reserved for just customer communication. (<a href="https://www.callfire.com/blog/2014/01/06/businesses-communicate-internally-with-sms">Vitiello Communications Group</a>)</li>
<li>64% of all consumers are likely to have a positive perception of a company that offers texting as a service channel (Harris Poll; link below).</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>So, what did you think of the texting statistics? Do you think more companies should start offering text messaging? Is there another, better channel that we’re missing, or are you just not fond of text messaging altogether? </strong><strong>Let us know in the comments, and don’t forget to download our 2014 Harris Poll report detailing why <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/high-demand-for-text-message-2014-report">64% of customers want to text your business</a>.</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://s.daryo.uz/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/Businessman-Texting2.jpg">Photo credit</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/45-texting-statistics-that-prove-businesses-need-to-take-sms-seriously/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>25 Statistics on the Power of Positive Customer Service</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/25-statistics-on-the-power-of-positive-customer-service/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/25-statistics-on-the-power-of-positive-customer-service/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Customer Experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Satisfaction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Statistics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/25-statistics-on-the-power-of-positive-customer-service/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Customer service stories often surface in a negative light—a service wasn’t cancelled, no one responded to a problem, or a company didn’t deliver on its promise. In fact, <a href="http://www.desk.com/customer-service/excellent-customer-service">nearly one-third of consumers</a> think that businesses are paying less attention to providing great customer service.</p>
<p>And unfortunately, the customer is always right about this. While <a href="http://www.helpscout.net/75-customer-service-facts-quotes-statistics/">over 80% of companies</a> boast that they provide &#8220;superior&#8221; customer service, only 8% of customers actually agree with them.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s a company to do?</p>
<p><span id="more-7249"></span>Invest in and provide a good service experience, for the good of your customers (and your company).</p>
<p>At OneReach, we think great customer service isn&#8217;t just about the channels you use&#8211;it&#8217;s about making service on any channel effortless, intuitive and available any time. Companies that invest in great customer service, be it through their contact centers, help pages, or self-service initiatives, can increase customer satisfaction, customer loyalty, and even save money.</p>
<p>Check out these customer service statistics to see the power of a positive customer service experience (and what happens when companies aren’t providing it).</p>
<ol>
<li>By the year 2020 (coming up fast!), customer service will beat out price and product as the key brand differentiator. (<a href="http://www.walkerinfo.com/customers2020/">Walker Info</a>)</li>
<li>It&#8217;s 6-7 times more expensive to attract a new customer than to keep an existing one. (<a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/">White House Office of Consumer Affairs</a>)</li>
<li>A 10% increase in customer retention can result in 30% increase in company value. (<a href="http://www.bain.com/publications/business-insights/loyalty.aspx">Bain &amp; Co.</a>)</li>
<li>If customers have a “very good” or “excellent” service experience, 97% of them are “very” or “extremely” likely to tell friends and family about it. (<a href="https://www.surveymonkey.com/blog/2015/05/18/good-customer-service-tips-growing-loyal-customer-base">Survey Monkey</a>)</li>
<li>89% of customers will start doing business with a competitor after a negative service experience. (<a href="http://blog.vpi-corp.com/blog/performance-optimization-2/40-stats-shaping-the-future-of-contact-centers">VPI Corp</a>)</li>
<li>82% of customers stopped doing business with a company after a bad customer service experience. (<a href="http://www.slideshare.net/RightNow/2011-customer-experience-impact-report">RightNow</a>)</li>
<li>Over 65% of customers say that valuing their time is the most important thing a company can do to provide good online service. (<a href="http://blogs.forrester.com/kate_leggett/12-06-20-consumers_drive_channel_preference_to_achieve_effortless_customer_service">NICE</a>)</li>
<li>Three out of five customers would try a new brand or company in order to get better service. (<a href="http://about.americanexpress.com/news/docs/2011x/AXP_2011_csbar_market.pdf">American Express</a>)</li>
<li>Over 90% of customers who have an effortless service experience with companies will buy from that company again. (<a href="http://www.thewisemarketer.com/briefs/archive.asp?action=read&amp;bid=4489">CEB</a>)</li>
<li>Only a paltry 1% of customers feel that their expectations of good customer service are always met. (<a href="http://www.slideshare.net/RightNow/2011-customer-experience-impact-report">RightNow</a>)</li>
<li>90% of customer service decision makers believe that delivering good customer service is essential to their companies&#8217; success. (<a href="http://www.aspect.com/globalassets/aspect-ngcc-forrester-wp.pdf">Forrester</a>)</li>
<li>58% of customers are willing to spend more with companies that provide a great customer service experience. (<a href="http://about.americanexpress.com/news/docs/2012x/axp_2012gcsb_us.pdf">American Express</a>)</li>
<li>87% of customers share good service experiences with others. (<a href="https://www.zendesk.com/resources/the-impact-of-customer-service/">Zendesk</a>)</li>
<li>Nearly 50% of customers who had a negative service experience have told over 10 people about it. (<a href="https://hbr.org/2010/07/stop-trying-to-delight-your-customers">Harvard Business Review</a>)</li>
<li>73% of consumers say that a friendly customer service rep can make them fall in love with a brand. (<a href="http://www.slideshare.net/RightNow/2011-customer-experience-impact-report">RightNow</a>)</li>
<li>74% of customers find a poor customer service experience annoying. (<a href="http://synthetix.pr.co/35674-7-out-of-10-people-think-online-customer-service-will-dominate-over-traditional-call-centres-within-a-decade">Synthetix</a>)</li>
<li>85% of organizations support multichannel customer service interactions. (<a href="http://www2.deloitte.com/content/dam/Deloitte/us/Documents/process-and-operations/us-sdt-consulting-2013-global-contact-survey-051513.pdf">Deloitte</a>)</li>
<li>Over 60% of companies think mobile customer service is a competitive differentiator. (<a href="http://www.icmi.com/About-ICMI/Press-Room/2013-Mobile-Customer-Service-Strategy-Results-Released">ICMI</a>)</li>
<li>90% of customers expect to receive a consistent customer experience across channels. (<a href="http://synthetix.pr.co/35674-7-out-of-10-people-think-online-customer-service-will-dominate-over-traditional-call-centres-within-a-decade">Synthetix</a>)</li>
<li>74% of customers have spent more in response to good customer service. (<a href="http://about.americanexpress.com/news/docs/2014x/2014-Global-Customer-Service-Barometer-US.pdf">American Express</a>)</li>
<li>68% of customers say they&#8217;ve switched brands because of bad customer service. (<a href="http://www.accenture.com/sitecollectiondocuments/pdf/accenture_utilities_customeracquisitionretention.pdf">Accenture</a>)</li>
<li>U.S. companies lose approximately $41 billion annually due to bad customer service. (<a href="http://www.smartcustomerservice.com/Articles/News-Briefs/Research-U.S.-Businesses-Lose-$41-Billion-Annually-Due-to-Poor-Customer-Service-93869.aspx">SmartCustomerService</a>)</li>
<li>78% of consumers have bailed on a transaction because of bad customer service. (<a href="http://about.americanexpress.com/news/docs/2011x/AXP_2011_csbar_market.pdf">American Express</a>)</li>
<li>81% of customers are likely to repeat business with a company after a good service experience. (<a href="http://blog.kissmetrics.com/happy-campers/">Kissmetrics</a>)</li>
<li>A 5% increase in customer retention can increase profits by up to 125%. (<a href="http://www.bain.com/Images/BB_Prescription_cutting_costs.pdf">Bain &amp; Co.</a>)</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>What do you think companies can do to create a powerfully positive customer experience? Is there one obvious thing they&#8217;re missing, or are there some big changes they could make? Let us know in the comments, and don’t forget to download our ebook on the <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/omnichannel-seamless-experience">seamless customer experience</a>!</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://blog.five9.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/customer-service-smile.png">Photo credit</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/25-statistics-on-the-power-of-positive-customer-service/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>10 Omnichannel Statistics You Need to Know</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/10-omnichannel-statistics-you-need-to-know/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/10-omnichannel-statistics-you-need-to-know/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[OmniChannel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Statistics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/10-omnichannel-statistics-you-need-to-know/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever reached out to customer service on one channel, gotten frustrated because things are going nowhere, and switched to another channel? Then, are you increasingly exasperated when you find out you have to start your conversation over?</p>
<p>Yeah, so are we.</p>
<p>Luckily, this type of customer experience can be avoided by companies that take an omnichannel approach. Despite its association with <a href="http://www.business2community.com/marketing/15-stats-explain-omni-channel-just-buzzword-0896737">marketing and retail</a>, omnichannel can be applied to customer service as well. Omnichannel service means bringing various channels together in a more integrated and consistent way, drawing on past interactions and customer data to create a seamless service experience. In fact, <a href="http://loyalty360.org/resources/article/survey-businesses-that-use-omni-channel-strategies-have-far-better-customer">over 90% of customers</a> expect this kind of experience from companies.</p>
<p><span id="more-7243"></span>At OneReach, we think omnichannel is an essential part of customer service that not only boosts customer retention but creates a powerfully positive customer experience. By adding omnichannel (and integration to inform the customer experience), businesses can increase CSAT tremendously with easy and effortless service experiences.</p>
<p>Check out these omnichannel statistics to see the impact it can have on businesses (and what happens when companies aren&#8217;t using it).</p>
<ol>
<li>87% of customers think brands need to put more effort into providing a seamless experience. (<a href="http://d16cvnquvjw7pr.cloudfront.net/resources/whitepapers/Omnichannel-Customer-Service-Gap.pdf">Zendesk</a>)</li>
<li>98% of Americans switch between devices in the same day. (<a href="http://www.mobilepaymentstoday.com/blogs/omnichannel-banking-a-consumer-first-not-bank-first-experience/">Google Research</a>)</li>
<li>Companies with extremely strong omnichannel customer engagement retain on average 89% of their customers, compared to 33% for companies with weak omnichannel customer engagement. (<a href="https://www.internetretailer.com/2013/12/31/why-omnichannel-strategy-matters">Aberdeen Group</a>)</li>
<li>89% of customers get frustrated having to repeat their issues to multiple representatives. (<a href="http://www.accenture.com/SiteCollectionDocuments/PDF/Accenture-Global-Consumer-Pulse-Research-Study-2013-Key-Findings.pdf">Accenture</a>)</li>
<li>Over 35% of customers expect to be able to contact the same customer service representative on any channel. (<a href="http://d16cvnquvjw7pr.cloudfront.net/resources/whitepapers/Omnichannel-Customer-Service-Gap.pdf">Zendesk</a>)</li>
<li>77% of strong omnichannel companies store customer data across channels, compared to 48% for weak omnichannel companies. (<a href="https://www.internetretailer.com/2013/12/31/why-omnichannel-strategy-matters">Aberdeen Group</a>)</li>
<li>61% of customers have not been able to easily switch from one channel to another when interacting with customer service. (<a href="http://blogs.aspect.com/2014/01/29/infographic-omni-channel-service-doesnt-measure-up-customers-are-tired-of-playing-games/">Aspect</a>)</li>
<li>64% of customers expect to receive real-time assistance regardless of the customer service channel they use. (<a href="http://d16cvnquvjw7pr.cloudfront.net/resources/whitepapers/Omnichannel-Customer-Service-Gap.pdf">Zendesk</a>)</li>
<li>Companies with extremely strong omnichannel customer engagement see a 9.5% year-over-year increase in annual revenue, compared to 3.4% for weak omnichannel companies. Similarly, strong omnichannel companies see a 7.5% year-over-year decrease in cost per contact, compared to a 0.2% year-over-year decrease for weak companies. (<a href="https://www.internetretailer.com/2013/12/31/why-omnichannel-strategy-matters">Aberdeen Group</a>)</li>
<li>By 2020, the demand for an omnichannel customer experience will be amplified by the need for nearly perfect execution. (<a href="http://www.pwc.com/us/en/retail-consumer/publications/retailing-2020.jhtml">PricewaterhouseCoopers</a>)</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>What’s your take on omnichannel service? Does it get you the answers you need effortlessly, or do you end up frustrated? Let us know in the comments, and don’t forget to download our ebook on the <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/omnichannel-seamless-experience">seamless experience</a>!</strong></p>
<p>Photo credit: <a href="http://www.playbuzz.com/nickelodeonlatam10/qu-nicktoon-describe-tu-vida">Playbuzz</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/10-omnichannel-statistics-you-need-to-know/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>10 Striking Statistics on Self-Service Today</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/10-striking-statistics-on-self-service-today/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/10-striking-statistics-on-self-service-today/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Self-Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Statistics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/10-striking-statistics-on-self-service-today/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today&#8217;s self-service is becoming more and more prevalent, spreading across channels from  web to voice to text to social. It&#8217;s a powerful, flexible form of service that more customers are using and businesses are adopting. In fact, <a href="http://www.intelliresponse.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/IR-State-of-Online-SS-WP-PROOF.pdf">over 50% of businesses</a> today are using self-service, and 64% plan to invest in and extend it to other channels (<a href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/?p=1299">texting, anyone?</a>)</p>
<p><span id="more-7216"></span>At OneReach, we think self-service is a valuable tool that not only cuts costs but increases customer satisfaction. By adding self-service (and automation to speed up resolution time), businesses can receive a great ROI and empower customers with quick and easy service experiences.</p>
<p>Check out these insights on the growth of self-service today (and beyond)!</p>
<ol>
<li>Over 50% of customers think it&#8217;s important to solve product issues themselves rather than rely on customer service. (<a href="http://cdn.zendesk.com/resources/whitepapers/Omnichannel-Customer-Service-Gap.pdf">Zendesk</a>)</li>
<li>Self-service usage increased from 67% in 2012 to 76% in 2014. (<a href="https://www.forrester.com/North+American+Consumer+Technographics+Customer+LifeCycle+Survey+1+2014/-/E-SUS2568">Forrester</a>)</li>
<li>45% of companies offering web or mobile self-service have reported an increase in site traffic and a decrease in phone calls. (<a href="http://www.destinationcrm.com/Articles/ReadArticle.aspx?ArticleID=90678">Destination CRM</a>)</li>
<li>A chat with a live agent can cost $6-12 per interaction, while an automated interaction on the IVR (or ITR) can cost as little as 25 cents. (<a href="http://www.oracle.com/us/corporate/analystreports/enterprise-application/forrester-tei-atg-359304.pdf">Forrester</a>)</li>
<li>40% of customers prefer self-service to human contact. (<a href="http://www.slideshare.net/stevenvanbelleghem/the-self-serving-economy">Steven Van Belleghem</a>)</li>
<li>The IVR makes up 27% of all calls in the contact center, but only 7% of companies offer an IVR solution that delivers a better experience than live agents. (<a href="http://www.howto.gov/sites/default/files/the-drivers-of-customer-satisfaction-in-the-contact-center.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">JD Power &amp; Associates</a>)</li>
<li>By adding self-service, a typical utility could see $1-3 million in annual savings. (<a href="http://www.accenture.com/SiteCollectionDocuments/PDF/Accenture_Utilities_MultiChannelSelfService.pdf">Accenture</a>)</li>
<li>By this year, 50% of online customer self-service tasks will be performed by virtual agents. (<a href="http://www.gartner.com/newsroom/id/1929014">Gartner</a>)</li>
<li>70% of customers prefer to use a company&#8217;s website to get answers to their questions rather than use phone or email. (<a href="http://blogs.forrester.com/diane_clarkson/10-04-06-do_your_customers_want_telephone_you_service">Forrester</a>)</li>
<li>By 2020, the customer will manage 85% of the relationship with an enterprise without interacting with a human. (<a href="http://mktimages.gartner.com/pv_obj_cache/pv_obj_id_92DB197B681D1A1003F701CB30B626FF3B111B00/filename/brochure_crm_2011.pdf">Gartner</a>)</li>
</ol>
<p>What&#8217;s your take on self-service? Does it get you the answers you need, or do you end up frustrated? Let us know in the comments, and don&#8217;t forget to download our ebook on the use of <a href="http://onereachcontactcenter.com/high-demand-for-customer-service-via-text-message/">texting for customer (self)-service</a>!</p>
<p>Photo by <a href="http://pixabay.com/en/office-notes-notepad-entrepreneur-614273/">FirmBee</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/10-striking-statistics-on-self-service-today/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
