<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Best Practices &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<atom:link href="https://onereach.ai/category/best-practices/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<description>Intelligently Automate Your Company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 11:39:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/cropped-OR-ICON-GOLD-W-DOTS-Larger-Background-02-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Best Practices &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How to Write Automated Texts That Sound Human</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/how-to-write-automated-texts-that-sound-human/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/how-to-write-automated-texts-that-sound-human/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Best Practices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/how-to-write-automated-texts-that-sound-human/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This post is co-written with Leslie O&#8217;Flahavan of <a href="http://www.ewriteonline.com/">E-WRITE</a>.</em></p>
<p>If your customers have opted-in to receive texts from your company, they probably realize that some of your texts are going to be automated. They understand that sometimes texts from your company were sent by an automated system and that you don’t actually have a human employee, chained to a desk, hand-typing each appointment confirmation or loyalty program welcome message!</p>
<p>However, even if your texts to customers are automated, they shouldn’t sound mechanical. Here are ten tips to help you write automated texts that sound human and build rapport with your customers.</p>
<h2><span id="more-7430"></span><strong>1. Use familiar, conversational words. </strong></h2>
<p>Text is closer to speech than any other written form of customer service, so choose words that you’d use if you were talking to a customer. This text from ZocDoc uses “info” and “Just remind,” which makes this text sound like it’s coming from a friendly company. (It also fits nicely within the 160 character limit).</p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="300">&nbsp;</p>
<p>Your info has been sent to your healthcare provider. Just remind the office that you completed your forms online thru ZocDoc! Problems? Reply “s” for support.</p>
<p><strong> </strong></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2><strong>2. Be concise</strong>.</h2>
<p>Wordy texts read like form letters, and no customer thinks, “Oh, you wrote this form letter just for me?” Cut the word count and you’ll come across as more personal.</p>
<p><strong>Original &#8211; Not concise </strong></p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="300">&nbsp;</p>
<p>AT&amp;T Free Msg: Welcome abroad! Our AT&amp;T Passport app is required to use in Wi-Fi in participating hotspots. If you have not already done so, please visit <a href="http://www.att.com/getpassportapp">www.att.com/getpassportapp</a> for iPhone, iPad or Android devices. Data charges may apply for download.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><strong>Revised &#8211; Concise</strong></p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="300">&nbsp;</p>
<p>AT&amp;T Free Msg: Welcome abroad! You’ll need our AT&amp;T Passport app to use Wi-Fi in participating hotspots. Please visit <a href="http://www.att.com/getpassportapp">www.att.com/getpassportapp</a> to download it on your iPhone, iPad or Android device. Data charges may apply.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2><strong>3. Give consistent instructions about how to text back</strong>.</h2>
<p>You’re going to reuse those automated texts repeatedly, so write them right. Don’t explain the same task two different ways in the same text—you don’t want to confuse your customer.</p>
<p><strong>Original &#8211; Confusing instructions about how to text back</strong></p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="300">&nbsp;</p>
<p>Salon H20: Reply “C” to confirm Brenda’s appt on Fri, Dec 18 at 12:30 PM. If you have questions, call 301-774-7999. HELP = Help STOP = End msgs</p>
<p>&nbsp;</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><strong>Revised – Consistent instructions</strong></p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="300">&nbsp;</p>
<p>Salon H20: Reply C to confirm Brenda’s appt on Fri, Dec 18 at 12:30 PM. If you have questions, call 301-774-7999. Reply “help” for help or “stop” to end msgs</p>
<p>&nbsp;</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2><strong>4. Use feeling words</strong>.</h2>
<p>One way to offset the automated quality of automated texts is to use words that indicate feelings. (Everyone knows robots don’t have feelings!) Words like “sorry,” “love,” and “happy” all evoke an emotional response in the reader.</p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="300">&nbsp;</p>
<p>A&amp;F: Sorry to see you go! You’ve been unsubscribed from texts. You will no longer receive messages. Contact 866-712-1032 or <u>http://bit.ly/WW3WWw</u> for more info.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>While this automated text—from a presidential candidate whose name begins with an H—doesn’t use a word that names a feeling, such as “sorry,” it uses intense, connected words to build a feeling of connection, including, “at the heart,” and “you’re with me.”</p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="300">&nbsp;</p>
<p>To South Carolina, the volunteers at the heart of our campaign and the supporters who power it: thank you. If you’re with me, chip in now: <a href="http://hrc.ms/bb">http://hrc.ms/bb</a> &#8212; H</p>
<p>&nbsp;</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2><strong>5. Use personal pronouns</strong>.</h2>
<p>If you want your automated texts to connect to your customer, use pronouns such as “we,” “you,” and “us.” Personal words make your texts sound, well, personal.</p>
<p><strong>Original – Personal pronouns build the relationship</strong></p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="300">&nbsp;</p>
<p>We noticed it’s your first time participating! FYI: Your phone number is completely private and we’ll never spam you.</p>
<p>&#8212;</p>
<p>Powered by <u>PollEverywhere.com</u></p>
<p>&nbsp;</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><strong>Revised – Without personal pronouns, the text sounds cold</strong></p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="300">&nbsp;</p>
<p>Thanks for participating for the first time! FYI: Phone numbers are kept completely private and <u>PollEverywhere.com</u> doesn’t send spam.</p>
<p>&#8212;</p>
<p>Powered by <u>PollEverywhere.com</u></p>
<p>&nbsp;</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2><strong>6. Consider using humor if it’s consistent with your brand.</strong></h2>
<p>If your brand voice is light, hip, or irreverent, try humor in your automated texts. Don’t try humor if it gets in the way of your message, however. (Local governments texting citizens about severe weather, I’m talking to you.)</p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="300">&nbsp;</p>
<p>Breaking News! Your GrubHub order is being prepared. Our crystal ball estimates your delivery time <u>between 1:25 PM and 1:35 PM</u>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2><strong>7. Use the conventions for writing text, not email</strong>.</h2>
<p>Your automated texts to customers don’t need to resemble the other ways you write. In fact, they shouldn’t. Texts rarely use “From” to identify the sender, and they don’t need subject lines. The wording in this text makes the sender sound both automated and unaware of how texts are commonly written.</p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="300">&nbsp;</p>
<p>FROM: Headlines Hair Designers</p>
<p>SUBJ: Appt Reminder</p>
<p>MSG: Fri, Feb 12 3:00 pm – Female Hair Cut @ Headlines Hair Designers</p>
<p>&nbsp;</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>The writing in this text has two other problems:</p>
<ul>
<li>“<strong>Female Hair Cut</strong>.” That’s just not what the customer would call it. She’d call it a haircut. She knows she’s female. If Headlines books a longer time for “female” haircuts than it does for “male” haircuts, that’s not information the customer needs to deal with. And the phrase “female hair cut” is just all kinds of wrong.</li>
<li>“<strong>@ Headlines Hair Designers</strong>.” Avoid using the @ sign when you need to write “at.” It makes your text look like it includes a Twitter handle, which could be confusing.</li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>8. Avoid bureaucratic words</strong>.</h2>
<p>Text is a casual customer service channel, even when automated. Don’t use words that make you sound like a lawyer (“ensure,” “advise,” etc.)</p>
<p><strong>Original – Bureaucratic wording</strong></p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="300">&nbsp;</p>
<p>SAFETY MESSAGE: Please ensure your phone is now switched off. Your cabin crew will advise when phones may be switched on again. Thank you for flying Emirates.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><strong>Revised – Plain language</strong></p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="300">&nbsp;</p>
<p>SAFETY MESSAGE: Please check to be sure your phone is now switched off. Your cabin crew will let you know when you may switch your phone on again. Thanks for flying Emirates!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2><strong>9. Avoid weird abbreviations and capitalizations</strong>.</h2>
<p>Automated texts need to be short, given the fact that space is at a premium. However, don’t abbreviate things in a manner no one would recognize. What will most customers think the “S:” means in the flood warning text? Be as clear as possible.</p>
<p><strong>Weird abbreviation</strong></p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="300">&nbsp;</p>
<p>S: Alert Montgomery Flood Warning &#8211; The National Weather Service has issued a FLOOD WARNING for Montgomery County as of 6pm (2/24/16). Flash flooding of streams, creeks, and low-lying areas is occurring or imminent. Do not drive through flooded areas. Do not drive through flood barriers.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Most texts use sentence case (“You qualify for more minutes”), not title case (“You Qualify for More Minutes,”) because most texts are written in short sentences. There’s no reason to write “Msg &amp; Data Rates May Apply” in title case. It makes this text seem more robot-written than human-written.</p>
<p><strong>Weird capitalization</strong></p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="300">&nbsp;</p>
<p>AMC: Conf #123456789. 7 tickets to see Interstellar on 11/29/2016 at 3:25 PM <u>http://bit.ly/ABC1dEf</u>  Msg &amp; Data Rates May Apply</p>
<p>&nbsp;</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>In the text below, the customer is probably wondering, “Why are you screaming at me?” and “Isn’t an LPN a Licensed Practical Nurse?” I’d write out “license plate” this time, or at least do “Plate #.”</p>
<p><strong>Weird capitalization and abbreviation</strong></p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="300">&nbsp;</p>
<p>PARKING SESSION DEACTIVATION REMINDER. Will deactivate: 9:59 PM. Activated: 3/20/2015 7:29 PM. Zone:12345 Space: n/a LPN: 2AB1234</p>
<p>&nbsp;</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2><strong>10. Paraphrase the customer’s question or need in the automated response</strong>.</h2>
<p>The best way to show someone you’re listening (or reading) closely is to restate what he or she asked for or wanted to know. In live customer service, we paraphrase to confirm that we understood the customer’s request. In automated customer service, paraphrasing is only possible when you’re sending specific, not generic, responses.</p>
<p>Though automated, this text comes across as genuine because the second sentence paraphrases the customer’s question or need.</p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="300">&nbsp;</p>
<p>Thanks for contacting Evanston 311. Please reply with the name of a restaurant that you are interested in seeing a health score for.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2><strong>Conclusion</strong></h2>
<p>So, to wrap up, even if you’re sending automated texts you should write them in a personal, friendly, connected style. Every text to a customer represents a chance to build a relationship.</p>
<p><strong>To learn what or what not to do when adding texting to your business, <a href="https://onereach.com/resources/10-things-about-text">download the whitepaper here</a>.</strong></p>
<p>Image of <a href="https://pixabay.com/en/business-technology-cell-phone-690675/">business texting</a> courtesy of Pixabay. CC0 License.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/how-to-write-automated-texts-that-sound-human/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>[INFOGRAPHIC] How Bad Customer Service Affects Your Business</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/infographic-how-bad-customer-service-affects-your-business/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/infographic-how-bad-customer-service-affects-your-business/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Best Practices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Infographic]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/infographic-how-bad-customer-service-affects-your-business/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This guest post is written by Robbie Richards, a member of the content marketing team at Jitbit.</em></p>
<p>Consider this:</p>
<p>89% of consumers have stopped doing business with a company because of a bad experience.</p>
<p>AND&#8230;</p>
<p>86% will not purchase from a business with negative online reviews.</p>
<p><i>The takeaway?</i></p>
<p>Bad customer service is the fastest way to lose existing customers, and deter potential customers from ever stepping foot in your door.<br />
<span id="more-7409"></span><br />
It is estimated to cost US businesses $84 billion a year.</p>
<p>Despite the bottom line implications, there are still a lot of companies out there failing to make support a major priority in 2016. More attention is given to acquisition, instead of retention.</p>
<p>As a result, companies incur higher marketing costs, their customers jump ship and go to the competition, and profit margins start to shrink.</p>
<p>It will slowly kill a business.</p>
<p>To illustrate just how big of an impact bad customer service can have on <b>your </b>business, the team at <a href="https://www.jitbit.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">JitBit </a>have put together the infographic below. If you want to learn more, check out the <a href="https://www.jitbit.com/news/bad-customer-service/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">11 most costly traits of bad customer service</a>.</p>
<p><img class="wp-image-2540 aligncenter" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Bad-customer-service-infographic_2.jpg" alt="Bad-customer-service-infographic_2" width="700" height="7447" /></p>
<h2 style="text-align: left;"><strong>About the Author</strong></h2>
<p><i><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-2541" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/profilepic.png" alt="profilepic" width="133" height="153" /></i>Robbie Richards writes for JitBit, a company that provides live chat and <a href="https://www.jitbit.com/helpdesk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">helpdesk software</a> to help businesses simplify and improve their customer support.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>To learn more from the experts on how to provide good, not bad, customer service, <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/customer-service-report-2015">download our influencer report here</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/infographic-how-bad-customer-service-affects-your-business/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Learn 7 Ways to Spice Up Your Customer Experience</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/learn-7-ways-to-spice-up-your-customer-experience/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/learn-7-ways-to-spice-up-your-customer-experience/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Best Practices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Experience]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/learn-7-ways-to-spice-up-your-customer-experience/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Some companies still haven&#8217;t found the magic recipe for providing a great customer experience, but OneReach&#8217;s Elias Parker might be able to help them out. <a href="http://uxmag.com/articles/these-7-ingredients-can-revitalize-customer-experience">In an article published by UX Mag</a>, Elias lists seven things companies can add to spice up their customer experience, including speed, variety, and consistency.</p>
<blockquote><p><span id="more-7169"></span>If you started swinging by the same Starbucks every day and always ordered a half-caf latte, you’d eventually expect the employees to know your order. The same kind of logic applies to customer experience: each time a company interacts with a customer, they should keep track of why they were contacted and what their response was. Customers expect you to know what their past interactions were about without having to repeat themselves.</p></blockquote>
<p><a href="http://uxmag.com/articles/these-7-ingredients-can-revitalize-customer-experience">Take a look at the rest of the article</a> to see what other ways you can provide the best customer experience, and download the <a href="http://onereachcontactcenter.com/high-demand-for-customer-service-via-text-message/">free Harris Interactive report</a> to learn more about how customers want service delivered.</p>
<p>Photo by Flickr user <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/toasty/2152070020">Kenneth Yu</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/learn-7-ways-to-spice-up-your-customer-experience/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>9 IVR Best Practices You Need to Know</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/9-ivr-best-practices-you-need-to-know/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/9-ivr-best-practices-you-need-to-know/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Best Practices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IVR]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/9-ivr-best-practices-you-need-to-know/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Interactive voice response (also known as IVR) is one of the most notorious service channels of all time. Originally introduced to decrease the amount of time agents needed to spend on the phone while increasing the number of problems solved. Unfortunately, IVR ended up creating brand new problems for the customer: long hold times, confusing menus and the continual inability to reach a rep. Today,<a href="http://www.interactions.net/2011/06/so-people-hate-ivr-is-this-news-to-anyone/"> only 13% of consumers</a> think IVR is easy to use, and only 15% believe IVR use benefits them.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Luckily, IVR doesn’t have to be this way.<a href="http://www.nuance.com/for-business/by-solution/customer-service-solutions/newsletter-issue-2/index.htm"> Over two-thirds of consumers</a> would prefer to use self-service technologies like IVR rather than speak with a live agent; they just haven’t had a great experience with it until now. Here are nine IVR best practices on to help you create a better service experience for both companies and customers.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><span id="more-7167"></span><strong>1. Let customers communicate how they want.</strong> Customers don’t think in terms of channels; they’re just trying to solve their problem by any means available. Don’t be afraid to give the caller the option to “speak with someone at any time by pressing star.” If you have the ability to channel pivot, you can provide them the option to switch to text message automation instead of voice automation so they can use the channel they want. It’s not just giving them the option to change the channel; it’s making each existing channel better for the customer.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>2. Keep it short and simple.</strong> Remember that people have no ability to visually see the options: they have to listen to the options one by one, so do everything you can to not include more than four options at a time. The longer the prompt, the more you risk losing their attention and forgetting what they heard in the beginning. Find every opportunity to be extremely concise. For example, “If you are interested in talking with someone about our sales offerings, press&#8230;” can become “For sales, press&#8230;”</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>3. Maintain context.</strong><a href="http://www.accenture.com/SiteCollectionDocuments/PDF/Accenture-Global-Consumer-Pulse-Research-Study-2013-Key-Findings.pdf"> Almost 90% of customers</a> hate having to repeat their problems multiple times. Keep track of the information gathered in the IVR so that when the customer is finally connected with an agent, they can get right down to business instead of going over the minutiae. The process goes a whole lot faster and the customer doesn’t get flustered trying to get you to <a href="http://pro.whitepages.com/3-tips-providing-ultimate-customer-experience-contact-center/">pronounce their hometown correctly</a>.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>4. Option before action.</strong> Have you ever been in an IVR where you are distracted, hear the option you want and snap back, only to find that the IVR has moved onto the next option? You then have to sit through the entire menu again. Each prompt has an option and an action&#8211;the best practice is to give the option first and the action second. For example, if you want a customer to press one to contact sales, you would say “For Sales” (the option) before “Press One” (the action). That way you don’t risk them forgetting what to press and having to restart. If you determine that the system has a hard time understanding them, the primary prompts from then on out in the flow should over be carried out DTMF (dual-tone multi-frequency, aka button pushing).</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>5. Be nice (but not too nice).</strong> Of course you want to be polite when you’re talking to a customer, but it’s important not to overdo it. Avoid using “please” for every request can become overly repetitious. If a customer completes a simple task like pressing a button, they don’t need to be thanked for it. On the flip side, if a customer has been waiting on hold for 20 minutes and gets connected to an agent, that would be an instance where you’d want to thank them for their patience.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>6. Let customers bypass the system.</strong> For every customer happily using IVR, there’s another customer who would rather speak with a live agent ASAP. Don’t be afraid to give the caller the option to “speak with someone at any time by pressing star.” If you have the ability to channel pivot, you can provide them the option to switch to text message automation instead of voice automation. Avoid going any further than three menus deep&#8211;you will be testing the caller’s patience after that.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>7.  Don’t make the same mistake over and over.</strong> If your customers get tripped up on one IVR step, Increase their chances of successfully navigating the IVR by making sure each re-prompt has different wording. The best practice is to start with voice recognition (e.g. “say Sales, say Support”) and then if unrecognized, give them the choices with different wording, then again in DTMF (“press one, press two”). If customers continue too a hard time with the voice recognition, present prompts from then on out in the flow should over DTMF options instead of voice recognition.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>8. Don’t abandon your IVR.</strong> Just like any other piece of machinery, your IVR needs regular tune-ups to make sure it’s working correctly. If agents are handling more calls than usual or customers are hanging up without going through the IVR, it might be time to reevaluate things. Industry experts recommend reviewing an up-an-running IVR once a month; newer systems should be reviewed on a daily to weekly basis.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>9. Add a personal touch.</strong> After your customer has used your IVR several times, you should start to notice a pattern in his or her behavior. Do they call in the same time every month to schedule an appointment? Are they consistently having trouble with one of your products? Do they call in at a specific time of day? After watching their behavior over a period of time, you should adapt your IVR to suit their needs based on their preferences and interaction history. Customers will appreciate the fact that you respect their time and will be more likely to use your IVR in the future.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em>To learn more about designing best-in-class text flows, professionally designed or do-it-yourself, visit <a href="onereach.com">onereach.com</a>.</em></p>
<p dir="ltr">Photo by Flickr user <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/columodwyer/8489536745">Colum O&#8217;Dwyer</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/9-ivr-best-practices-you-need-to-know/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>10 Things To Consider When Text-Enabling Your Contact Center</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/10-things-to-consider-when-text-enabling-your-contact-center/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/10-things-to-consider-when-text-enabling-your-contact-center/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Best Practices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Contact Center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/10-things-to-consider-when-text-enabling-your-contact-center/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">The following provides a rough outline of what needs to be considered when implementing text messaging services in a contact center or business. While some of these items may seem daunting they can actually be completed pretty quickly depending on the size and scope of the implementation.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><span id="more-7144"></span></p>
<ol>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Identify text support targets (Based on value and feasibility)</strong> – Not everything can be or should be supported through text messaging. Companies should consider using texting for support tasks that can be resolved quickly or that can reduce customer wait time. (such as order or ticket status) Tasks that require sensitive data such as password resets or billing information should be avoided unless precautions can be taken on the implementation.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<ol start="2">
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Automation and Live agent blend</strong> – Over 60% of Americans who text would prefer to text a contact center with their customer service needs rather than call in. Companies should determine what level of automation is appropriate for each support task and when to include an agent. Some tasks can be completely automated while others can be only partly automated ending in an agent interaction. Using relevant data from back office systems during a text interaction can reduce agent chat time and improve customer experience.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<ol start="3">
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Text support discovery mechanisms</strong> – In order for customers to use text support, they need to know about it. A common and effective way to introduce the concept of texting a business is to announce it in the IVR. Another option is to have a live agent inform them that they can send them a text message notification for things like problem resolutions, documentation, schedule reminders, etc. Websites and other online and printed material are also useful.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<ol start="4">
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Customer experience plan</strong> – Because text messaging is such an intimate channel, it is critical to get the user experience right. Chances are if a customer has a bad experience they will decide to go back to calling your company and leave the text channel for good. To ensure that CX is accounted for during the deployment of text services, companies should consider establishing a UX outline, adding A/B testing support, and determine appropriate KPIs and reports.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<ol start="5">
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Inbound/outbound mix</strong> – Based on the type of text message support services that are identified, the texting volumes between inbound automated messages, live support and outbound proactive notifications must be determined. This will help identify the type of text message solution to implement. Establishing a baseline of estimated inbound/outbound text message volumes can be done based on the type of task and the automation that will be implemented.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<ol start="6">
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Long code vs. Short code</strong> – For common support interactions, long codes (a company’s 10 digit telephone number) can be used for 1-to-1 interactions between a business and a customer (1 to 3 is a rough limit). Long codes are more recognizable to a customer since they text people all the time. Short codes are generally better for large volume outbound blasts but can be used interactively as well. Both have their merits but long codes are generally cheaper, more flexible and can even be enabled for a companies 1800  number. Companies must consider MMA and carrier guidelines when determining the type of number and implementation to use.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<ol start="7">
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Back office Integration strategy</strong> – As part of the automation strategy you need to determine which back office solutions are required for integration and what integration options are available. Common ones are CRM, Billing, and Ticketing.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<ol start="8">
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Agent staffing</strong> – While it is possible to use your  existing web chat agents to support text messaging support tasks, it is not always the best choice. Phone agents are usually trained to answer support questions and already have the required tools therefore it may make sense to have phone agents  manage text interactions depending on where the customer is in the support process. Also, since phone agents take calls, they can easily transition from text to voice and back if needed. However, it’s important to remember that text chat is not the same as a web chat. For instance, there are text restrictions (160 characters) and the type of interactions and approach will vary.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<ol start="9">
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Channel integrations</strong> – As part of an overall customer experience plan there needs to be thought given to how text messaging will fit into the overall channel strategy. For instance, will the customer be able to start on a voice call and transition to text messaging and back? How will agents support text along with other channels? How will you be able to track a customer’s interactions across channels? This might include the need to consolidate of Voice of the Customer (VOC) customer satisfaction scores.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<ol start="10">
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Text support rollout plan</strong> – Once the decision has been made to include text messaging into the support mix, there are different ways to go about the implementation. Generally, starting with a pilot which is only exposed to a certain amount of the customer pool is the safest. This can be supported in a typical A/B testing fashion, such as only exposing the service to a limited amount of people that call in or visit a page. The other option is to choose one or two support tasks with limited use and track the engagement level. Data gathering and testing is the goal in the initial phases. Based on initial customer feedback you can iterate through the experience until you get the VOC scores that are desired.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p><em>To learn more about text-enabling your existing phone number, visit <a href="http://www.onereach.com">onereach.com</a>.</em></p>
<p>Photo by Flickr user <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/122969584@N07/13780153345/in/photolist-7xMwVL-dDQ8L-mZGTuM-efiKyE-aMV1Ae-5LqyNr-4D5chi-57gjm3-oZAx5-297mx8-F6B9B-mZGXyi-4tXLnF-3fAHEC-ajRYzx-eKvdAk-2mH7Ew-3fwjj4-cTz5RS-6BDxAu-3fvbJe-cW1Lk5-7SSJvk-9XiVES-9e6hnM-bubUum-haG8mz-4PGpH3-cKwD3A-6PmyVV-8rqwjP-8Zf5Ac-8Pviar-nVMH1r-awG2xv-bH6JEX-nTrNNG-bH6JLa-bH6HEv-bubV3d-bubV4s-bubV5m-bubTdq-bH6GYk-bH6GDD-bubTJq-bubT9S-bubUwW-bH6EGv-bH6Ewt">CWCS Managed Hosting</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/10-things-to-consider-when-text-enabling-your-contact-center/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Tips When Adding New Communication Channels into Your Business</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/5-tips-when-adding-new-communication-channels-into-your-business/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/5-tips-when-adding-new-communication-channels-into-your-business/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Best Practices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Communication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/5-tips-when-adding-new-communication-channels-into-your-business/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The way people communicate with one another is rapidly changing. We are spending more time online or sending text messages than talking on the phone. In fact, if you’re out in public and take a look around, you’re bound to see someone texting within 10 feet of you.</p>
<p><span id="more-7107"></span>In the same way that communication has changed between individuals, there is now a fundamental shift in how consumers interact with businesses. According to <a href="http://www.genesys.com/resources/whitepapers/deploying-a-contact-center-in-the-cloudin-the-cloud.pdf">research from Ovum</a> on consumer preferences for customer service, the use of alternate customer service communication channels such as <a href="http://onereachcontactcenter.com/sms/">SMS</a>, email, and web chat has more than doubled in a two-year period. And really, when <i>was</i> the last time you actually picked up a phone to call a customer service representative?</p>
<p>The reality is that businesses either need to embrace new technology and focus on new communication channels or risk getting left behind. For most this may be easier said then done, so we’ve put together some tips to consider when adding new communication channels to your contact center.</p>
<h2><strong>Tip #1: Throw away traditional metrics and rethink your KPIs</strong></h2>
<p>If you work in, near, or around a contact center, then you’re probably all too familiar with average call times or average resolution time. Well, not surprisingly, when you add new channels, these metrics are no longer enough. Make sure that you consider each of your channels when creating performance metrics. Companies need to use metrics &amp; KPIs that truly evaluate the effect of a channel on both customer experience and internal efficiency. Analytics + insights = awesome multichannel management.</p>
<h2><strong>Tip #2: Eliminate information silos </strong></h2>
<p>When moving from one communication channel to multiple communication channels, it is <b>crucial</b>  that voice interactions cross into other channels like text or web chat to create a fully <a href="http://onereachcontactcenter.com/integrations/">integrated, personalized experience</a> for your customer. Each interaction should seem like it is managed by one—not multiple—organizations. This means ensuring that the customer is tracked across all channels. Take it from us—your customer doesn’t want to look up their account number every time they communicate with your business.</p>
<h2><strong>Tip #3: Make sure your agents are trained properly</strong></h2>
<p>It may seem obvious, but agents must be comfortable engaging across all channels. A customer representative who has previously only been trained to manage phone calls may have a different skill set than a customer rep who has always handled web chat. If you’re going to offer multiple channels, make sure you take the time and resources to train employees so that they have the knowledge to create the ultimate customer experience.</p>
<h2><strong>Tip #4: Create guides for web and text speak</strong></h2>
<p>Don’t assume that your employees will always have appropriate texting and web chat etiquette. What works in personal conversation is often not the type of language that you would want representing your business. Tone is very difficult to interpret over text, so even something as simple as changing “Reminder” to “A friendly reminder” can make a world of difference in the way your brand is perceived. If you’re interested in learning more, check out <a href="http://onereachcontactcenter.com/10-sms-tips-for-companies/"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">10</span><span style="text-decoration: underline;"> Things Every Company Should Know Before Using Text Messaging</span></a>.</p>
<h2><strong>Tip #5: Provide a consistent experience across all channels</strong></h2>
<p>If you’re going to offer multiple channels of communication, you had better do it right. Multichannel customer service isn’t simply about facilitating seamless transitions between channels, but providing a superior, consistent experience across each channel. The more channels there are, the easier it is for the experience to become mismanaged. In order to provide a consistent experience, it is imperative that a customer conversation has context through <a href="http://onereachcontactcenter.com/integrations/">integrated customer data</a>, history, and <a href="http://onereachcontactcenter.com/automation/">automation</a>. The best contact centers have systems that play well with each other.</p>
<p>Your multichannel contact center should be committed to providing the best customer experience around.</p>
<p><i>Have any more tips for multichannel contact centers? Comment and let us know!</i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/5-tips-when-adding-new-communication-channels-into-your-business/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
