<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>News &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<atom:link href="https://onereach.ai/category/news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<description>Intelligently Automate Your Company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 11:39:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/cropped-OR-ICON-GOLD-W-DOTS-Larger-Background-02-32x32.png</url>
	<title>News &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>OneReach CEO Featured In Contact Center Pipeline</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/onereach-ceo-featured-in-contact-center-pipeline/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/onereach-ceo-featured-in-contact-center-pipeline/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/onereach-ceo-featured-in-contact-center-pipeline/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>OneReach CEO Rich Weborg was recently featured in Contact Center Pipeline&#8217;s article &#8220;Texting with Customers.&#8221;</p>
<p><span id="more-7397"></span>In it, he discussed the prevalence of texting as a communication channel, as well as how texting fits into a company&#8217;s customer service strategy.</p>
<blockquote><p>Text is the app that never leaves your phone. It&#8217;s the only app everybody has that is consistent, no matter what mobile platform or wireless carrier the consumer uses.</p></blockquote>
<p>We believe that text messaging is an essential part of a company’s support strategy, as 64% of customers would prefer texting to calling for customer service. Businesses that offer texting to customers will be able to meet customer demand for alternative communication channels while providing a cost-effective communication solution.</p>
<p>You&#8217;ll need a Contact Center Pipeline subscription to view the article. You can sign up for free and download this issue <a href="https://www.contactcenterpipeline.com/signin.aspx?ReturnURL=CcpDownloadPub.aspx&amp;PubID=1197">here</a>.</p>
<p><strong>To learn more about adding texting to your customer service strategy, <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/mobile-strategy">download our newest whitepaper here</a>.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/onereach-ceo-featured-in-contact-center-pipeline/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Clinton Uses Texting and Voice To Attack Sanders</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/clinton-uses-texting-and-voice-to-attack-sanders/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/clinton-uses-texting-and-voice-to-attack-sanders/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Use Cases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/clinton-uses-texting-and-voice-to-attack-sanders/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/election-texting-post/">We&#8217;ve written before</a> about how texting could be used for political campaigns. You could use it for voter registration, voting day reminders, or even to set up a text hotline to get real-time feedback on what&#8217;s going on at polling places.</p>
<p>But now we can add a new texting use case to the list: attack ads.</p>
<p><span id="more-7393"></span>BuzzFeed News Reporter Evan McMorris-Santoro <a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/evanmcsan/clinton-uses-presidents-day-to-accuse-sanders-of-disloyalty#.hroMQE3RY">had a firsthand experience</a> with this texting use case. He received a text message from the Clinton campaign touting her support of Barack Obama and calling out &#8220;someone&#8221; who didn&#8217;t support Obama.</p>
<p>When Evan texted back the word HEAR to learn more, he got an automated call from the Hillary campaign with a soundbite of her supporting one of Obama&#8217;s decisions and Bernie Sanders opposing him. After the call, it ended with a text saying Hillary was the only one who would continue Obama&#8217;s legacy.</p>
<p>This is definitely a unique texting use case, not only for its message but for its use of two communication channels to get that message across. I won&#8217;t get into politics here, but I commend Clinton for using two powerful communication channels together to interact with her base and deliver a one-on-one experience that other channels can&#8217;t.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/evanmcsan/clinton-uses-presidents-day-to-accuse-sanders-of-disloyalty#.hroMQE3RY">Check out the full article on BuzzFeed</a>, and don&#8217;t forget to <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/10-things-about-text">download our whitepaper</a> on the 10 things you need to know when adding texting to your business.</strong></p>
<p><em>The opinions expressed here are solely that of the contributor and don&#8217;t necessarily represent the views of OneReach.</em></p>
<p>Photo by Flickr user <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/cornstalker/23575629583/">Matt A.J</a>. <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/">CC2.0 License</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/clinton-uses-texting-and-voice-to-attack-sanders/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ben &#038; Jerry’s and OneReach: A Sweet Combination</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/ben-jerrys-and-onereach-a-sweet-combination/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/ben-jerrys-and-onereach-a-sweet-combination/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Use Cases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/ben-jerrys-and-onereach-a-sweet-combination/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Climate justice is about to get a little bit sweeter.</p>
<p>Ben &amp; Jerry’s is rallying climate activists (and anyone with a sweet tooth) to take action on climate change. The ice cream maker, a long-time supporter of climate justice, is urging citizens worldwide to contact world leaders in advance of the <a href="http://www.cop21.gouv.fr/en">United Nations Climate Change Conference</a> in Paris, which begins at the end of November.</p>
<p><span id="more-7347"></span>Ben &amp; Jerry’s wants world leaders to commit to strong carbon reduction goals, and is supporting a transitioning to 100% clean energy by 2050. They’re currently offering citizens the ability reach out to decision makers over email, but that can be an easy channel for leaders to ignore.</p>
<p>Phone calls—well, let’s just say they know how to grab your attention.</p>
<p>For their current campaign, “Save Our Swirled,” Ben &amp; Jerry’s wanted to provide communication channels that were going to be the most impactful on this issue, and knew that direct calls would be a great, easy way to for citizens to take action. They decided to use voice calls to contact local leaders, specifically state governors to implement the US Clean Power Plan, and they turned to OneReach to help make their vision a reality.</p>
<p>OneReach designed a click-to-call widget for the website that not only lets citizens call governors, but also lets them tweet at or email them. (<a href="http://www.benjerry.com/flavors/salted-caramel-brownie-ale-ice-cream">Check out the widget here</a>&#8211;you have to be over 21). For Ben &amp; Jerry’s, this secondary option means they can engage with state leaders on the channel they prefer, but also have the ability to contact state leaders multiple times.</p>
<p>This isn’t Ben and Jerry’s only climate campaign, though. They produce a lot of content educating fans on climate justice, and have even taxed their own CO2 omissions to be used to reduce carbon impact. Their goal is to reduce their impact by 80% by 2050.</p>
<p>We’re excited to have helped Ben &amp; Jerry’s and are glad we’re giving activists (and ice cream lovers) the chance to serve up climate justice.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/ben-jerrys-and-onereach-a-sweet-combination/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>OneReach Featured in Forrester Report</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/onereach-featured-in-forrester-report/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/onereach-featured-in-forrester-report/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Big Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/onereach-featured-in-forrester-report/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Big news!</p>
<p>OneReach was recently featured in the <a href="https://www.forrester.com/Weave+Support+For+Text+Chat+Into+Your+Omnichannel+Customer+Service+Strategy/fulltext/-/E-res122956">Forrester report</a> &#8220;Weave Support For Text Chat Into Your Omnichannel Customer Service Strategy.&#8221; We are honored to have been included and are in agreement with all of their findings.</p>
<p><span id="more-7341"></span>What we liked about the report is that it acknowledged the prevalence of text messaging and its importance in an omnichannel strategy. It also addressed the importance of incorporating interactive text into your channel mix, as well as some key challenges that text chat faces.</p>
<p>As we’ve covered before and as this report ably does, texting is great way to engage customers on a channel they already use. Forrester research has found that 77% of online consumers who use a cell phone send or receive text messages at least monthly or more.</p>
<p>Again, we are very honored to have been included in this report and hope to be considered for future ones if the situation allows.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.forrester.com/Weave+Support+For+Text+Chat+Into+Your+Omnichannel+Customer+Service+Strategy/fulltext/-/E-res122956">You can read the summary of the report here</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/onereach-featured-in-forrester-report/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>OneReach Launches Shared Short Code</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/onereach-launches-shared-short-code/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/onereach-launches-shared-short-code/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/onereach-launches-shared-short-code/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Big news! OneReach has debuted a new shared short code, 70700, as an alternative to our existing long code numbers. Clients can choose a name for their short code program (ie “CompanyInfo”), which will also serve as their keyword.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">End users who text in that keyword into the shared 70700 number will be directed to a client’s flow associated with that keyword. Clients can also assign several different keywords to the 70700 number and have all the keywords direct users to the same flow.</span></p>
<p><span id="more-7251"></span>Clients can currently receive 150 messages a minute (2.5 messages a second) over the shared short code, with capacity set to increase in the coming weeks. Any business can harness short codes to:</p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">send time-sensitive updates to customers</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">field common customer questions like store hours </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">send out marketing messages offering special deals to subscribers</span></li>
</ul>
<p><strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’re excited to be able to offer shared short codes; we believe our clients should have the option to choose the type of number that best suits their needs, and our short code launch will help us further accomplish that.</span></strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/onereach-launches-shared-short-code/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>OneReach Crafts Unique Campaign With Stella Artois</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/onereach-crafts-unique-campaign-with-stella-artois/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/onereach-crafts-unique-campaign-with-stella-artois/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Big Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IVR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Use Cases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/onereach-crafts-unique-campaign-with-stella-artois/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Are you ready to say bonjour to the simple life? Stella Artois thinks so.</p>
<p><a href="onereach.com">OneReach</a> recently collaborated with <a href="http://www.stellaartois.com/en_us/stella-artois-cidre/hamptons-picnic-properties.html">Stella Artois</a>, ad agency <a href="http://www.mothernewyork.com/">Mother New York</a> and production company <a href="http://www.stopp.se/">Stopp</a> to create a unique user experience for Stella Artois web visitors. To promote their Hamptons Picnic Properties sweepstakes, Stella Artois provided users with an interactive experience where users could chat with brand ambassador Le Président before entering to win the competition.</p>
<p><span id="more-7242"></span>Users who visit the Stella Artois Cidre website can input their phone number and receive a call from the fictional Le Président. The user and Le Président can then engage in a conversation about hair care, the perfect date, and even selfies.</p>
<p>Mother New York was responsible for the overall creative idea and campaign, while Stopp was responsible for the creative execution and development. OneReach facilitated the phone call and voice recognition through VoIP.</p>
<p>Nicole Ferraris, interactive producer at Stopp, had this to say about the OneReach platform:</p>
<blockquote><p>What caught our attention with OneReach was the turnkey solution for voice recognition and the graphical user interface, allowing us to design an interactive phone call very quickly. By leveraging an existing tool set like OneReach, we could devote more of our time to polishing the user experience instead of constructing the underlying system.</p></blockquote>
<p>OneReach CEO Rich Weborg was equally impressed with this unique use case, saying:</p>
<blockquote><p>We were really impressed by how the team at Stopp used IVR capabilities to create an engaging (and funny!) interactive video for their marketing program. Our product has a wide variety of use cases, but this was truly a first for us. Stopp’s creative use of our technology was really impressive. They did a great job of weaving the technology (voice and web) together for a seamless experience. We would love to work with them again on equally exciting programs.</p></blockquote>
<p>Want to try out the experience for yourself? Give Le Président a call below! And to learn more about creating a personalized experience for customers, <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/omnichannel-seamless-experience">download our ebook here</a>.</p>
<p><iframe src="http://hamptonspicnicproperties.com" width="750" height="422" frameborder="0" scrolling="yes" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe>Photo Credit: <a href="http://www.mothernewyork.com/news/hamptons-picnic-properties">Mother New York</a>. Edited.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/onereach-crafts-unique-campaign-with-stella-artois/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>OneReach Featured on NBC&#8217;s 9News</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/onereach-featured-on-nbcs-9news/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/onereach-featured-on-nbcs-9news/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/onereach-featured-on-nbcs-9news/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Exciting news! OneReach was recently featured as part of <a href="http://www.9news.com/story/tech/personal-tech/stories/2015/06/09/tech-tuesday-laptop-stand-dating-site/28745289/">&#8220;Tech Tuesday&#8221; on NBC&#8217;s 9News</a>, where they profile three interesting Colorado tech companies every week. In addition to a video feature (starting at 1:54, below), they had the following to say about OneReach.</p>
<blockquote><p><span id="more-7241"></span>For the Crushing It category, we have <a title="http://www.onereach.com/" href="http://www.onereach.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">OneReach,</a> based in West Denver. This company makes it easier for other companies to interact with all of their customers. We live in a world where younger people especially never talk on the phone, they prefer texting, social media, etc. Yet many older companies still require customers to interact with them by making a phone call. OneReach makes it possible for all kinds of communication to reach the right people at a company, and make sure those customers satisfied. They are already doing work for RE/MAX and other big names, and they are hiring.</p></blockquote>
<p>We&#8217;re very excited to have received attention from a prominent Denver news station and are eager to stay top-of-mind in the months and years to come.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.9news.com/story/tech/personal-tech/stories/2015/06/09/tech-tuesday-laptop-stand-dating-site/28745289/">Check out the full article here</a>, and don&#8217;t forget to watch the video below (starts at 1:54).</p>
<p><object id="flashObj" width="640" height="390" classid="clsid:D27CDB6E-AE6D-11cf-96B8-444553540000" codebase="http://download.macromedia.com/pub/shockwave/cabs/flash/swflash.cab#version=9,0,47,0"><param name="movie" value="http://c.brightcove.com/services/viewer/federated_f9?isSlim=1" /><param name="bgcolor" value="#FFFFFF" /><param name="flashVars" value="videoId=4285501838001&amp;playerID=2862111174001&amp;playerKey=AQ~~,AAAAB_wnNRk~,WN9MweAQd_tph1IXNFcwfQg_Iu_Aq-oV&amp;domain=embed&amp;dynamicStreaming=true" /><param name="base" value="http://admin.brightcove.com" /><param name="seamlesstabbing" value="false" /><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /><param name="swLiveConnect" value="true" /><param name="allowScriptAccess" value="always" /><embed src="http://c.brightcove.com/services/viewer/federated_f9?isSlim=1" bgcolor="#FFFFFF" flashvars="videoId=4285501838001&amp;playerID=2862111174001&amp;playerKey=AQ~~,AAAAB_wnNRk~,WN9MweAQd_tph1IXNFcwfQg_Iu_Aq-oV&amp;domain=embed&amp;dynamicStreaming=true" base="http://admin.brightcove.com" name="flashObj" width="640" height="390" seamlesstabbing="false" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" swliveconnect="true" allowscriptaccess="always" pluginspage="http://www.macromedia.com/shockwave/download/index.cgi?P1_Prod_Version=ShockwaveFlash" /></object></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/onereach-featured-on-nbcs-9news/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>OneReach CEO Featured On Dell.com</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/onereach-ceo-featured-on-dell-com/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/onereach-ceo-featured-on-dell-com/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/onereach-ceo-featured-on-dell-com/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Exciting news!</p>
<p>OneReach CEO Rich Weborg was recently featured on <a href="https://powermore.dell.com/technology/will-voip-and-unified-communications-define-the-future/">Dell.com&#8217;s Power More site</a>, which provides information and analysis on technology, business, and gadget-geek culture. In the article, Rich discussed the future of VOIP and unified communications and highlighted three key trends companies should be taking note of, such as channel convergence.</p>
<blockquote><p><span id="more-7237"></span>&#8220;While the communication industry has been talking about multi- and omnichannel for a while, a lot of channels are still not supported within a UC perspective. Of course text messaging comes to mind. Not many companies allow a customer to text for support and use automation or live agent interactions to get help from a business in that channel. To add to this, we will also see other text apps like WhatsApp and Facebook Messenger begin to support businesses. If a customer wants to use that channel, customers and providers will ultimately support it.”</p></blockquote>
<p>We believe that text messaging is an essential part of a company&#8217;s support strategy, as customers are starting to demand service on more channels than ever. Businesses that provide service on the channels customers want will be able to increase engagement and overall satisfaction.</p>
<p>To read the rest of the article, <a href="https://powermore.dell.com/technology/will-voip-and-unified-communications-define-the-future/">click here</a>, and don&#8217;t forget to <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/omnichannel-seamless-experience">download our new ebook</a> on the seamless customer experience.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/onereach-ceo-featured-on-dell-com/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>OneReach Featured in CRM Magazine</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/onereach-featured-in-crm-magazine/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/onereach-featured-in-crm-magazine/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/onereach-featured-in-crm-magazine/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Exciting news!</p>
<p>OneReach CEO Rich Weborg was recently featured in an article from the April issue of CRM Magazine, &#8220;<a href="http://www.destinationcrm.com/Articles/ReadArticle.aspx?ArticleID=102615&amp;PageNum=1">Text Takes Precedence as a Customer Service Preference</a>.&#8221; In it, he discusses the history of text messaging within business, the advances made in today&#8217;s text market, and best practices surrounding the text channel.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8216;When texting started, it was expensive for businesses to get started, and it was heavily regulated,&#8217; Weborg says. &#8216;What we’ve been seeing over the last few years is that it’s becoming flexible and cheap for businesses to set up. The price is so low now that any business can have access to [text messaging],&#8217; he adds.</p></blockquote>
<p><span id="more-7219"></span>At OneReach, we believe that text messaging is a powerful customer service tool , and we&#8217;re excited that the service industry is recognizing its value.</p>
<p><strong><em><a href="http://www.destinationcrm.com/Articles/ReadArticle.aspx?ArticleID=102615&amp;PageNum=1">Check out the full article here</a>, and don&#8217;t forget to download our <a href="http://onereachcontactcenter.com/high-demand-for-customer-service-via-text-message/">2014 Harris Report</a> on customers&#8217; preference for text message in customer service!</em></strong></p>
<p>DestinationCRM is designed to serve as a resource for companies who have identified CRM as a key aspect of their business strategy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/onereach-featured-in-crm-magazine/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>OneReach Named One of 50 Colorado Startups to Watch in 2015</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/onereach-named-one-of-50-colorado-startups-to-watch-in-2015/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/onereach-named-one-of-50-colorado-startups-to-watch-in-2015/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/onereach-named-one-of-50-colorado-startups-to-watch-in-2015/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Exciting news!</p>
<p>Built In Colorado named OneReach as one of <a href="http://www.builtincolorado.com/blog/50-colorado-startups-watch-2015">50 Colorado startups</a> to watch in 2015. The list features 50 cloud-software companies all founded in the last five years, spanning the state from Denver to Boulder to Louisville.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re excited and honored to be one of the 50 startups to watch in 2015! This is great feedback and adds to our belief that the future of powerful enterprise software lies in cloud (read more about cloud-software benefits for the contact center <a href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/?p=1105">here</a>).</p>
<p>We can&#8217;t wait to see what the rest of the year brings!</p>
<p><a href="http://www.builtincolorado.com/">Built In Colorado</a> is a news and hiring resource for startups in the state of Colorado.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/onereach-named-one-of-50-colorado-startups-to-watch-in-2015/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
