<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Gripes &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<atom:link href="https://onereach.ai/category/gripes/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<description>Intelligently Automate Your Company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 11:39:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/cropped-OR-ICON-GOLD-W-DOTS-Larger-Background-02-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Gripes &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>5 Lessons Learned from Customer Service Failures</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/5-lessons-learned-from-customer-service-failures/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/5-lessons-learned-from-customer-service-failures/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Customer Experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gripes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guest Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Self-Service]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/5-lessons-learned-from-customer-service-failures/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This guest post is written by Erica Strother Marois, the Community Specialist at <a href="http://www.icmi.com">ICMI</a>. </em></p>
<p>We’ve all been on the receiving end of poor customer service. Long wait times, annoying IVRs, unforgiving return policies, and a lack of channel options can all be maddening. And inevitably, these frustrations spill over to the front line employees. Customer service is more complex and stressful than ever, and ICMI research indicates that <a href="http://www.icmi.com/Resources/Research/2015-Smarter-Service-for-the-Connected-Consumer">the industry</a> is only growing more complicated.</p>
<p>What can customer service leaders do to alleviate stress and improve the customer experience? To answer that, we turn to some of the most infamous customer service failures in recent history. (After all, some of the best insight comes from the biggest failures).</p>
<p><span id="more-7385"></span>Here are five lessons learned from headline-grabbing customer service failures:</p>
<h2><strong>1. Sometimes customers are wrong. Make it easier for them to be right.</strong></h2>
<p>“The customer is always right.” It’s a quote that business professionals have recited for years, but <em>is</em> the customer always right? Or is the customer ever to blame for poor service?</p>
<p>Remember the Maine Diner that kicked a customer out of her restaurant last summer? The customer’s child was disruptive, so she asked them to leave. Who was right? Plenty of people actually sided with the owner.</p>
<p>And remember this controversial <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/matt-walsh/bad-customer-service_b_3799574.html">Huffington Post article from 2013</a>?</p>
<p>Honestly, the customer isn’t always right. But it’s our job to treat them like they are. And even more importantly, it’s our job to make it easier for them to be right.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-2414 size-full" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/erica-blog-post-1.png" alt="customer service failures" width="542" height="191" /></p>
<p>Are your customers calling the wrong line for service? Perhaps your customers are angry about late fees imposed on their account? Think about what you could do to prevent the situation from ever taking place.  Could you improve your website? Could you send text reminders to let your customers know their bill due date is approaching? In the case of that Maine diner—should the owner offer snacks and coloring books for young children? Perhaps a kid-friendly seating section?</p>
<p>Sure—customers are wrong sometimes, but that shouldn’t change their experience, or your company’s approach to service.</p>
<h2><strong>2. Taking ownership doesn’t mean taking blame.</strong></h2>
<p>It’s human nature to be defensive. No one enjoys being wrong. Unfortunately, defensiveness doesn’t solve problems. When it comes to customer interactions, it’s essential to take ownership when situations don’t go as planned. This doesn’t always mean falling on the sword and taking all the blame, it means taking responsibility for making the situation right. It also means listening—<em>really listening</em>—to your customers and looking for the lesson in their feedback. Help your customers regain confidence in your company by taking control of the situation, making it right, and preventing future problems.</p>
<p>View feedback as a gift, not a burden.  Don’t discourage your customers from sharing how they feel, or offering their tips for improvement. And certainly never approach customer feedback the way <a href="http://www.cnn.com/2014/08/04/travel/bad-hotel-review-fine-backlash/">this hotel</a> did.</p>
<h2><strong>3. Customer service is a tough job.</strong></h2>
<p>Remember the <a href="https://www.thedijuliusgroup.com/blog/2014/taco-bell-employee-shoots-unhappy-customer-frontier-pilot-buys-pizzas-for-all-passengers/646/">fast food employee</a> who in a fit of frustration <em>shot</em> a customer? Thankfully the customer was okay, but how did the situation escalate to that point?</p>
<p>Dealing with angry customers isn’t pleasant or easy. And while it’s never acceptable for an agent or employee to behave unprofessionally, it’s important to acknowledge the challenging nature of customer interactions. It’s impossible to prevent a problem if you don’t admit it exists. Show your employees that you know how tough their job is, and take steps to alleviate some of the stress.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-2415 size-full" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/erica-blog-post-2.png" alt="customer service failures" width="491" height="239" /></p>
<p>Offer on-site yoga classes. Dedicate a room for quiet meditation. Give your agents stress balls, or adult coloring books for breaks.</p>
<p>More importantly, arm your employees with the training and tools needed to tackle difficult situations. Consider difficult customer interactions as learning moments. Bring recordings or transcripts of heated exchanges to group training sessions, and ask team members how they’d respond in a similar situation.  Role play. Help agents prepare for the worst, and they’ll feel more comfortable and confident when a difficult call comes their way.</p>
<h2><strong>4. Don’t forget the human touch.</strong></h2>
<p>An expectation of 24/7 service, in a customer’s language and channel of choice is no longer uncommon. To meet these rising expectations, many companies have relied on automation to close the gap. While there are certainly instances when automation can be effective, remember that customer service is still a people business. Forgetting the human touch causes your company to feel unauthentic, and that can lead to less loyal customers. This is especially true in service channels such as social media that are supposed to be (you guessed it) <em>social</em>.</p>
<p>Case in point: a few months ago, a well-known telecommunications provider crashed ICMI’s weekly Twitter chat.  Awesome, right? Encouraging to witness a respected brand listening to their customers on social media, huh? Not exactly. It quickly became glaringly obvious that we were dealing with bots—and not the intelligent type.  You can read more about the entire exchange by checking out this <a href="http://www.toistersolutions.com/blog/2015/10/28/automation-fail-how-attcares-stumbled-into-a-tweet-chat">blog post by Jeff Toister</a>.  Spoiler alert: this company has become a running joke in the <a href="http://www.icmi.com/forums/forum1005-icmichat-forum.aspx">#ICMIchat community</a>, and serves as a prime example of how <em>not</em> to handle automated customer service.</p>
<h2><strong>5. Give your agents the freedom to make things right.</strong></h2>
<p>Just like scripts, policies can be used as a helpful guide for serving customers. Setting expectations makes the experience more positive for both customers and agents. But remember there are times when every rule must be broken.  Rigid policies can often make an employee’s job even harder, so it’s critical to empower your employees. Give them the freedom to exercise common sense and bend the rules when needed.</p>
<p>For example, imagine you work in a hotel. A distressed (and naked) customer shows up at the front desk. He’s been locked out of his room and needs help getting back in. You ask for his ID, but it’s in his room (which he’s locked out of). According to hotel policy, you’re only allowed to issue a new key to customers who are able to show photo identification. How would you handle this situation? This happened several months ago, and due to the <a href="http://news.yahoo.com/video/naked-guy-gets-locked-hotel-150253974.html">strict hotel policy</a> the employee wasn’t able to help the guest in the best way possible.</p>
<p>Rules and guidelines are valuable, yes.  But teaching your employees how to determine when to break the rules is even more valuable. Don’t let policies leave your customers feeling like a number instead of a valued guest.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-2416 size-full" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/erica-blog-post-3.png" alt="customer service failures" width="493" height="175" /></p>
<p>Has your business learned any lessons from customer service gone wrong? Have you as a customer been on the receiving end of a customer service hall of shame moment? Share your experiences in the comments below! Let’s all remember to embrace the insight that comes from service failures!</p>
<h2><strong>About the Author</strong></h2>
<p>Erica Strother Marois is the Community Specialist at <a href="http://www.icmi.com">ICMI</a>. In her role at ICMI she hosts and plans the weekly #ICMIchat twitter chat, manages a robust network of contact center writers and speakers, and produces the weekly <em>Contact Center Insider Newsletter</em>. Erica is a connecter of people, and loves being a part of the contact center community.</p>
<p>Connect with Erica:  Twitter: <a href="https://twitter.com/ens0204">@ens0204 </a> |  LinkedIn: <a href="http://linkd.in/16kW2cj">http://linkd.in/16kW2cj</a>  | Google+: <a href="http://bit.ly/1zkp9YS">http://bit.ly/1zkp9YS</a>   | Email: <a href="mailto:estrother@icmi.com">estrother@icmi.com</a></p>
<p>Image of boy facepalm by <a href="https://pixabay.com/en/boy-facepalm-child-youth-666803/">mintchipdesigns</a>. CC0 license. Edited.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/5-lessons-learned-from-customer-service-failures/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Tried To Text Domino&#8217;s for Pizza And Had a Horrible Customer Experience</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/i-tried-to-text-dominos-for-pizza-and-had-a-horrible-customer-experience/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/i-tried-to-text-dominos-for-pizza-and-had-a-horrible-customer-experience/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Big Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Communication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Satisfaction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gripes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Use Cases]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/i-tried-to-text-dominos-for-pizza-and-had-a-horrible-customer-experience/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tired of ordering pizza over the phone? Domino’s understands—that’s why they’ve launched <a href="anyware.dominos.com">AnyWare</a>, letting you “order your favorite oven-baked goodness on your favorite devices.”</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’m not going to lie—this is a pretty awesome use case (in theory). With AnyWare, you can text, tweet and even use your Smart TV to order pizza and more, and all you have to do is send a pizza emoji.</span></p>
<p><span id="more-7253"></span></p>
<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/D1SrOjuBSEU" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>Easy as (pizza) pie, right?</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Not so much, which kinda sucks because I was really excited by the prospect of being able to text to order a pizza. (No really, I was).</span></p>
<p><a href="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-text-1.png"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-1743 size-medium" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-text-1-264x300.png" alt="dominos text 1" width="264" height="300" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">See, the key to ordering pizza from Domino’s on any of your smart devices lies in creating a Pizza Profile apparently, where you have to input your name, email address, and phone number to get your hands on that slice of cheese. By creating an account, you’re able to Easy Order based off of past purchases and skip entering your personal payment information every time.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’re all about text messaging and effortless service at OneReach, so this seemed like a great use case to test out. Pizza + texting = success, right?!?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Excited with the thought of pizza for lunch, and with my stomach growling, I went off to create my Pizza Profile. However, hitting the site should have been my first clue as to what I was about to experience because apparently you have to divulge your deepest, darkest secrets to order a pizza. After logging in to enable text ordering, I was presented with a whole lot of pizza legalese asking for my consent.</span></p>
<p><strong><strong><a href="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos1.png"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1744" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos1-546x331.png" alt="dominos1" width="546" height="331" /></a></strong></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I entered my phone number and saved my settings. Next, I had to double opt-in to confirm that I did, in fact, want to order pizza.  </span></p>
<p><strong><strong><a href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/dominos-text-2.png"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-1741 size-medium" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-text-2-e1440719073409-289x300.png" alt="dominos text 2" width="289" height="300" /></a></strong></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Then, I had to set up an Easy Order (oh, how I wish it had been) so the system knew what to query. </span></p>
<p><strong><strong><a href="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-double-optin.png"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-1745 size-large" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-double-optin-546x255.png" alt="dominos double optin" width="546" height="255" /></a></strong></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Almost done? I wish! The pop-up told me I had to place my order </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">online</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> before I could use text messaging. Honestly, I kind of got the feeling this was a cash grab to get everyone to order way more pizzas than they need, all for supposed convenience’s sake.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I was at a loss. I didn’t even know </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">where </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">to place my Easy Order. Luckily, my phone came to my rescue when I opted in to receive messages and I could start placing my Easy Order.</span></p>
<p><a href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/dominos-text-3.png"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-1746 size-medium" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-text-3-e1440719007201-269x300.png" alt="dominos text 3" width="269" height="300" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Just kidding&#8211;I had to go back online </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">again</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. So far, not so easy.</span></p>
<p><a href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/dominos-text-4.png"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-1747 size-medium" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-text-4-e1440719030547-289x300.png" alt="dominos text 4" width="289" height="300" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">No, I don’t want to </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">cheese it up</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">—I just want to order my damn pizza over text message.</span></p>
<p><strong><strong><a href="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-cheese-it-up.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1748" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-cheese-it-up.png" alt="dominos cheese it up" width="457" height="291" /></a></strong></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">C’mon, this is supposed to be easy! I just want to order my pizza over text message!!</span></p>
<p><strong><strong><a href="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-chocolate.png"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1749" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-chocolate-546x291.png" alt="dominos chocolate" width="546" height="291" /></a></strong></strong></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Finally</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, on the payment page, I found what I was looking for.</span></p>
<p><strong><strong><a href="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-easy-order.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1750" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-easy-order.png" alt="dominos easy order" width="318" height="142" /></a></strong></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Awesome. Easy Order saved. Right? Wrong. Even though I submitted my order (14” with pepperoni and mushrooms), I still had no Easy Order to show for it. At this point, I was getting really frustrated (and hungry).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Not to be deterred, I tried once again to order over text, but because I didn’t save my credit card information, I couldn’t order. Because guess what—the only way to update your payment method is to MAKE ANOTHER PAYMENT.</span></p>
<p><strong><strong><a href="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-credit-card-2.png"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1751" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-credit-card-2-546x73.png" alt="dominos credit card 2" width="546" height="73" /></a></strong></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Seriously. Yeah.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Still aiming for my end goal of ordering pizza over text message, I went back <em>online</em> to order something cheap (3 20 oz. sodas) to re-enter my payment information. And when I went back to my phone and texted my little pizza emoji, guess what? Still didn’t work, because life sucks sometimes.</span></p>
<p><a href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/dominos-text-5.png"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-1752 size-medium" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-text-5-e1440718690657-289x300.png" alt="dominos text 5" width="289" height="300" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Luckily, the delivery guy was nice enough to deliver my two orders together, and when I asked if my online credit card payment went through (because according to the texts, it wasn’t valid), he showed me the receipt, where it clearly did.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In summary, not only was I </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">not</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> able to order over text message, but I had a heck of a time even trying to order online.</span></p>
<p>The goal of this article is not to bash Domino’s&#8211;they should be applauded for even attempting to deploy a text-to-order service. In addition, I’m assuming that once I got my Easy Order set up, it would have been as easy to order as advertised instead of what I went through.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1753" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1753" style="width: 546px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-happy.png"><img class="size-large wp-image-1753" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-happy-546x287.png" alt="This is definitely not how I felt after trying to order. Photo from Domino&quot;sss" width="546" height="287" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1753" class="wp-caption-text">This is definitely NOT how I felt after trying to order. Photo from Domino&#8217;s AnyWare video.</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Still, what’s ultimately lacking from the Domino’s AnyWare experience is the “anywhere” aspect of it. Domino’s tried and failed to create a seamless omnichannel experience that lets you order pizza whenever, wherever, and however you want. It relied too heavily on the Web to enable an experience that should have taken place largely on other channels.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A true omnichannel experience would have seamlessly transferred customers from channel to channel (ie a link to a secure payment page for ordering), rather than forcing them back to the Web to do the very thing they should have been able to do by texting or tweeting: order pizza.</span></p>
<h1><b>Text Domino’s 2.0</b></h1>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Even though I didn’t get my pizza over text message, I still wanted to see if there was a better way to design this whole text debacle. Because even though it didn’t work, it should have worked. And it can work.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here’s how it should have been done (and can be done). Domino’s, feel free to use this model PUH-LEESE!</span></p>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">First, I would text into Domino’s, without needing a Pizza Profile. That was the one part of the user experience that continuously failed me, </span><a href="http://www.eater.com/2015/5/20/8631373/i-ordered-dominos-pizza-emoji-it-took-three-hours-twitter"><span style="font-weight: 400;">and I’m not</span></a> <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2015/05/20/dominos-tweet-to-order-system-isnt-as-great-as-it-sounds/#.v3rtkt:wfb2"><span style="font-weight: 400;">the only one</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Had I not been so committed to seeing this through, I would have bailed with many profanities following and ordered from Papa John’s.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">I would receive a text message asking if I’d like to place my usual order (not Easy Order, because that sure as heck wasn’t easy), or if I’d like to place a new one.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The system would already know my address and billing information, so I wouldn’t have to input that information online, taking me out of my mobile experience. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’d confirm that I’d like the pizza delivered to my regular address.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The system would then ask me if I’d like to pay with the card I already have on file.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’d confirm, and then I’d get a message that my pizza was on my way.</span></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Easy as that.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But, why tell you when I can show you? Here’s how it would look&#8230;</span></p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-2388 aligncenter" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-texting2.png" alt="text dominos" width="301" height="573" /></p>
<p>Want to try a great text-to-order experience for yourself? <strong>Text “PIZZA” to 70700.</strong> Note&#8211;you won’t actually be ordering pizza, and there are no integrations to find the nearest Domino’s or to pay for pizza. Still, it’s an example of what a smart ordering experience could be (and should have been) like.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Enjoy!</span></p>
<p><strong>To learn more about adding text to your business (the right way), <a style="font-weight: bold;" href="http://onereach.com/resources/10-things-about-text">download our whitepaper here</a>, or shoot us a text at 303-974-7351. We&#8217;re always happy to chat.</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://www.kawankumagz.com/articleFoto/Hal-Hal_yang_Kita_Rasakan_Saat_Mengirim_Chat_ke_Gebetan_(Bagian_1).jpg">Photo credit</a>. Edited.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/i-tried-to-text-dominos-for-pizza-and-had-a-horrible-customer-experience/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 Challenges of SMS Marketing</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/3-challenges-of-sms-marketing/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/3-challenges-of-sms-marketing/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gripes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/3-challenges-of-sms-marketing/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>How many marketing messages do you think you see each day? 100? 500?</p>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="http://www.marketing-made-simple.com/articles/promotional-clutter.htm#.VFf7e_nF9lx">Try 5,000.</a></p>
<p dir="ltr">Now how would you feel if some of those 5,000 messages were delivered directly into your pocket over text? It would be pretty annoying, right?</p>
<p dir="ltr"><span id="more-7172"></span>According to a study conducted by<a href="http://www.marketing-made-simple.com/articles/promotional-clutter.htm#.VFf7e_nF9lx"> Yankelovich Consumer Research</a> (no relation to Weird Al), the average American sees 10 times as many ads as they did in the 1970s. The study also found that over 60% of people feel advertising and marketing are out of control.</p>
<p dir="ltr">SMS marketing is powerful, but with great power comes great responsibility. Here are three challenges of SMS marketing you should think about.</p>
<h2 dir="ltr">It’s not as individualized</h2>
<p dir="ltr">Most businesses use short codes for SMS marketing: these are 5-6 digit numbers designed to manage a huge amount of incoming and outgoing traffic. The downside to sending out a gajillion text messages is that you lose some of the personal connection you get from 1-to-1 text messages. According to research by DemandGen, <a href="http://blog.hubspot.com/marketing/data-personalize-marketing-li">40% of consumers</a> more likely to buy from retailers who personalize their communications across channels.</p>
<h2 dir="ltr">It’s not conversational</h2>
<p dir="ltr">A lot of businesses use texting to keep in touch with their customers. While this is a great way to stay top-of-mind, it’s not a great way to create a dialogue. Without giving customers the chance to respond (other than in the form of a keyword), you’re basically just yelling at them to present this digital coupon for 20% off your next purchase. This is bad because instead of fostering a relationship and encouraging conversation, you’re overwhelming them with solely your content without getting any feedback. Having a reply strategy that supports automated or live responses will help facilitate the conversation that SMS marketing lacks.</p>
<h2 dir="ltr">It’s strictly regulated</h2>
<p dir="ltr">Because of the near-unlimited sending power that comes with short codes, there are a lot of rules restricting how it can be used. For example, companies can only send marketing messages to those who have opted in, meaning they have to get permission from the user to send messages in the future. This rule is there for a reason: companies like<a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/papa-johns-faces-lawsuit-over-texts-2012-11"> Papa John’s</a> have overstepped their bounds in the past, angering customers and finding themselves facing a $250 million lawsuit. If you’re worried about managing effective opt-in/opt-out, it might be time to start letting your customers text your company. Then, there’s no question about whether or not they’re cool with texting your brand.</p>
<h2 dir="ltr">Conclusion</h2>
<p dir="ltr">If you do decide to use SMS marketing, keep these limitations in mind. You want your business to be noticed, but not for the wrong reasons and you want to be respectful not only of your customers but also the expectations around the channel you’re using. Don’t text people if they can’t text you.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em>To learn more about text-enabling your business, professionally designed or do-it-yourself, visit <a href="http://onereach.com">onereach.com</a>.</em></p>
<p>Photo by Flickr user <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/markusgoller/9589188125">Markus Goller</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/3-challenges-of-sms-marketing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>OneReach Shares Customer Service Horror Stories</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/onereach-shares-customer-service-horror-stories/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/onereach-shares-customer-service-horror-stories/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Customer Experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gripes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IVR]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/onereach-shares-customer-service-horror-stories/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">What’s scarier for businesses than a one-eyed zombie clown lumbering at you with a chainsaw?</p>
<p dir="ltr">The thought of losing $41 billion a year.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><span id="more-7170"></span>That&#8217;s right: poor customer service costs U.S. businesses over <a href="http://www.callcentrehelper.com/the-true-cost-of-poor-customer-service-53029.htm">$40 billion dollars each year</a>. Top frustrations include unhelpful staff, being put on hold, being passed around to multiple agents and the agents’ lack of knowledge. In fact, over 50% of people are so frustrated at the thought of calling a business that they will switch to a competitor without trying to solve the problem.</p>
<p>To get into the Halloween spirit, we thought we’d share the most hauntingly horrific customer service horror stories we’ve had on the phone. Read on&#8230;if you dare!</p>
<h2>The Case of the Disappearing Furniture</h2>
<p dir="ltr">I bought a sectional from a home furniture store that was to be delivered to a new townhouse the week I was moving in. The sales person assured me it would be there on a specific day between 11 a.m. and 3 p.m. It didn&#8217;t show up on that day so I called the store where I purchased it. The sales person wasn&#8217;t in so they gave me the number of their customer support. They were unable to to locate it. I was told it shipped from California, but that was all they knew and they would get in touch when it arrived in Denver.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Meanwhile, my living room is now composed of camp chairs of various colors and sizes. Three days go by and I call them only to be told, &#8220;Oh yeah, it&#8217;s in Denver at a warehouse, but we don&#8217;t know where or when they can deliver it.” I ask for the number of the warehouse and am told they are not allowed to give it out.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Finally, I ask for a manager and am told they are in a meeting. I am promised that it will be on a delivery truck in the morning. They next day nothing arrives and I call back. Same story from them. I threaten to just return it and go somewhere else and miraculously they locate it and deliver it the next day. The delivery men scratch the floor and are unapologetic.</p>
<p dir="ltr">I wrote an email to the company explaining the experience. Still haven&#8217;t heard back. &#8211;Grant</p>
<h2>Disembodied Voices</h2>
<p>I haven&#8217;t called them personally, but I&#8217;ve heard of a consumer goods company with hold times between 4-7 hours long. Seriously. People really want to buy their product. During the hold, they play a series of voice recordings. This sucks since you can’t just put it on speaker and hope to notice when a real voice comes on. &#8211;Kevin</p>
<h2>The Haunted Email Account</h2>
<p>I called into my email provider&#8217;s customer service when I noticed my emails were in British time and my news page was all British news. I was worried that someone had maybe tried to hack into my account. The first guy I reached helped me try and change my computer settings; when that didn&#8217;t work, he transferred me to someone else. After suggesting the same solution the first guy had, he told me he could externally reboot my email account and then monitor my computer remotely for any changes if I paid $129. I denied wanting this service several times after he kept pitching it, and eventually got so frustrated that I hung up. I asked one of my coworkers for help and he got since he had experienced the problem too, he helped me figure it out in under a minute. &#8211;Gigi</p>
<h2>The IVR Road to Nowhere</h2>
<p>I have called into a pharmacy and been placed on hold, told I was the next customer in line, then given a repetitive voice message telling me how much I was valued. After 10 minutes, the system drops the call. This went on 4 times before someone finally picked up. I explained my frustration with experience and was told that they implemented a new phone system that was acting weird (not the case). This still happens months later. No sympathy from the people on the other end just excuses. &#8211;Grant</p>
<p>Photo by Flickr user <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/16005131@N08/5572381045">Saleh Almoqaibel</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/onereach-shares-customer-service-horror-stories/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>These Overused IVR Phrases Have Got to Go</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/these-overused-ivr-phrases-have-got-to-go/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/these-overused-ivr-phrases-have-got-to-go/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gripes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IVR]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/these-overused-ivr-phrases-have-got-to-go/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">Almost every IVR contains one of these frustrating phrases:</p>
<ul>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr"><em>“Please listen carefully, as our menu has changed.”</em></p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr"><em>“We are currently assisting other customers. Your call will be answered in the order in which it was received.”</em></p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr"><em>“You can find information on our website at…”</em></p>
</li>
</ul>
<p dir="ltr">When working with an <a href="http://blog.talkdesk.com/what-is-an-ivr-and-6-benefits-of-using-one">integrated voice response (IVR) system</a>, there are a number of things you have to take into consideration. Although IVR lets companies handle multiple customers at once, the prompts can become redundant, driving customers to hang up or bypass the menu altogether.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><span id="more-7160"></span>Customer engagement is crucial in retaining and attracting customers that will continue to do business. Being proactive <a href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/?p=34">in reading your customers’ minds</a> is key. Here are a few simple solutions that will help remove these overused IVR phrases from your system for good:</p>
<h3 dir="ltr">“Please listen carefully, as our menu has changed.”</h3>
<p dir="ltr">How many times have customers heard this? Too many. Over <a href="http://onereachcontactcenter.com/high-demand-for-customer-service-via-text-message/">80% of consumers</a> think it’s frustrating to be tied to a phone or computer to wait for customer service help; offering alternatives like text chat lets customers navigate an IVR system in a way that is convenient for them. Another solution would be to place more amicable options earlier in the menu to avoid using this phrase at all.</p>
<h3 dir="ltr">“We are currently assisting other customers. Your call will be answered in the order in which it was received.”</h3>
<p dir="ltr">Most systems now instantaneously alert the customer to their number in line and how long their wait will be. Recently, more and more companies have been offering callback options so customers don’t have to wait on hold. However,<a href="http://onereachcontactcenter.com/high-demand-for-customer-service-via-text-message/"> 44% of consumers</a> with texting capabilities would prefer to press a button to initiate a text conversation immediately, rather than waiting on hold to speak with an agent. For companies that are interested in increasing customer satisfaction, integrating texting into your channel mix can be a great way to honor customer preference while freeing up customer service representatives.</p>
<h3 dir="ltr">“You can find information on our website at…”</h3>
<p dir="ltr">Most companies have websites in place and customers are already aware of that. While this kind of prompt is well-intentioned, aimed at decreasing the number of incoming calls and providing more self-service, it isn’t necessary here&#8211;they’re calling in for a reason. If your prompts are filled with self-service options that answer additional questions, your customers will be well-informed and won’t have to turn to another channel.</p>
<h3 dir="ltr">Getting rid of these annoying prompts</h3>
<p dir="ltr">Employing these methods will not only help ban these phrases from your IVR system, but will add efficiency to your processes. Anticipating customer needs and questions prior to them having to look for the information will help your brand and retain customer loyalty. Capitalizing on the advantages of an IVR system will not only enhance the user experience, but improve the call center structure.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em>To learn more about custom IVR, professionally designed or do-it-yourself, visit <a href="onereach.com">onereach.com</a>.</em></p>
<p dir="ltr">
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/these-overused-ivr-phrases-have-got-to-go/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Everyone Hates Phone Trees</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/everyone-hates-phone-trees/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/everyone-hates-phone-trees/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gripes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/everyone-hates-phone-trees/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>&#8220;I really appreciate Company X&#8217;s large confusing phone tree!&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8211; said no one ever.</p></blockquote>
<p>We all know the drill &#8211; we need something from Company X, but Company X can&#8217;t afford to staff an army to answer phones, so they wave the magic &#8220;phone tree&#8221; wand, spin us in a few circles, and hope that somehow we will be happy with that.</p>
<p>For me this translates into one single mode of operation when dealing with companies:<strong> try to avoid &#8211; <span style="text-decoration: underline;">at all costs</span> &#8211; having to call them</strong>. I don&#8217;t want to listen to their menus. I don&#8217;t want to be put on hold. I don&#8217;t want to enter my account information multiple times because your magic phone tree isn&#8217;t powerful enough to remember it.</p>
<p>The funny part to me is that the money-saving phone tree systems typically cost hundreds of thousands of dollars. I didn&#8217;t go to &#8220;Enterprise Business School&#8221;, but I&#8217;m pretty sure spending that much money to irritate your customers is bad for business. Especially when there are significantly cheaper better options available.</p>
<p>Not every automated phone system is terrible. I once called Comcast and was pleasantly surprised to hear something like the following (I&#8217;m paraphrasing here):</p>
<p>&#8220;Hi Jeremy, thanks for calling customer support. We&#8217;re pretty busy right now, so would you like us to call you back when someone&#8217;s available?&#8221;</p>
<p>Yes, yes, a thousand times yes! They know who I am without me entering some 20 digit account number! They know I want to talk to someone! They don&#8217;t want to waste my time!</p>
<p>Of course, this kind of &#8220;custom&#8221; solution costs a fortune and requires an entire team of consultants and developers, right? <strong>Nope</strong>. There are solutions out there, including <a href="http://www.onereach.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">OneReach</a>, that are affordable and can be set up by anyone with basic computer skills.</p>
<p>Consider this your customer support PSA: don&#8217;t go chasing after those &#8220;cost effective&#8221; phone tree systems just so you can give your customer&#8217;s the run-around. Find a better solution, one that treats customers like <em>people</em>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/everyone-hates-phone-trees/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Elitch&#8217;s Phone Tree of Doom</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/elitchs-phone-tree-of-doom/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/elitchs-phone-tree-of-doom/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gripes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/elitchs-phone-tree-of-doom/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Had this experience yesterday: my wife and I had free tickets for our kids to go to Elitch Garden&#8217;s amusement park, but didn&#8217;t know if we could use them on a holiday. My wife called them up and got their automated voice system.</p>
<p>Now she needed an actual person to talk to, but as is par for the course, this phone tree was trying to prevent her getting one easily. And yep, they succeeded in that goal.</p>
<p>&#8220;<em>Press 0 if you&#8217;d like to speak to an operator.</em>&#8221; She did, heard a beep, then got disconnected. She tried this five more times, and each time the system hung up on her.</p>
<p>We didn&#8217;t want to make the 30-minute drive with three hyped-up kids only to find out at the gates that our tickets weren&#8217;t valid, so she kept calling. At this point, the phone number stopped working altogether: &#8220;<em>We&#8217;re sorry, we cannot connect you to that number&#8230;</em>&#8221; My guess is that their phone system wasn&#8217;t able to handle the holiday call volume.</p>
<p><strong>Double-fail</strong>. Sorry, but at this point, I was willing to change all our plans just because I couldn&#8217;t talk to someone on their end. Hopefully someone from Elitch Gardens will read this and get a phone system that doesn&#8217;t lose them business.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/elitchs-phone-tree-of-doom/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
