<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>SMB &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<atom:link href="https://onereach.ai/category/smb/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<description>Intelligently Automate Your Company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 11:39:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/cropped-OR-ICON-GOLD-W-DOTS-Larger-Background-02-32x32.png</url>
	<title>SMB &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How Cross-Functional Support Benefits Your Business</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/how-cross-functional-support-benefits-your-business/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/how-cross-functional-support-benefits-your-business/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Benefits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SMB]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech Support]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/how-cross-functional-support-benefits-your-business/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Startups can be crazy, exciting places to work. While it can often feel like there are more balls in the air than hands to catch them, somehow everything ends up getting done. This is because, many times in startups, people from one department jump into another department to tackle the tasks at hand.</p>
<p>The collaborative, hands-on nature of startups is a great example of cross-functionality at work. <a href="http://searchcio.techtarget.com/definition/crossfunctional">Cross-functional teams</a> combine the strengths and talents of different individuals to reach a common goal. Applied to customer service, cross-functional support means uniting individuals from several different departments (marketing, sales, operations, etc.) to figure out how to provide the best service possible to customers.</p>
<h2><span id="more-7343"></span><strong>How cross-functional support can benefit your company</strong></h2>
<p>Teamwork is an essential part of any startup or established company’s success, but working as a team to meet the needs of a customer is an entirely separate challenge. Cross-functional teams, however, are uniquely equipped to meet that challenge by using their respective skills to collaborate on a customer’s problem.</p>
<p>Venture capitalist <a href="http://tomtunguz.com/churn/">Tomasz Tunguz</a> sums up his thoughts on collaboration:</p>
<blockquote><p>The customer success team is on the front lines with customers passing feedback to product and marketing. Customer success provides a check on the sales team, ensuring the right customers are prioritized and closed.</p></blockquote>
<p>The best way to understand a product is to use it, so what better way for marketers to learn what prospects want than to provide customer support for that product every once in awhile? The same goes for product teams, executives, etc.</p>
<p>Cross-functionality also allows companies to create more personal, customer-centric interactions thanks to multi-departmental insight. Take what Kleiner Perkins partners Ted Schlein and Creighton Hicks recently said about <a href="http://www.kpcb.com/blog/the-magic-of-customer-empathy">customer centricity</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>Understanding how users interact with your product is essential to successful product development. It benefits not only design and production, but also marketing, selling and support.</p></blockquote>
<p>This type of collaboration also enables team members to learn new skills and create useful customer service content across departments. For example, if a cross-functional meeting determines that customers have been having trouble using a new product, marketing can create product-specific collateral that sales can later use. Operations can also check in to make sure the new product is working correctly. A combined knowledge of the customer means each department can do their job better. They can also pool resources from across departments (equipment, personnel, etc.) to meet the task at hand.</p>
<p>Cross-functional support can also boost company creativity and allow different departments to bond over a shared purpose – customer success. Each team member can bring their respective strengths and insights to the group to figure out how to improve the customer experience and address problems quickly and efficiently. This also creates a sense of synergy that may not have been there before. Employees from different departments can work together to identify service problems or opportunities that might not have been apparent had the employees not worked together. Once this collaborative group has been established, they can continue innovating and sharing to drive customer service change.</p>
<h2><strong>Using collaboration to optimize and enhance the customer journey</strong></h2>
<p>By collaborating to solve problems encountered throughout the entire customer journey, companies can create more targeted support for each stage. In turn, these hyper-focused interactions will create loyalty, as venture capitalist <a href="http://www.bvp.com/blog/customer-loyalty-magic">Ethan Kurzweil</a> has said. In fact, research has shown that <a href="http://www.thewisemarketer.com/briefs/archive.asp?action=read&amp;bid=4489">over 90% of customers</a> who have an effortless service experience with companies will buy from that company again.</p>
<p>Cross-functional teams can create user personas to identify pain points and probable actions taken throughout their journey, then decide what needs must be addressed. That’s because as the customer passes through each stage of the customer journey, each department has hands-on experience assessing their wants and needs and can pass those insights along to the larger team. When cross-functional teams do come together to reach a goal (in this case providing better service), they combine their knowledge to create a cohesive customer service plan.</p>
<p>Cross-functional support is a great way for each department to get firsthand customer feedback as well as offer exceptional customer service experiences. By prioritizing customer success, companies of all size can benefit from loyal customers and well-rounded teams.</p>
<p><strong>Like what you&#8217;ve read here? Check out our ebook on how to <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/omnichannel-seamless-experience">provide seamless omnichannel customer support</a>.</strong></p>
<p><em><a href="http://www.desk.com/blog/cross-functional-support-why-its-good-for-your-company/">This post originally appeared on Desk.com</a>.</em></p>
<p>Photo from <a href="http://startupstockphotos.com/">Startup Stock Photos</a>. Edited.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/how-cross-functional-support-benefits-your-business/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Desk.com: Small Businesses Using Big Tools</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/desk-com-small-businesses-using-big-tools/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/desk-com-small-businesses-using-big-tools/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Customer Experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SMB]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/desk-com-small-businesses-using-big-tools/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Customer service is a strategic advantage, especially for small organizations who rely on word of mouth to grow their business. But having a strategy is not enough- it’s important to use tools that empower every employee to provide customers with the service they deserve.</p>
<p><span id="more-7159"></span>Tools like Desk.com have been great about letting every employee participate in the customer service process.Acquired by Salesforce in 2011, Desk offers multiple customer support methods.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Self-help pages</strong>—customers can get answers to their FAQs on a custom support center microsite</li>
<li><strong>Giving customers access</strong>—customer can contact service agents through a customizable contact form</li>
<li><strong>Ticket tracking</strong>—agents can categorize cases by submission time, type of problem, customer status, etc.</li>
<li><strong>Showing customer their needs are being taken seriously</strong>—companies can add a Q&amp;A section to their site, allowing agents to moderate conversations and answer questions directly</li>
</ul>
<p>But what about the next step? What does the future look like?</p>
<p>Not too different from the present, as it turns out.</p>
<h1>Desk.com: The Future Is Here</h1>
<p>Thanks to our partnership with companies like Desk.com, OneReach is bringing big contact center technology to the small business. Your business can now respond to multiple customers at once, no matter what channel they’re using. By integrating with existing customer databases, small businesses can draw on personalized information in live or automated communications.</p>
<p>Some of the features a system like OneReach offer are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Screen pops with relevant customer information</li>
<li>New case creation for each customer call</li>
<li>Log call notes</li>
<li>Ability to text or call for support</li>
</ul>
<p>Companies of any size can take advantage of tools like OneReach’s without breaking the bank.</p>
<h1>Improving The Customer Experience</h1>
<p>At the end of the day, businesses of all sizes can benefit from the basics by:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Making their customers feel known.</strong> According to an Accenture survey, 89% of customers are frustrated having to repeat their issue to multiple agents. Eliminate customer angst using data to create context. If a customer calls in in the future, the system should remember what their previous call was about, what channel it came in on, what agent they spoke with, and customize the interaction based on that. Companies should also centralize communications, sending customer data collected on any channel to one major hub like the cloud.</li>
<li><strong>Being responsive.</strong> According to a Harris Interactive survey, 75% of customers think it takes too long to get in touch with a live agent. Companies can set up automated flows across channels to respond to customers when no agents are online, ensuring the customer can still get their problem solved. Businesses should also provide customers with the option to talk to an agent on any channel, such as pivoting to a live text chat instead of waiting on hold.</li>
<li><strong>Showing gratitude.</strong> Customers are taking time out of their day to interact with your company, so be sure to thank them for it. (Don’t overdo this, though, or it’ll start coming across as insincere). However, if a customer has been waiting on hold for a long time, that’s when it’s acceptable to thank them for their patience.</li>
<li><strong>Surprising them.</strong> A lot of customers see customer service as a tedious process; it’s your job to change that perception. Even just introducing a new channel can shake things up: “You mean I can just text you instead of going through a phone tree or waiting on hold?” Review your support channels on a regular basis to see how they can be made even better; your customers will thank you for it.</li>
</ul>
<p>By introducing bigger and better communications tools, companies can provide consistently great communication that customers will stop and take notice of.</p>
<p><em>To learn more about OneReach’s integrations with systems like Desk.com, visit <a href="onereach.com">onereach.com</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/desk-com-small-businesses-using-big-tools/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
