<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>customer service &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<atom:link href="https://onereach.ai/tag/customer-service/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<description>Intelligently Automate Your Company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 11:39:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/cropped-OR-ICON-GOLD-W-DOTS-Larger-Background-02-32x32.png</url>
	<title>customer service &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Sharing the Love:  Amy Krouse Rosenthal and the Emerging Connection between Author and Reader</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/sharing-the-love-amy-krouse-rosenthal-and-the-emerging-connection-between-author-and-reader/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/sharing-the-love-amy-krouse-rosenthal-and-the-emerging-connection-between-author-and-reader/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Satisfaction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI in publishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer service]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/sharing-the-love-amy-krouse-rosenthal-and-the-emerging-connection-between-author-and-reader/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Throughout much of history, authors have maintained a distance from readers, their experiences separated by both time and place. As novelist Paolo Coelho noted, writing is “a solitary experience.” The work of the author was often created in isolation—seemingly forged in the rarified air of their literary mountain before being handed down to the waiting masses.</p>
<p>Now, not so much.</p>
<p>Modern writers are encouraged to engage with their readers and, thanks to technology, have numerous possible channels to choose from. This makes the modern author more a reachable human, and less a remote mystic.</p>
<p>This may seem grievous to the lone wolf author who would prefer to remain isolated and mysterious. But the reality in our connected world is that readers expect a level of access to authors, and success in the literary world depends on it. In his editorial piece “<a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/daviddisalvo/2012/05/10/the-aloof-author-is-dead-long-live-the-writer/#48b4eb3e2649" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Aloof Author Is Dead, Long Live the Writer</a>,” David DiSalvo of Forbes Magazine writes:</p>
<p>Technology has riddled the barriers between authors and readers full of holes. Ignoring the multiple ways readers can interface with writers isn’t an option — but more to the point, why would anyone want to ignore them? In the new economy, writers must build brands for themselves and maintain them over time. Every mode of interaction with readers offers opportunities to strengthen the brand.</p>
<p>As novelist and blogger Kate Pullinger described in her article “<a href="http://www.katepullinger.com/website_archive/index.php/blog/comments/connecting-readers-to-writers-the-only-possible-future-of-publishing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Connecting Readers to Writers: the only possible future of publishing</a>,” “(T)he only important question left, really, is how to connect writers to readers. Any publisher who isn’t addressing this directly and urgently will be in trouble soon.”</p>
<p>While blogs and eBooks have begun providing a somewhat interactive experience, printed literature has remained in the same static place it has for centuries. After all, how can the ancient medium of paper provide a modern interactive experience?</p>
<p>Enter author Amy Krouse Rosenthal.</p>
<p>Amy is bending the world of print media towards truer interactivity by partnering with OneReach to use text-based audience participation. Written in a wry, memoir style, her new book <a href="https://www.textbookamykr.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Textbook Amy Krouse Rosenthal</a> invites readers to actively join in the discussion.</p>
<p>At the beginning of the book, readers are encouraged to text “Hello” to a Chicago number (the author’s hometown). A cheery greeting comes back from the author, which sets up a relationship of sorts between author and reader.</p>
<p>At various intervals in the book, Amy prompts the reader to engage by using text inputs to the previously used number. Information either flows from the reader to the author (such as self-portraits and photos) or from the author to the reader (such as audio files of a poet reading his work). All of these inputs are then posted on the author’s website.</p>
<p>This unique immersive experience was done very intentionally. Amy Krouse Rosenthal <a href="http://www.chicagotribune.com/lifestyles/books/ct-prj-amy-krouse-rosenthal-textbook-20160803-story.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">says</a> “the text-messaging aspect of the book, at the end of the day, is about connecting with people.” This human need for connection is well-documented and has even been recently called “as fundamental as our need for food and water” by neuroscientist <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NNhk3owF7RQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Matthew Lieberman</a>.</p>
<p>We are only just beginning to see this connection between author and reader. What OneReach has done is create an interactive and immersive experience that has been lacking up until now. Future writers may be able to construct an entirely new way of providing details or even compel an interaction with their story lines. The possibilities are limited only by the author’s imagination. Consider these:</p>
<p>• Choose Your Own Adventure books. Remember those? Also known as “gamebooks,” they used to let the reader choose different endings and options as they progressed through the pages of the book. How cool would it be to adapt that in a more technologically immersive way? A reader could text their choices and receive instructions for the next step in the story.</p>
<p>• Interactive mysteries. Readers would need to solve part of the mystery before getting a text with the next clue. This would make them almost a character in the story as they help to solve the crime.</p>
<p>• Immersive talk tracks. Imagine going on the Boston walking tour and getting texts showing images of what you’re looking at, but from the colonial period. Bot technology could also be used so you could ask questions about what you’re seeing and get a real-time answer.</p>
<p>• Scavenger hunts. Thanks to the proliferation of activities like Pokemon Go and geocaching, scavenging has never been more popular. Authors can include location-specific or theme-specific clues and readers can respond with the correct answer or upload an image of the item.</p>
<p>• Personalized books. When I was a child, one of my favorite books was a personalized one, where my own name had been included in the storyline. Admittedly, it was done with old technology, and looked like someone had just clumsily fed the template through a typewriter. That didn’t matter to me. I loved the idea that I was part of the story, and felt so very important! Using texts, an author could now give prompts for names, details, and image uploads, essentially having the reader build the story as they go. At the end, readers could even get a digital or printed copy of the story they created.</p>
<p>These are just a few ideas, limited only by the imagination of writers now and in the future. As culture changes, so must the authors and publishing companies operating within it. Although really, no matter how much technology changes, people are—as always—still just earnestly searching for connection. And a writer like Amy Krouse Rosenthal gives them just that.</p>
<p>Try it for yourself and let us know what you think!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Image courtesy of www.whoisamy.com, taken by Brooke Hummer</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/sharing-the-love-amy-krouse-rosenthal-and-the-emerging-connection-between-author-and-reader/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekly Review: 5/31 Edition</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/weekly-review-5-31-edition/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/weekly-review-5-31-edition/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence in business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer service]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/weekly-review-5-31-edition/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Happy Friday! Here’s our picks for the best customer service, customer experience, bot and mobile articles of the week, in no particular order.</p>
<h2><span id="more-7434"></span></h2>
<h2><a href="http://www.cmswire.com/customer-experience/combine-ai-and-the-human-touch-for-exceptional-customer-service/">Combine AI and the Human Touch for Exceptional Customer Service</a>&#8211;<strong> by <a href="https://twitter.com/Chris_HGS">Chris Lord</a></strong></h2>
<p>Customer service has evolved a lot in the past few decades. Support interactions used to be limited to just a phone call, but now customers can reach a company over email, social media and even text message. Self-service is an option to make customers’ lives easier, but it&#8217;s not a substitute for good customer service.</p>
<h2></h2>
<h2><strong>Au<a href="http://www.1to1media.com/view.aspx?docid=35796&amp;utm_content=title&amp;utm_source=1to1weekly&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=05232016">tomate or Humanize</a>&#8211; by <a href="http://twitter.com/JudithAquino">Judith Aquino</a> </strong></h2>
<p>As technology continues to advance, machines will be able to carry out a big number of tasks normally handled by humans. Businesses should really prioritize where robots are best used vs humans who have innovated solutions.</p>
<h2><strong><a href="https://www.b2bmarketing.net/resources/blog/why-sms-your-most-powerful-b2b-marketing-tool">Why SMS is your most Powerful B2B Marketing Tool</a> by Roxanne Abercrombie </strong></h2>
<p>It&#8217;s really pretty simple, SMS is the easiest and quickest way to get your information in front of your consumer. If you&#8217;re not using text messaging in your business you might be missing one of the most valuable tools in marketing.</p>
<h2></h2>
<h2 class="alpha tweet-title"><a href="http://Nearly 1 in 4 people abandon mobile apps after only one use">Nearly 1 in 4 people abandon mobile apps after only one use</a>&#8211; by <a href="https://twitter.com/sarahintampa">Sarah Perez </a></h2>
<p class="alpha tweet-title">At OneReach, we’ve worked with many consumers who are in high demand for customer service via text messaging. As reseach shows, apps are expensive to drive adoption, not used much and deleted after one time use.</p>
<h2><strong>To learn more about providing a great customer experience across channels, <a href="https://onereach.com/resources/omnichannel-seamless-experience">download our whitepaper here</a>. </strong></h2>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/weekly-review-5-31-edition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Leading Off Customer Interactions With Positivity</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/leading-off-customer-interactions-with-positivity/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/leading-off-customer-interactions-with-positivity/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer service]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/leading-off-customer-interactions-with-positivity/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This guest post is written by Jeremy Watkin, Head of Quality at <a href="http://gofcr.com">FCR</a>.</em></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’m a huge baseball fan— a Los Angeles Angels of Anaheim fan to be exact. In baseball, the order in which the players bat is called a “lineup.” The general rule of thumb is that the first batter, or leadoff hitter, is one of the best players at getting on base— either by hit or walk. This person also tends to be one of the faster players, so when they do get on base, they can both steal bases and score on hits where the slower players wouldn’t be able to.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let’s go ahead and take this analogy and mosey on over to customer service. Imagine that our customers are pitching to us and the questions they are asking are the pitches. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another thing you should know about baseball is that most major leaguers have no problem hitting a fastball— especially if it’s right down the middle and they know it’s coming. It’s often the pitches that move around a lot, like the curveball and slider, that keep hitters off balance.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We tend to be good at answering the fastball questions from customers. After all, we are well-trained customer service experts for the product or service we support. It’s the curveballs that give us fits. Think about the questions we either don’t know the answer to or know we specifically can’t accommodate.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s in those moments that we so often take the wrong approach at the plate. We generally approach those curveballs with words like unfortunately, no, sorry, can’t, I don’t know, and a variety of other negative responses. More times than not, responding to our customers in this manner is a sure way to strike out.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When customers consistently throw their best curveballs, and they will, it’s important to have our best responses ready to go. While this is important for all customer service channels, it’s all the more important for the text-based ones like email, SMS, and social media where we may only get one chance to respond— on behalf of the entire company! Clearly this is something we should practice ahead of time.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Practice hitting the curveball (AKA answer tough questions)</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When it comes to hitting the curveball, sometimes it’s all in your approach. The approach I’ve seen (and done) over and over again is the one where we respond telling the customer we can’t do something. Hypothetically speaking, let’s say we work for a company that sells widgets and a customer asks if we can overnight ship a widget to them. Knowing full well that we don’t offer overnight shipping, the typical approach is to say something like:</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’m so sorry but unfortunately we don’t offer overnight shipping at this time. Thank you so much for contacting us. Have a nice day.</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At that point we’ve essentially struck out. The response focused on what we couldn’t do with no focus on what we could do. Whether the customer states it or not, they are forced to either wait or take their business elsewhere.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Like a professional hitter, let’s change our approach and see if we can hit the curveball this next time. Here’s a response that focuses on what we can do for the customer:</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Thank you so much for your interest in our widgets! I&#8217;ve provided a few of my personal favorites below as you search for your favorite. </span></i></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">In regards to our shipping, we&#8217;ve found that our order fulfillment time is so quick that customers often receive their items faster than our estimates. While we don&#8217;t specifically offer overnight shipping, let me know if you have any flexibility on the date you need to receive this by. I want to get a fresh, new widget out to you and will do what I can to make that happen as soon as possible.</span></i></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Play by Play</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Do you see what I did there on my second response? Like a good baseball analyst, let’s break it down:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><b><b>Show Ownership- </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">After thanking the customer for their inquiry and gently sharing some suggestions with them, I very softly touched on the fact that I couldn’t do exactly what they were asking. I did however let them know that I was there to help connect them with a solution.</span></b></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><b>Begin a Dialog- </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">In my first reply, I told the customer I couldn’t help them&#8230;PERIOD. That’s effectively the end of the discussion unless the customer wants to argue with me and tell me I’m wrong. In my second approach, I sought to find an alternate solution for them that we could easily support. Perhaps the customer didn’t need overnight shipping, that just happened to be the only possible option they saw. If they needed the item in 2-3 days, that’s a big difference and I, as the expert on my product, can determine if we can accommodate that.</span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><b>Solution-minded- </b><span style="font-weight: 400;">In welcoming the customer’s response, I’ve shown myself to be open and receptive to what they have to say. In some cases, the customer will have more flexibility than we initially assumed. If the customer does respond stating that they need it by tomorrow, our company then has a decision to make. This is a great place to employ the </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">1 to say yes, 2 to say no </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">principle. Rather than responding and saying “Unfortunately there’s nothing I can do,” ask someone in leadership if there’s something we can do. What if the customer’s willing to pay extra for the expedited shipping?</span></li>
</ul>
<p>The point of this is that we are finding ways to do business with customers and solve their problems. That’s a good thing. While there are certainly times to say no to customers, we say no far too often where even just a little flexibility and understanding would create a customer for life.</p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Practice Makes Perfect</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let’s try a few more statements on for size before we end this post. I’ll present the negative and then the positive:</span></p>
<h4><b><i>Question: What’s the status of my order?</i></b></h4>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Negative Answer: Unfortunately your order is still in our warehouse because it was delayed by a day.</span></i></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Positive Answer: Thank you so much for your patience with your order. It is shipping today. If you haven’t received tracking information to your email, it should be there very soon. I hope this information helps.</span></i></p>
<p><b><i>Question: My online order status says “backordered.” When will I receive it?</i></b></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Negative Answer: Unfortunately, your order is indeed backordered and will be unavailable for another month or so.</span></i></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Positive Answer: I’m sorry for the delay in fulfilling this order. It looks like we will be able to ship your product out to you in about a month. If this order is more urgent than that, here are some other products that are very similar that we do have in stock right now. Let me know if you’d like to order one of those instead.</span></i></p>
<p><b><i>Question: Why is my credit card being declined?</i></b></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Negative Answer: There are many reasons your credit card might be declined. Are you sure there’s enough money in your account. You are going to need to contact your bank.</span></i></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Positive Answer: I’m sorry your credit card is being declined. That’s frustrating and we really want you to be able to use our service as soon as possible. I would suggest contacting your bank to see if they have information about the decline. If they say everything is ok, give us a call and we’ll help you try your card again.</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">My eternally optimistic colleague, Hammer Winn helped me in writing this article and so it’s only fitting to quote him as we think about adopting a more positive mindset in our responses to others:</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;This approach not only changes the tone of the interaction, but also creates a customer for life. Practicing this positive approach not only improves your customer service but also has the power to improve your life and relationships.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Take a moment to think about some of your responses throughout each day and find ways to rewrite them so they focus on a solution, show ownership, and encourage dialog with the customer. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To slightly modify a quote from the great baseball player, Mark McGwire, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Customers dig the long ball. </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Learn to hit the curveball and you will hit more home runs with your customers.</span></p>
<h2><strong>About the Author</strong></h2>
<p><img class="alignleft wp-image-2659 " src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/ImageJeremyWatkin-150x150.jpg" alt="" width="129" height="129" />Jeremy Watkin is the Head of Quality at <a href="http://gofcr.com"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">FCR</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the most respected outsource provider. He has more than 15 years of experience as a customer service professional.  He is also the co-founder and regular contributor on </span></i><a href="http://communicatebetterblog.com"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Communicate Better Blog</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">.  Jeremy has been recognized many times for his thought leadership.  Follow him on </span></i><a href="http://twitter.com/jtwatkin"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Twitter</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span></i><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jtwatkin"><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">LinkedIn</span></i></a><i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for more awesome customer service and experience insights.</span></i></p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/leading-off-customer-interactions-with-positivity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
