<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Trends &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<atom:link href="https://onereach.ai/category/trends/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<description>Intelligently Automate Your Company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 11:39:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/cropped-OR-ICON-GOLD-W-DOTS-Larger-Background-02-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Trends &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Mobile Phones Aren’t Even Phones Anymore</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/mobile-phones-arent-even-phones-anymore/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/mobile-phones-arent-even-phones-anymore/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trends]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/mobile-phones-arent-even-phones-anymore/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This guest post is written by Olga Grigorenko, a freelance writer for <a href="http://fueled.com">Fueled</a>.</em></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We can all remember the days when we memorized our friends’ numbers, carefully recorded new contacts in address books, and coquettishly wrote down our digits on party napkins. Telephones were lifelines and phone calls were indispensable. But then </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">mobile</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> phones happened, and our means of communication changed drastically. Exchanging contact information became far more simplified and reaching anyone over the phone became significantly easier. Phone calls could now be made on the go &#8211; anywhere, anytime.</span></p>
<p><span id="more-7426"></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 1970, mobile phones were installed into cars and just three years later, Motorola produced the first handheld mobile phone. The network of wireless towers built to service these mobile phones was arranged in what was called a </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">cellular layout</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, due to its close resemblance to a biological cell. Mobile phones used on this cellular network were soon simply called </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">cellular phones</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">; while </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">cellular</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">mobile</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> are not technically synonymous, they’ve become completely interchangeable in the common vernacular.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since then, wireless phones have developed into devices more comparable to computers than telephones, a factor evident not only in their capabilities, but in our usage of them. Mobile phones are now used for taking pictures, sending emails, <a href="https://fueled.com/">using apps</a>, and listening to music. So when exactly did we stop using our mobile devices as phones and why is it that we still call them </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">phones?</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The fact of the matter is that the ways in which we communicate with each other have changed, and our mobile phones have changed accordingly. Physical phone calls occur less often because they limit us to one task at a time, while texting allows us the freedom to simultaneously listen to music, draft a work email, and </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">also</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> post on Instagram. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Still, all of these advanced capabilities were added onto the </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">cell phone</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, and not vice versa. This perhaps, is the only reason we still call our mobile devices cell phones, and it’s very likely that this may change in the future. There are many other phrases that have managed to outlive their literal meaning. We </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">type</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> but not on typewriters; we </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">rewind</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> things that weren’t unwound; we listen to internet </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">radio</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that doesn’t run on radio waves; we </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">CC</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> (Carbon Copy) people on emails when there’s no carbon paper on our desks. So the question arises: what exactly should we be calling these devices that we carelessly carry around in our pockets?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a few decades, what we now call </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">phones</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> will be able to execute amazing feats &#8211; like supporting photorealistic games, or substituting personalized med packs. As these devices and our use of them continue to evolve, so will our terminology for them. There is no doubt that the ways in which we communicate with each other will continue to change, but our essential human need for communication and contact will remain the same.</span></p>
<p><strong>To learn more about providing a great mobile customer experience over text message, <a href="https://onereach.com/resources/10-things-about-text">download the whitepaper here</a>.</strong></p>
<h2><strong>About the Author</strong></h2>
<p><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-2616" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Olga-150x150.jpg" alt="Olga" width="150" height="150" />Olga Grigorenko is a writer, painter and aspirational dog-owner born and raised in New York City. When she is not busy with work and life in the environs of her Brooklyn home, Olga tends to her wanderlust by exploring as much of the world as possible.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Image of <a href="http://kaboompics.com/one_foto/1063/girl-using-iphone-mobile">girl using iPhone</a> courtesy of Kaboompics.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/mobile-phones-arent-even-phones-anymore/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Year End Review: Customer Service Trends in 2015 and Beyond</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/year-end-review-customer-service-trends-in-2015-and-beyond/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/year-end-review-customer-service-trends-in-2015-and-beyond/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Big Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Communication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Contact Center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Self-Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trends]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/year-end-review-customer-service-trends-in-2015-and-beyond/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As we look back on 2015, it’s tempting to refer to that age-old adage: “The more things change, the more things stay the same.”</p>
<p>This year, that couldn’t be further from the truth.</p>
<p>That’s because 2015 was the year the technology really made its presence known in customer service. Automation, artificial intelligence, social media, CRM integrations, texting&#8211;all were major customer service trends in 2015.</p>
<h2><span id="more-7370"></span><strong>Customer Service Trends in 2015</strong></h2>
<p>2015 was the year that:</p>
<p><strong>Customer service got smart.</strong> This year, artificial intelligence wasn’t just limited to the realms of science fiction a la Age of Ultron—it was also slowly incorporated into different companies’ service offerings. Amazon made its entry into the home automation market with Alexa, a virtual assistant that can field questions ranging from the time of day to traffic predictions to good restaurants nearby. On the enterprise-level side, IBM continued to expand the capabilities of Jeopardy-winning Watson, adding self-service into varied industries like healthcare, education and finance, among others.</p>
<p><strong>Customer service got automated.</strong> Over <a href="http://www.dimensiondata.com/Global/Downloadable%20Documents/2015%20Global%20Contact%20Centre%20Benchmarking%20Summary%20Report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">55% of customers</a> would like a self-service experience, which provides businesses with the unique opportunity to speed up the customer experience while decreasing costs. In the restaurant industry, established chains like Outback Steakhouse and Olive Garden let customers <a href="http://www.csmonitor.com/Business/Saving-Money/2015/0514/Restaurant-table-tablets-A-gimmick-or-actually-helpful" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">order via tablets</a>, while market newcomer <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2015/09/09/upshot/restaurant-of-the-future-service-with-an-impersonal-touch.html?_r=2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Eatsa</a> automated the bulk of the food delivery process. Automated self-service also extended to digital channels—companies like <a href="http://www.toistersolutions.com/blog/2015/10/28/automation-fail-how-attcares-stumbled-into-a-tweet-chat" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">AT&amp;T</a> automated social media responses (not always with the best outcome), while <a href="https://www.twilio.com/customers/stories/uber" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Uber</a>, Snooze and more texted customers about the status of their ride or table.</p>
<p><strong>Customer service got focused.</strong> Over 80% of companies want to use <a href="https://fonolo.com/blog/2013/09/17-important-customer-experience-statistics-for-the-call-center/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">customer service</a> as a way to differentiate themselves from their competition. But what defines a good customer service experience? In 2015, we interviewed over 60 industry influencers and found that the best way to <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/customer-service-report-2015" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">improve customer service</a> was to focus on the employee experience. By focusing on employees and treating them with respect, companies can ensure that they pass that goodwill onto customers. Case in point: <a href="https://jobs.zappos.com/why-zappos" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Zappos</a> or <a href="http://www.google.com/about/careers/lifeatgoogle/benefits/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Google</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Customer service got diversified.</strong> In 2015, companies made an effort to diversify their service offerings, providing support on established and emerging channels.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Mobile.</strong> In 2015, companies increasingly relied on mobile to interact with their customers. This year saw the official launch of Apple Pay, Starbucks’ continued success with mobile app <a href="http://www.nfcworld.com/2015/07/24/336798/one-in-five-starbucks-sales-in-the-us-made-with-mobile-payments/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">payments</a> (more than $9 million in orders processed per week) and Magic’s simple but powerful text concierge service. As mentioned above, more and more companies saw the value of adding texting to their support strategy, making it easier for customers to contact them on a channel they prefer. However, not every attempt to implement mobile customer service was successful—Domino’s unfortunately disappointed some customers with the rollout of its text-to-order service.</p>
<p><strong>Video.</strong> Audiovisual communication has been popular among consumers for years, but 2015 was the year when video really started to gain a foothold in B2C interactions. Amazon’s Mayday is probably the most well-known example, but <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2015/01/28/this-is-webrtcs-yearor-is-it/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">American Express</a> and other companies helped customers solve their problems over video. WebRTC’s open source nature also made it easier for any company to incorporate video into their service offering.</p>
<p><strong>Social.</strong> 2015 was the year social platforms got serious about customer service interactions. <a href="https://twitter.app.box.com/customer-service-on-twitter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Twitter</a>released a customer service playbook outlining the benefits of using social for customer service, as well as how to apply it to an organization. <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2015/06/15/facebook-pages-can-now-show-how-quickly-they-respond-to-customers-messages/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Facebook</a> also launched a new feature that keeps track of how long it takes company pages to respond to customer messages, giving customers better insight into the responsiveness of an organization. This is especially important, given the fact that over 40% of customers expect a response on <a href="http://www.convinceandconvert.com/social-media-research/42-percent-of-consumers-complaining-in-social-media-expect-60-minute-response-time/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">social</a> in 60 minutes or less.</p>
<p><strong>Voice.</strong> Voice is still king in contact center service interactions, but times are changing. Research from<a href="http://www.dimensiondata.com/Global/Downloadable%20Documents/2015%20Global%20Contact%20Centre%20Benchmarking%20Summary%20Report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Dimension Data</a> found that while voice accounts for 65% of all contact center interactions, digital interactions will surpass voice by the end of 2017. And with <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/07/07/technology/tech-companies-leave-phone-calls-behind.html?_r=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Internet-based companies</a> making a concerted attempt to direct customers towards digital, with other companies ditching corporate <a href="http://www.inc.com/associated-press/jpmorgan-chase-getting-rid-of-voicemail-for-some-employees.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">voicemail</a>, it became very clear in that businesses couldn’t just rely on voice for communication.</p>
<p><strong>Web chat</strong>. Over 70% of contact centers will offer web chat by the end of 2016, up from just 33% in 2015. There are several reasons why companies would want to invest in web chat—it’s cheaper than voice, agents can handle multiple conversations at once and respond in real-time, etc. And there’s a reason companies from Nordstrom to Nike are using web chat to interact with customers—while 91% of customers are happy with web chat’s ability to solve customer support issues, 62% of customers are more inclined to buy a product if live chat is available.</p></blockquote>
<h2><strong>Looking ahead to 2016</strong></h2>
<p>2015 was an exciting year for customer service, with lots of progress made in digital interactions and automation. 2016 is set to be an equally exciting year, if not more so, as companies continue to build on the advances made in 2015. We can’t say for sure what will happen in customer service in 2016, but we’ve got a few ideas.</p>
<p>Below are our customer service predictions for 2016.</p>
<p><strong>Continued rise in cloud computing</strong>. In 2016, businesses will continue to migrate to the <a href="http://www.icmi.com/Resources/Technology/2014/05/Is-the-Cloud-Contact-Center-Passing-You-By" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">cloud</a> for its accessibility, storage, simplicity, and security, among other benefits. In fact, 88% of businesses are currently using the <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/benkepes/2015/03/04/new-stats-from-the-state-of-cloud-report/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">public cloud</a>. In addition, <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/louiscolumbus/2015/09/27/roundup-of-cloud-computing-forecasts-and-market-estimates-q3-update-2015/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gartner</a> predicts that by 2020, roughly 25% of organizations will use cloud-based CRMs. Cloud-based software-as-a-service, or <a href="http://www.pwc.com/gx/en/industries/technology/publications/global-software-100-leaders/saas-trends.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SaaS</a>, will also become more prevalent, growing at a rate of 21.3% per year and making up 14.2% of software spending. <a href="http://www.statista.com/statistics/273642/worldwide-software-as-a-service-revenue-forecast/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SaaS revenue</a> is predicted to hit $32.8 billion in revenue in 2016, up 17% from 2015.</p>
<p><strong>Delivering on the omnichannel promise. </strong>In 2013, <a href="https://d16cvnquvjw7pr.cloudfront.net/resources/whitepapers/Omnichannel-Customer-Service-Gap.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Zendesk </a>research found that over 85% of customers thought companies needed to do a better job of providing a seamless experience. In 2015, companies were on the right track but weren’t quite there yet—nearly 50% of contact centers named integration of Web, contact center and CRM systems as their top challenge, with <a href="http://www.dimensiondata.com/Global/Downloadable%20Documents/2015%20Global%20Contact%20Centre%20Benchmarking%20Summary%20Report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">integration</a> of systems to enable channel hopping close behind (41%). We predict that in 2016, companies will continue to take steps toward providing an omnichannel experience. Companies will find and use service platforms that manage and can integrate with multiple service channels/CRMs and similar systems.</p>
<p><strong>Personalization.</strong> This trend is a combination of the previous two trends—cloud services will enable companies to provide a personalized experience across channels. We predict that the ability to integrate customer data into service interactions will become increasingly mainstream in 2016, both in response to <a href="http://venturebeat.com/2015/07/14/consumers-want-privacy-yet-demand-personalization/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">consumer demand</a> and a desire to differentiate on great <a href="https://fonolo.com/blog/2013/09/17-important-customer-experience-statistics-for-the-call-center/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">customer experiences</a>. The SaaS pricing model of most cloud services will also make it easy for businesses of any size to provide great customer service.</p>
<p><strong>Proactive customer service.</strong> <a href="http://www.wired.com/insights/2014/11/the-internet-of-things-bigger/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Internet of Things</a> is rapidly changing our personal and professional lives. IoT-based companies, but other businesses as well, will leverage customer data to provide a proactive service experience. Although IoT is primarily focused on the B2C experience (think FitBit or any smartfridge), other organizations can learn from IoT innovations. Take, for example, the proactive service experience industry pundits anticipate will take shape in the IoT industry: <a href="http://www.destinationcrm.com/Articles/Web-Exclusives/Viewpoints/Revolutionizing-Customer-Service-with-the-Internet-of-Things-105722.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gartner</a> predicts that by 2018, five percent of IoT devices will automatically trigger service cases.</p>
<p><strong>More artificial intelligence.</strong> In 2016, AI will continue to get smarter, and its presence in business will continue to grow. This is evidenced by the amount of <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/article/artificial-intelligence-in-business-the-state-of-play-and-future-prospects/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">venture capital</a> being put toward AI-centered businesses, which grew from $75 million in 2013 to $300 million in 2014. And while <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/article/artificial-intelligence-in-business-the-state-of-play-and-future-prospects/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">artificial intelligence</a> is primarily being used for voice recognition and response, <a href="http://www.destinationcrm.com/Articles/Editorial/Magazine-Features/The-2015-CRM-Rising-Stars-IBMs-Watson-Brings-Cognitive-Computing-to-Customer-Support-102108.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gartner</a> predicts that 10% of computers will be able to learn from past interactions by 2017. At OneReach, we’re helping to make this possible through the use of AI in IVRs or self-service.</p>
<p><strong>Moving towards a mobile-first future.</strong> Our world is becoming increasingly mobilized—nearly two billion global citizens now own a <a href="http://www.emarketer.com/Article/2-Billion-Consumers-Worldwide-Smartphones-by-2016/1011694" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">smartphone</a>. This mobile change extends to customer service, where 62% of companies think <a href="http://www.icmi.com/About-ICMI/Press-Room/2013-Mobile-Customer-Service-Strategy-Results-Released" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">mobile service</a> is a competitive differentiator and 64% of customers would prefer to text customer service. Texting is poised to make a big gain in the customer service field, with more than 60% of <a href="http://www.dimensiondata.com/Global/Downloadable%20Documents/2015%20Global%20Contact%20Centre%20Benchmarking%20Summary%20Report.pdf/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">contact centers</a>offering it by 2017. In 2016, we predict that companies will continue to provide customer service on mobile devices, whether it’s via text message, mobile applications, mobile websites, or other channels.</p>
<p><strong>More digital/emerging channels.</strong> As mentioned above, customer service interactions will shift to focus on emerging digital channels, both in response to consumer preference and cost savings. Take, for instance, the increased use emerging channels: One in four contact centers will offer <a href="http://www.dimensiondata.com/Global/Downloadable%20Documents/2015%20Global%20Contact%20Centre%20Benchmarking%20Summary%20Report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">video</a> by the end of 2017, one in two contact centers will offer a smartphone app by the end of 2017, and three out of five contact centers will offer texting/IM by the end of 2017.</p>
<h2><strong>Conclusion</strong></h2>
<p>2015 was a big year for customer service, and 2016 is set to be an even bigger one. We predict that new applications of technology like artificial intelligence and automation will define customer service in the coming years, as they already have today. Companies and contact centers that embrace the customer service trends in 2015 and beyond are poised to make an impact on the market that will be felt for years to come.</p>
<p><strong>For more on how to improve your customer service in 2016, <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/customer-service-report-2015">download our influencer report</a> with insights from more than 60 customer service pros.</strong></p>
<p><em>This post originally appeared on <a href="http://www.icmi.com/Resources/Customer-Experience/2016/01/Customer-Service-Trends-in-2015-and-What-They-Mean-for-2016">ICMI</a> and has been republished with permission. </em></p>
<p>Image credit: <a href="https://pixabay.com/en/man-guy-smoking-cigarettes-bench-691422/">Unsplash</a>. CC0 License. Edited.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/year-end-review-customer-service-trends-in-2015-and-beyond/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekly Review: 12/18 Edition</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/weekly-review-12-18-edition/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/weekly-review-12-18-edition/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/weekly-review-12-18-edition/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Happy Friday! Here’s our five picks for the best customer service, customer experience and mobile articles of the week, in no particular order.</p>
<h2><span id="more-7366"></span><strong><a href="http://gulfnews.com/news/uae/government/sms-999-for-emergencies-new-texting-service-for-the-differently-abled-1.1635968">SMS 999 for Emergencies: New Texting Service for the Differently-abled</a> by <a href="http://gulfnews.com/">Noorhan Barakat</a></strong></h2>
<p>At OneReach, we’re big believers in using text messaging to help others. But helping other extends far beyond customer service—it applies to emergencies as well. That’s why it’s so heartening to see Dubai Police embracing the use of SMS so that disabled citizens can text instead of call for emergencies. Some people may feel more comfortable using text or may not be able to speak in certain situations, making communication via SMS all the more valuable. In his article for Gulf News, Noorhan Barakat goes on to explain how this SMS service can be enhanced with information about citizens.</p>
<blockquote><p>Brigadier Kamel Butti Al Suwaidi added that Dubai Police has a list of people with disabilities that is tied into the system so the officer in the operations room is aware of the sender’s condition. ‘This new service is in line with Dubai Police’s strategy of providing best services to the public and is also part of its social responsibility,’ he said.</p></blockquote>
<p>The more you know about your audience and their needs, the better you’ll be able to help them. Dubai embracing their citizens’ need for alternative communication channels is a great example of this.</p>
<p>Read the full article on <a href="http://gulfnews.com/news/uae/government/sms-999-for-emergencies-new-texting-service-for-the-differently-abled-1.1635968">Gulf News</a>.</p>
<h2><strong><a href="http://customerthink.com/customer-survey-mistakes-almost-all-companies-make-2/">Customer Survey Mistakes Almost All Companies Make</a> by <a href="http://www.vocalabs.com/">Peter Leppik</a></strong></h2>
<p>Surveys are a valuable way to collect customer feedback, learn from it, and use it to improve the rest of your organization. While the goals of surveys may vary (customer satisfaction, customer effort, etc.), all can be used to produce valuable insights that an organization can learn from and iterate upon. However, there are a few mistakes companies want to avoid making when they conduct surveys. According to Peter Leppik, one of those mistakes includes focusing on metrics, not customers.</p>
<blockquote><p>Many companies focus solely on the metrics and forget the customers behind them. Metrics make sense as a progress marker, but the goal is not to improve metrics but to improve customer experiences.</p></blockquote>
<p>Numbers are great, but they&#8217;ll only get you so far. By treating customers like what they are&#8211;people&#8211;companies will make sure their customer experience is always on-point.</p>
<p>Read the full article on <a href="http://customerthink.com/customer-survey-mistakes-almost-all-companies-make-2/">CustomerThink</a>.</p>
<h2><strong><a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/blakemorgan/2015/12/17/5-must-have-components-of-a-modern-customer-experience/">5 Must-Have Components of a Modern Customer Experience</a> by <a href="http://twitter.com/blakemichellem">Blake Morgan</a></strong></h2>
<p>More and more companies today are seeking to differentiate on the <a href="https://fonolo.com/blog/2013/09/17-important-customer-experience-statistics-for-the-call-center/">customer experience</a>—in fact, over 80% of companies want to use CX to stand out from their competition. But companies aren’t the only ones looking for better CX—86% of customers would pay for a better customer experience. And with customer expectations changing and becoming more technology-focused, how can companies make sure they’re providing the best CX possible? In her Forbes article, customer experience expert Blake Morgan suggests using a customer intelligence tool.</p>
<blockquote><p>Big companies have more pieces of data than there are grains of sand on the earth or stars in the sky. A lot! Through a customer intelligence tool that offers speech tracking, clicks, sentiment and text analytics the company can gain valuable insight into common issues with their products and services.</p></blockquote>
<p>Any company that wants to differentiate based on customer experience needs to know the kind of experience customers want. Then they’ll be able to provide the best experience possible.</p>
<p>Read the full article on <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/blakemorgan/2015/12/17/5-must-have-components-of-a-modern-customer-experience/">Forbes</a>.</p>
<h2><strong><a href="http://www.inc.com/chris-matyszczyk/the-5-biggest-juiciest-lies-of-customer-service.html">The 5 Biggest, Juiciest Lies of Customer Service</a> by <a href="http://www.twitter.com/ChrisMatyszczyk">Chris Matyszczyk</a></strong></h2>
<p>What does authentic customer service look like? Is it the ability to talk to a live agent? Is it having someone there to empathize with you? Is it getting your problem solved on the first try by a knowledgeable agent? In reality, it’s all of these things and more. Unfortunately, some companies provide customers with an inauthentic user experience, which can end up losing them business, and some phrases can signal to customers that you’re being insincere. In his Inc. article, Chris Matyszczyk explains how the phrase “We value your business” can rub customers the wrong way.</p>
<blockquote><p>Why does this one so often come out when a company has just shown you how little it  values your business? It has either behaved negligently or its product has unexpectedly failed and the first thing the customer service rep comes out with (on IM, of course) is to tell you how much it values your business. When it comes to valuing someone you should show it, not say it.</p></blockquote>
<p>As Matyszczyk says, it means a lot more when a company shows you they care rather than tells you they care. Authentic customer service should mean doing everything in your power to solve the customer’s problem.</p>
<p>Read the full article on <a href="http://www.inc.com/chris-matyszczyk/the-5-biggest-juiciest-lies-of-customer-service.html">Inc</a>.</p>
<h2><strong><a href="http://uxmag.com/articles/the-7-steps-of-using-journey-mapping-to-optimize-cx">The 7 Steps of Using Journey Mapping to Optimize CX</a> by <a href="http://www.keylimeinteractive.com/">Ania Rodriguez</a></strong></h2>
<p>The customer experience doesn’t always start when a customer calls when a customer calls in for customer service. It starts when a customer first interacts with your brand. For some, this might mean tweeting with you on social media, web chatting in with a question about your product, or downloading whitepaper detailing your service. The point is, each customer experience starts at a different place. So how can you anticipate how your customers will interact with your brand? According to customer experience expert Ania Rodriguez, companies should use journey maps.</p>
<blockquote><p>As UX designers begin mapping customers’ journeys, they should record and visualize the persona’s attributes, attitudes, and emotions through all customer or prospective touchpoints. At each point, the persona’s needs and drivers should be detailed, as should the capabilities to improve each touchpoint and the cumulative omnichannel experience.</p></blockquote>
<p>By using journey maps, companies can make sure they’re providing customers with the best experience possible, no matter where the experience started.</p>
<p>Read the full article on <a href="http://uxmag.com/articles/the-7-steps-of-using-journey-mapping-to-optimize-cx">UX Magazine</a>.</p>
<p><em>We’ll be taking the next two Fridays off for the holidays but will pick up the Weekly Review in January.</em></p>
<p><strong>To learn more about providing a great mobile customer experience, <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/mobile-strategy">download our new whitepaper here</a>. </strong></p>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christmas_ornament">Christmas ornament image</a> from Wikipedia. Edited.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/weekly-review-12-18-edition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekly Review: 12/11 Edition</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/weekly-review-12-11-edition/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/weekly-review-12-11-edition/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Review]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/weekly-review-12-11-edition/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Happy Friday! Here’s our five picks for the best customer service, customer experience and mobile articles of the last week or so, in no particular order.</p>
<p><span id="more-7363"></span></p>
<h2><strong><a href="http://www.wired.com/2015/12/the-up-next-program-preps-kids-for-college-by-texting-them">The Up Next Program Preps Kids for College by Texting Them</a> by Liz Stinson</strong></h2>
<p>Teens and twentysomethings <em>love</em> to text. It’s an easy, efficient way to get in touch with friends, whether it’s to make plans for a night on the town or just to let someone know how they’re doing. But one government program has decided to tap into teens’ passion for texting with a new initiative called Up Next. When students opt in, they receive “precisely timed” reminders to fill out financial aid forms, applications and more to help ensure they’re on track to receive a college education. In her article for Wired, Liz Stinson outlines why this new approach to education is so effective.</p>
<blockquote><p>Up Next translates oft-dense information about government forms and programs into bite-sized, actionable texts that, when deployed at the right time, make the process of getting stuff done a lot less cumbersome. This is in line with the White House’s increased focus on using behavioral science research to improve the efficiency and effectiveness of government programs.</p></blockquote>
<p>We’re extremely excited to see how text messaging is being used in higher education. It’s a great example of the different was texting can be applied in different industries, to great effect.</p>
<p>Read the full article on <a href="http://www.wired.com/2015/12/the-up-next-program-preps-kids-for-college-by-texting-them">Wired</a>.</p>
<h2><strong><a href="http://www.inc.com/robin-camarote/4-lessons-for-delivering-flawless-customer-service.html">4 Lessons for Delivering Flawless Customer Service</a> by <a href="http://twitter.com/robincamarote">Robin Camarote</a></strong></h2>
<p>Having well-trained, intelligent employees on your team is an extremely important part of customer service delivery. In fact, our recent influencer report found that the #1 way to improve customer service is to focus on the employee experience. While this can come in many forms (training, one-on-one meetings, special events, etc.), the goal is the same: to make sure your employees are performing well. In her article for Inc., author Robin Camarote discusses the importance of taking care of your employees and empowering them to provide the best service possible. One of the ways is to encourage creative thinking and problem solving.</p>
<blockquote><p>Encourage creative, independent thinking and problem solving. Giving employees reasonable latitude to expend both time and money enables them to take a great experience &#8220;over the top&#8221; or to fix a bad one quickly.</p></blockquote>
<p>By treating employees well and empowering them to do their best, they in turn will pass that goodwill onto customers.</p>
<p>Read the full article on <a href="http://www.inc.com/robin-camarote/4-lessons-for-delivering-flawless-customer-service.html">Inc</a>.</p>
<h2><strong><a href="http://www.mycustomer.com/service/channels/is-artificial-intelligence-the-future-of-customer-service">Is Artificial Intelligence the Future of Customer Service?</a> by Chinia Green of <a href="http://www.celaton.com/">Celaton</a></strong></h2>
<p>For a time, AI was relegated to the realm of science fiction, only possible in shows like <em>Star Trek</em> or movies like <em>The Terminator</em>. But this has changed in recent years with the emergence of automated personal assistants like Apple’s Siri, Microsoft’s Cortana, Amazon’s Echo and the supercomputer IBM Watson. And artificial intelligence is now starting to bleed into industries like customer service, which seems a natural fit given AI’s capacity to handle large amounts of information like customer data, as well as its low cost when compared to human interactions. But is AI set to take the human element out of customer service? Not entirely, according to Celaton’s Chinia Green.</p>
<blockquote><p>With AI, organisations will be able to understand what customers are saying in real-time and respond rapidly and appropriately. A growing number of the correspondence received will be able to be dealt with minimal human intervention, ensuring that customers receive a swift, consistent and personal service. Whilst allowing humans to focus on more high value tasks, such as spending more time talking to customers to develop ‘relationships’ and reputation.</p></blockquote>
<p>Artificial intelligence will be able to help answer common questions quickly and easily, but support agents will still manage more complex queries.</p>
<p>Read the full article on <a href="http://www.mycustomer.com/service/channels/is-artificial-intelligence-the-future-of-customer-service">MyCustomer</a>.</p>
<h2></h2>
<h2><strong><a href="http://customerthink.com/ibm-chief-strategist-for-watson-trend-app-answers-4-questions-for-marketing-innovators/">IBM Chief Strategist for Watson Trend App Answers 4 Questions for Marketing Innovators</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/ernanroman">Ernan Roman</a></strong></h2>
<p>The holiday season is in full swing, and with it comes the mad dash to buy just the right presents for your loved ones. But how do you know exactly what to get them, or even if they’ll like it? Enter the IBM Watson Trend app, which identifies the top trending gifts in health, tech, and toys. The app has found that the Apple Watch is a big ticket item (no surprise there) but its insights into other gifts might just be the inspiration you need for your holiday shopping. In his latest article, CX expert Ernan Roman interviews IBM Chief Strategist for the Watson Trend App Justin Norwood, and asked him about how the app will improve the customer experience. Here’s some of what he had to say.</p>
<blockquote><p>Shoppers can use the app to understand why people are buying certain products or brands this holiday season, and it also can tell what products will be hot next, before they sell out. The app does this by distilling sentiment of tens of millions of online conversations found in 10,000 sources across social media sites, blogs, forums, comments, ratings and reviews – something no human being could do.</p></blockquote>
<p>Artificial intelligence’s power comes from its ability to sort through massive amounts of data to gain understanding and spot trends. And while AI can be applied to help you find the best gift, the possibilities it opens are limitless.</p>
<p>Read the full article on <a href="http://customerthink.com/ibm-chief-strategist-for-watson-trend-app-answers-4-questions-for-marketing-innovators/">CustomerThink</a>.</p>
<h2><strong><a href="http://www.gofcr.com/customer-service-to-text-messaging-you-complete-me/">Customer Service to Text Messaging: “You Complete Me”</a> by <a href="http://twitter.com/jtwatkin">Jeremy Watkin</a></strong></h2>
<p>At OneReach, we’re unabashed lovers of text messaging. It’s easy to use, it’s ubiquitous, it’s affordable—all of which make it a great fit for customer service. In fact, research has found that 64% of customers would rather text than call a business for their service needs. And even though texting has been around for over 20 years, it’s finally starting to be adopted by businesses not just for marketing, but for customer service. But how do you get started with adding texting to your service department? In a recent blog post, customer service expert Jeremy Watkin outlines best practices for adding texting, one of which is to be appropriately empathetic.</p>
<blockquote><p>When you’re going for concise, there doesn’t need to be a big empathy statement. A simple “I’m sorry” or “I’m here to help” can go a long way toward giving the customer confidence that you are taking ownership if their issue. On the other side “Awesome!” or “That’s outstanding!” can convey a spirit of genuine excitement.</p></blockquote>
<p>When texting with customers for their service needs, you need to keep their problem top of mind, as well as their feelings. This will ensure you deliver the best, most authentic service possible.</p>
<p>Read the full article on <a href="http://www.gofcr.com/customer-service-to-text-messaging-you-complete-me/">FCR</a>.</p>
<p><strong>To learn more about the benefits of adding texting to your business, <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/mobile-strategy">download our whitepaper here</a>.</strong></p>
<p>Image from <a href="http://spaniaidag.es/2015/10/28/billigere-a-bruke-mobilen/">Spania I Dag</a>. Edited.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/weekly-review-12-11-edition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Contact Centers Will Go Digital By 2017</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/contact-centers-will-go-digital-by-2017/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/contact-centers-will-go-digital-by-2017/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Contact Center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trends]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/contact-centers-will-go-digital-by-2017/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Contact centers need to get ready to get digital.</p>
<p>According to the <a href="http://www.dimensiondata.com/Global/Global-Microsites/CCBenchmarking">2015 Global Contact Centre Benchmarking Report</a> by Dimension Data, digital interaction will outpace voice interaction within the next two years. Digital interactions currently comprise 35% of customer interactions: this includes IVR, text messaging, mobile applications, social media, websites, and more. This is in line with customers&#8217; demand for a seamless omnichannel experience, one that&#8217;s more contextualized and personalized on every channel.</p>
<p><span id="more-7214"></span>The report also found that nearly 75% of organizations believe the contact center is a competitive differentiator, and one of the best ways to stay competitive is to provide the best customer experience. With voice traffic predicted to decrease 42% in the next two years, offering great service on alternative channels will be more important than ever. Luckily, 35% of agents are now skilled in managing multiple channels, and that number will only increase over the next few years.</p>
<p>Also of note: 38% of contact centers currently offer SMS, and 23% have plans to add it in the next 12 months. That means 61% of contact centers will offer SMS support in 2016.</p>
<p>View the summary report from <a href="http://www.dimensiondata.com/Global/Global-Microsites/CCBenchmarking">Dimension Data&#8217;s website</a>, and don’t forget to download our <a href="http://onereachcontactcenter.com/high-demand-for-customer-service-via-text-message/">free Harris report</a> about America’s preference for texting.</p>
<p>Image from <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Contact-center-two-agents.jpg">Wikimedia</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/contact-centers-will-go-digital-by-2017/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Self-Service: The Next Channel You Can&#8217;t Ignore</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/self-service-the-next-channel-you-cant-ignore/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/self-service-the-next-channel-you-cant-ignore/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Self-Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trends]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/self-service-the-next-channel-you-cant-ignore/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Self-service has been around for generations, from the advent of personal shopping in grocery stores to the global presence of ATMs. But it was really in the last quarter century that self-service hit its stride, thanks to the rise of the Internet. Customers can solve their own problems or answer their own questions thanks to the ubiquity of this technology.</p>
<p><span id="more-7201"></span>OneReach&#8217;s Elias Parker explains further in his CustomerThink article:</p>
<blockquote><p>The now 25 year-old Internet quickly changed many industries, from communications to commerce to customer service. People can now search online for solutions to their problems, or check their account balance without having to talk to an agent. And frankly, people prefer to manage customer service themselves when they want, from where they want. In fact, Forrester found that more than 70% of customers prefer self-service to talking on the phone or sending an email.</p></blockquote>
<p><strong><a href="http://customerthink.com/the-future-of-self-service-the-next-channel-you-cant-ignore/">Check out the full article here</a> for insight on the future on self-service, and download the <a href="http://onereachcontactcenter.com/high-demand-for-customer-service-via-text-message/">free Harris Interactive report</a> to learn more about how customers want service delivered.</strong></p>
<p>Photo by <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/42806032@N07/5468105087/">Polycart</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/self-service-the-next-channel-you-cant-ignore/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>8 Important Text Trends of 2014 (and Beyond)</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/8-important-text-trends-of-2014-and-beyond/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/8-important-text-trends-of-2014-and-beyond/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trends]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/8-important-text-trends-of-2014-and-beyond/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In December 1992, 22-year-old Neil Papworth sent the first ever text message, appropriately saying “Merry Christmas.” Papworth and coworkers had originally conceived text messaging as an <a href="http://www.realcleartechnology.com/2014/12/08/texting_turns_22_24545.html">internal communication tool</a>, but providers soon found a way to monetize texting with paid messaging plans.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Teens and young adults were the first to adopt the technology in the 1990s, enjoying the ability to communicate without their parents understanding. Since then, text messaging has exploded in popularity among all ages. <a href="http://onereachcontactcenter.com/high-demand-for-customer-service-via-text-message/">Over 93% of millennials text</a>, but so do <a href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/?p=1036">68% of baby boomers</a>. Texting isn’t strictly a young man’s game.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><span id="more-7195"></span>Texting also isn’t just for person to person communication anymore. In 2014, businesses started to adopt SMS for all aspects of their business, not just marketing. Businesses can now use texting to communicate with customers, and vice versa. A Harris Interactive survey conducted on behalf of OneReach found that <a href="http://onereachcontactcenter.com/high-demand-for-customer-service-via-text-message/">64% of customers</a> would rather text a business than call them. Text adoption started to climb in 2014 as businesses started to understand the positive impact it could have.</p>
<p dir="ltr">But now, an increasing number of businesses are responding to consumer demand for text, and are using the text messaging throughout their enterprise. Businesses that offer text can send their customers appointment reminders, account balances, surveys, and much more.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Texting isn’t just limited to businesses; local governments have started to take advantage of it too. Communities like <a href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/?p=629">Evanston, Ill.</a>, use texting for traffic updates and snow alerts, but also let citizens text them back. <a href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/?p=646">Humanitarian organizations are using texting</a> to solicit donations, send tips and advice, and alert citizens about incoming disasters. One powerful example of texting can be seen in <a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/goatsandsoda/2014/10/27/357647182/the-red-cross-is-using-text-messaging-to-take-down-ebola">this year’s Ebola crisis</a>.</p>
<p dir="ltr">A lot of businesses use social media to provide customer support, but they’re not limited to that channel (nor should they be). For example, a lot of companies use Twitter for customer support, which makes sense since over 500 million Twitter messages are sent each day, but so are 23 billion text messages. Texting is more popular than any social network, and the more businesses recognize that, the better service they can provide.</p>
<h2 dir="ltr">Technological breakthroughs</h2>
<p dir="ltr">Texting has made some major strides in the past year, most notably:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Channel pivot.</strong> With the introduction of business texting, a new technology breakthrough has emerged. Companies can now expose their SMS channel within their IVR. For example, instead of waiting on hold, the caller could press * to transition out of the voice queue and into a texting expereience (either automated or a live conversation). This acts as a discovery mechanism which is good because customers aren’t <a style="font-style: normal;" href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/?p=499">always interested in talking to someone</a>. They’re usually trying to get their problem solved with the least amount of effort. Companies that let customers channel pivot (switching between a phone call and text or vice versa) give customers the chance to communicate on their terms. <a style="font-style: normal;" href="http://onereachcontactcenter.com/high-demand-for-customer-service-via-text-message/">A Harris Interactive study</a> commissioned by OneReach found that 44% of customers would prefer to live chat with an agent immediately rather than wait on hold. When customers do switch channels, they should be able to pick up the conversation right where they left off.</li>
<li><strong>Text enabling 10-digit numbers.</strong> In the past, businesses relied on short codes (5 or 6 digit numbers) to communicate with customers over SMS. These numbers cost several thousand dollars a year and are heavily regulated. Long code numbers (traditional 10-digit numbers) only cost $1-2 per month and can be used to send voice messages as well as texts, providing a cost-effective, functional alternative to short codes. (Learn more about the benefits of text-enabling a business<a style="font-style: normal;" href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/?p=129"> here</a>,<a style="font-style: normal;" href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/?p=273"> here</a> and<a style="font-style: normal;" href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/?p=1092"> here</a>).</li>
<li><strong>Text enabling toll-free numbers.</strong> Text-enabled toll-free numbers allow businesses to get more out of their 800 number and support a more consistent communication strategy. Toll-free numbers usually send customers through a drawn-out IVR process, but now customers carry out these interactions in seconds rather than minutes over text. This also means customers can carry out service interactions over text, saving themselves and agents time.</li>
<li><strong>MMS Support.</strong> In addition to calling and texting a business,<a style="font-style: normal;" href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/?p=556"> customers can now MMS a business</a>. Thanks to companies like<a style="font-style: normal;" href="https://www.twilio.com/mms"> Twilio</a> and <a style="font-style: normal;" href="https://www.zipwhip.com/">Zipwhip</a>, businesses can send multiple file types to customers, and vice versa. Customers can share photos, forward voicemails to text message, and read PDF help files without needing to interact with an agent.</li>
<li><strong>API Economy.</strong> APIs can be a difficult concept to grasp, but what they essentially do is tell two separate software applications how to interact with one another. This lets contact centers integrate their services with CRMs like Salesforce, so that they can personalize interactions based on customer data.</li>
<li><strong>Context. </strong><a style="font-style: normal;" href="http://www.accenture.com/SiteCollectionDocuments/PDF/Accenture-Global-Consumer-Pulse-Research-Study-2013-Key-Findings.pdf">Almost 90% of customers</a> hate having to repeat their problem multiple times. That’s because most departments in a company store their data separately, keeping them from creating a comprehensive view of their customers. Advanced contact center solutions unite all customer data in one place, regardless of the channel they use or the department they reach. If a customer texts a company, an agent should be able to see a history of all their past interactions, whether they’re national or site-specific.</li>
<li><strong>Personalization.</strong> Today’s customers are looking for personalized experiences on multiple channels. This goes beyond adding someone’s name to a text message (although it includes that too). Companies can use a customer’s past interactions with the company to deliver a more optimized, personalized experience. The more a company knows about a customer at the beginning, the quicker they can help them and the more satisfied the customer will be.</li>
<li><strong>Automation.</strong> Customers expect speed in their service interactions and companies can deliver that with<a style="font-style: normal;" href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/?p=724"> interactive text response (ITR)</a>. Customers trying to check their balance or reset their password don’t need a human to walk them through that; they can do it themselves with automation. However, just because responses are automated doesn’t mean they need to be<a style="font-style: normal;" href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/?p=267"> completely robotic</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="ltr">Companies and customers alike are starting to realize the value of text as a service channel. It’s got the capabilities of all the other channels combined—the one-on-one interaction of voice, the immediacy of live chat and the flexibility of self-service. Plus, it doesn’t require an internet connection like today’s popular messaging apps do.</p>
<h2 dir="ltr">Looking Ahead to 2015</h2>
<p dir="ltr">At OneReach, we believe 2015 will be a bigger year than ever for business texting. In fact, it’s gonna be such a big year that we have some big predictions to go along with it, like:</p>
<ul>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Using SMS for support will overtake the use of SMS for marketing in the enterprise.</strong></p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr"><strong>More enterprises will add an (Interactive Text Response (ITR) capabilities</strong></p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Text surveys will replace email surveys in companies that offer both support channels.</strong></p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr"><strong>In 2014, SMS was for innovators in 2015, SMS will start becoming mainstream.</strong></p>
</li>
<li dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr"><strong>In 2015, we will see a significant increase in enterprise use of text message support.</strong></p>
</li>
</ul>
<p dir="ltr">We also believe businesses will integrate texting with other channels as part of their omnichannel service offering—one where customers can switch between channels without companies missing a beat. In addition, we predict that more and more companies will automate their service in 2015&#8211;interactive text response (ITR) will become an increasingly preferred form of communication.</p>
<p dir="ltr">IP messaging services like Whatsapp and iMessage will be added to contact center offerings and will be integrated with other channels.<a href="http://www.mobileindustryreview.com/2014/12/text-message-sms-turns-22.html"> Although IP messaging has siphoned off</a> part of the worldwide text traffic, SMS will still be a channel to be reckoned with<a href="http://www.portioresearch.com/en/blog/2013/the-15-trillion-$-dollar-story-of-sms.aspx"> for years to come</a>.</p>
<p dir="ltr">2015 will also see phone carriers clashing with companies that provide text-enabled toll-free numbers. Late this year, Twilio CEO Jeff Lawson told Wired that carriers<a href="http://www.wired.com/2014/12/fcc-sms/"> will start enforcing new fees and rules</a> on text companies like his. We expect the FCC to issue a ruling this year on whether or not carriers are entitled to any of the profit that comes with these messages.</p>
<p dir="ltr"><strong>Needless to say, 2015 is going to be a big year for business texting and the customer experience. What predictions do you have for the upcoming year? Let us know in the comments or text “2015” to 720-414-5269!</strong></p>
<p dir="ltr">Have a great New Year!</p>
<p>Photo from <a href="http://www.google.com/imgres?imgurl=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.marketing-mobile-interactif.fr%2Fwp-content%2Fuploads%2F2013%2F11%2Finfographie-SMS-en-France-2013-marketing-mobile-interactif-smartphone-2.jpg&amp;imgrefurl=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.marketing-mobile-interactif.fr%2F%3Fp%3D632&amp;docid=8wMDABwGkHl9fM&amp;tbnid=---Vk_yGR7zURM&amp;w=640&amp;h=304&amp;ei=5iekVK_2CImyogTvzILIBQ&amp;ved=0CAgQxiAwBg&amp;iact=c">Marketing Mobile Interactif</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/8-important-text-trends-of-2014-and-beyond/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Year End Review: Customer Service in 2014</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/year-end-review-customer-service-in-2014/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/year-end-review-customer-service-in-2014/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trends]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/year-end-review-customer-service-in-2014/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When you think of customer service in 2014, chances are the first thing your mind jumps to is the <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2014/08/11/comcast-customer-service-phone-call_n_5668191.html">horrific Comcast service call</a>. But 2014 was actually a great year for customer service: omnichannel service picked up steam, customers had more ways to solve problems than ever, and contact centers started implementing new, useful channels.</p>
<p><span id="more-7192"></span>OneReach CEO Rich Weborg discusses the introduction of channels like SMS support in his <a href="http://www.icmi.com/Resources/Strategy-and-Planning/2014/12/Year-End-Review-Service-Channels-of-the-Past-Present-and-Future">year end ICMI article</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>Historically, most businesses that support SMS use it for marketing or notification purposes only. However, with the emergence of toll-free SMS, <a href="http://onereachcontactcenter.com/sms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">business number texting</a>, SMS automation, text chat and business <a href="https://www.twilio.com/mms" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">MMS</a>, the concept of using text messaging for customer support is now a reality. While many organizations started to really consider SMS as a viable service channel, only the <a href="http://www.cityofevanston.org/news/2014/08/evanston-launches-improved-service-for-residents-to-text-the-city/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">early adopters</a> began to realize the benefits.</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Want to find out what 2015 will bring? <a href="http://www.icmi.com/Resources/Strategy-and-Planning/2014/12/Year-End-Review-Service-Channels-of-the-Past-Present-and-Future">Take a look at the rest of the article here</a>, and don’t forget to download our <a href="http://onereachcontactcenter.com/high-demand-for-customer-service-via-text-message/">free Harris interactive report </a>to learn more about how customer want service delivered.</p>
<p>Photo by Flickr user <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/garryknight/4659576761">Garry Knight</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/year-end-review-customer-service-in-2014/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
