<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>journal-popular &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<atom:link href="https://onereach.ai/tag/journal-popular/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<description>Intelligently Automate Your Company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 11:39:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/cropped-OR-ICON-GOLD-W-DOTS-Larger-Background-02-32x32.png</url>
	<title>journal-popular &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Forrester: 10% of U.S. jobs will be lost to automation in 2019</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/forrester_jobs/</link>
				<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 17:56:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Learning about AI and Bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OmniChannel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Phone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-popular]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-recent]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://onereach.ai/?p=5249</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Raconteur explores how bots are changing the role of Chief Financial Officers (CFO) and their corresponding departments [...]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">VentureBeat’s recent article on Forrester’s latest report on artificial intelligence brings up some interesting points. There is often talk of the gloom and doom that AI will bring on, especially in terms of eliminating key jobs through automation. There is no doubt that AI is going to have a massive impact on the way businesses operate, but what does this new future look like?</span></p>
<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-4588 size-large" src="https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-1024x725.jpg" alt="" width="1024" height="725" srcset="https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-1024x725.jpg 1024w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-300x212.jpg 300w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-768x543.jpg 768w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-150x106.jpg 150w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-600x425.jpg 600w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-900x637.jpg 900w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-20x13.jpg 20w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Robot-Woman-Sofija-Mitrovic-340x240.jpg 340w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p><b>The rise of digital workers</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Firstly, companies and startups alike are going to see an increase in digital workers created by robotic process automation (RPA) and AI. An increasing number of businesses are looking to scale at faster levels than before, and are going to be searching for solutions that can automate and optimize tasks traditionally done by humans. </span></p>
<p><b>Automation is all about giving and taking</b></p>
<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-2433 size-large" src="https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-1024x463.png" alt="" width="1024" height="463" srcset="https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-1024x463.png 1024w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-768x348.png 768w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-300x136.png 300w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-1200x544.png 1200w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-20x9.png 20w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-150x68.png 150w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-600x272.png 600w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai-900x407.png 900w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/huai.png 1202w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Automation tends to be associated with loss of jobs, and while this holds true in Forrester’s findings, that is not the whole story. 2019 will see roughly 10% of US jobs eliminated due to automation, but that same automation will also </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">create</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> about 3% of today’s jobs.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, this new increase in automation has bigger implications down the line. As companies begin to fully scale operations to keep up with the rest, it means the marketplace for AI solutions is going to be fiercely competitive. A Deloitte survey currently posits the annual global growth rate for AI-as-a-serve at 48.2%, with no signs of slowing down. This ripple effect then bleeds into other business areas, such as recruitment for AI talent, as businesses look for ways to retain their edge. Forrester’s survey posits that this search for talent will lead to “unprecedented job match success rates.”</span></p>
<p><b>Use cases you need to know about</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Forrester’s research points to four use cases wherein businesses see a real return on investment: </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Analytics that solve platform issues</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Chatbots integrated with RPA bots</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Internet-of-things (IoT) events that trigger “digital workers”</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Text analytics that organize unstructured data into “clean files” for RPA software.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Spot some commonalities? These use cases all point towards the future of AI &#8212; intelligent automation. Rather than strip away necessary jobs, AI is being used to free up employee time from rote tasks, and increase overall job satisfaction. These solutions are able to bridge the gap between menial tasks and human expertise, rather than limit the personal touch. According to the report, ML’s [machine learning] strength is data. Knowledge engineering’s strength is human wisdom. Used together, enterprises can dramatically accelerate the development of AI applications.</span><b>”</b></p>
<p>Read the full article <a href="https://venturebeat.com/2018/11/06/forrester-10-of-u-s-jobs-will-be-lost-to-automation-in-2019/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>WELCOME TO THE ERA OF THE AI COWORKER</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/welcome-to-the-era-of-the-ai-coworker/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 01:25:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-popular]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://onereach.ai/?p=4871</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>While far from a perfect replacement for humans, artificial intelligence is getting smarter. And fast. </strong></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In 2016, New York Times hailed Google’s new translator as “the great AI awakening,” a trend that has proven itself time and time again during 2017. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wireless headphones that can translate in 40 different languages? You can thank Google, again, for that. Although translation might seem one of the first industries at risk, the truth is that AI is planning a grand entrance to workplaces in a variety of niches. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And while it might not replace your job (yet), there’s a good chance you’ll be asked to embrace it with open arms as a co-worker. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Deemed to be “plucky young assistants on steroids”, the promise of AI for corporations looking to increase productivity while decreasing financial output (just to name a few reasons) is bright enough that you’ll need to put on your sunglasses, and soon. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What are the odds that AI coworkers will lead to workplace utopia, rather than leaving countless unemployed? Time will tell.</span></p>
<p><em>Read the <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/welcome-to-the-era-of-the-ai-coworker/?utm_source=ActiveCampaign&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_content=Issue+69%3A+Top+15+employers+of+AI+talent%2C+Google+launches+chatbot+analytics%2C+AI+beats+pathologists&amp;utm_campaign=Weekly+Newsletter+11+22+2017+Issue+69" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="color: #ff0000;">full article in Wired, here. </span></a></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Software 2.0 &#8211; Reinterpreting Software</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/software-2-0-reinterpreting-software/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:57:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Robb]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OmniChannel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Phone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SMS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Strategy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-popular]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-recent]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://onereach.ai/?p=4829</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><b><i>“If you think of neural networks as a software stack and not just a pretty good classifier, it becomes quickly apparent that they have a huge number of advantages and a lot of potential for transforming software in general.”</i></b></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Reinterpreting the way you understand neural networks will completely change the way you think of software. And, according to Andrej Karpathy, the Director of AI at Tesla, it’s for the best. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Coined “Software 2.0”, which is written by neural network weights rather than humans, these weights will not replace Software 1.0 (much to the relief of today’s coders). Instead, Software 2.0 will help to lighten the load, taking on tedious tasks involved in creating the software behind visual and speech recognition, speech synthesis, machine translation, robotics, and games. Karpathy’s argument for the numerous benefits of porting complex programs into Software 2.0, despite its recognized limitations, should be enough to convince any coder to accept this new age transition.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Read more <span style="color: #ff0000;"><a style="color: #ff0000;" href="https://medium.com/@karpathy/software-2-0-a64152b37c35" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a></span>.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Integrate Multiple Channels into a Single Seamless Experience</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/how-to-integrate-multiple-channels-into-a-single-seamless-experience/</link>
				<pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 15:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Robb]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-popular]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://onereach.ai/?p=4137</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Today, there are more ways than ever before to connect with your customers. As communication options have evolved and grown, customers have come to expect a seamless communication experience across channels.]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[Today, there are more ways than ever before to connect with your customers. As communication options have evolved and grown, customers have come to expect a seamless communication experience across channels.]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Your Mobile Strategy Isn’t Complete Without Text Messaging</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/why-your-mobile-strategy-isnt-complete-without-text-messaging/</link>
				<pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 15:29:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Robb]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-popular]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://onereach.ai/?p=4135</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[In today’s world, customer service is no longer restricted to a simple phone call. A recent report from Dimension Data [...]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>&#8220;Why Your Mobile Strategy Isn&#8217;t Complete Without Text Messaging&#8221;</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://onereach.com/img/resource_mobile_strategy_book.jpg" /></p>
<p>In today’s world, customer service is no longer restricted to a simple phone call. A recent report from Dimension Data found that digital interactions account for 35% of all contact center interactions. Digital interactions are also increasingly becoming mobile&#8211;Pew Research found that over 64% of American adults now own a smartphone, up from 35% in 2011.</p>
<p>To meet consumers’ demand for mobile and digital experiences, many businesses are developing apps. But while apps are a highly-used communication channel, the upfront cost and predominant use of gaming and social apps don’t justify the investment.</p>
<p>This is why texting is such an essential part of your mobile strategy. It’s fast, it can be professional but personal, it’s easy to use, it’s in real-time, it picks up where you left off, it connects to the Internet, etc. With texting, businesses can engage with customers on a channel they prefer, while keeping costs down and satisfaction up.</p>
<p>In this whitepaper, we’ll dive into:</p>
<ul>
<li>how and why people are using apps, and what that means for your business</li>
<li>why an app may not be the best channel to engage with customers</li>
<li>how texting fills in the gaps of an app-centric strategy</li>
<li>case studies of companies using texting to great success</li>
</ul>
<p><em><span style="color: #33cccc;"><a style="color: #33cccc;" href="https://onereach.com/resources/mobile-strategy" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Download the free whitepaper to <strong>read the complete findings</strong> and discover why businesses need to add texting to their mobile strategy.</a></span></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Harris Poll: Customers Prefer SMS Over Phone for Many Tasks, It’s Official.</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/harris-poll-customers-prefer-sms-over-phone-for-many-tasks-its-official/</link>
				<pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 15:28:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Robb]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-popular]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://onereach.ai/?p=4133</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[Historically, companies have incorporated texting into their business strategy for outbound marketing or reminder blasts, [...]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>&#8220;The High Demand for Customer Service via Text Message&#8221;</strong></p>
<p><img src="https://onereach.com/img/resource_highdemand_book.jpg" /></p>
<p>Historically, companies have incorporated texting into their business strategy for outbound marketing or reminder blasts, using short codes. However, this is not how people experience texting in their personal lives.</p>
<blockquote><p>64% of consumers with texting capabilities would <strong>prefer to use texting over voice</strong> as a customer service channel.</p></blockquote>
<p>One emerging customer service channel—texting via SMS—is turning out to be more important than previously thought. To find out exactly what customers would like most from the customer service text channel, Harris Interactive conducted a nation-wide survey of over 2000 adults on behalf of OneReach. Some key overall findings:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>64%</strong> of consumers with texting capabilities would <strong>prefer to use texting over voice</strong>as a customer service channel.</li>
<li><strong>44%</strong> of consumers with texting capabilities would <strong>prefer to press a button to initiate a text conversation immediately, rather than waiting on hold</strong> to speak with an agent.</li>
<li><strong>77%</strong> of consumers with texting capabilities aged 18-34 are likely to have a <strong>positive perception of a company that offers text capability</strong>.</li>
<li><strong>81%</strong> of all consumers agree that it is <strong>frustrating to be tied to a phone or computer to wait</strong> for customer service help.</li>
</ul>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="https://onereach.com/resources/high-demand-for-text-message-2014-report" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Download the free whitepaper to<strong> read the complete findings</strong> and discover why businesses need to take messaging channels seriously.</a></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amplifying Management With AI Implementation &#8211; PWC</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/amplifying-management-with-ai-implementation-pwc/</link>
				<pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 14:41:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Robb]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OmniChannel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Strategy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-popular]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-recent]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://onereach.ai/?p=4823</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>72% of business execs believe AI will be the business advantage of the future.</strong></p>
<p>Technology is great at interrupting the everyday norm, especially when it comes to business. But perhaps no other sector of business is in greater need of reinvention than management, which is tasked with the bulk of a company’s work.</p>
<p>In order to keep up with the demand, management teams are finding creative ways to implement AI, optimizing processes and making better use of their limited time. And, according to a Digital IQ survey done recently, it’s not just some management teams strategizing with AI, it’s more than half.</p>
<p>54% of business executives making “substantial investments” in AI today, and that number is only predicted to continue its rapid growth trend.</p>
<p>Among the AI innovations these execs are most excited to take advantage of are:</p>
<p>The ability to have full-time virtual personal assistants (31%)<br />
Automating data analysis (29%)<br />
Automating email communication and utilizing chatbots (28%)</p>
<p>By freeing up their time by allowing AI to take care of the most repetitive tasks, management executives can focus more on big ideas, helping their companies grow more rapidly and efficiently.</p>
<p>Read the full article <span style="color: #ff0000;"><a style="color: #ff0000;" href="http://pwcartificialintelligence.com/#amplifying-management" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a></span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>10 Questions Every Org. Must Consider If In The Race</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/10-questions-every-organization-should-consider-when-competing-in-the-race-to-ai-adoption/</link>
				<pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 12:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Robb]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OmniChannel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SMS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Strategy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-popular]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://onereach.ai/?p=4678</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[In order to understand the importance of chatbots and voice bots in today’s business world, you first have to note the context [...]]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In order to understand the importance of chatbots and voice bots in today’s business world, you first have to note the context in which they are being created. Despite the illusion of complexity, both types of bots are just software operating on an interface. And that interface also isn’t anything new; it’s actually the first interfaced used by humans: language. Built in to our cognitive development as humans, language is very much a part of who we are. Bots, then, aren’t creating something new. Instead, they’re simply finding a new way to do what we as humans have done for millenniums.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At the heart of the chatbot and voice bot revolution is the desire (and capacity) for using language to communicate with computers. The ability to do this means that we can actually train computers to not just understand, but also create, language, giving them the ability to tap into the interface we know so well.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In order for future bot experiences to be successful, they must be well-versed in the human language.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">How do they acquire these skills?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Through the training we give to them.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While it would be plausible for the opposite to take place (us training ourselves to talk to computers, aka coding), it’s a much better user experience for computers to learn to speak to us via our language.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This, then, brings us to the 10 business, design and technology questions that everyone should explore before setting out to build bots or create other AI solutions. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You’re already past questions like “how do bots and AI work?”, “what can they do for my organization?” and “should my organization make a bot?”. You already know that stuff, and likely the last thing you need is more marketing and sales pitches peddling bots and AI as the magic answer. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Whether you’re looking to make your existing stuff more awesome or you&#8217;re just getting started on your first AI and bot-stuffs, we think that you’ll be glad for the questions and answers our customers came across through many years of bot-building and AI problem solving.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/10-Questions-To-Consider-About-Your-AI-1.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-4685 size-full" src="https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/10-Questions-To-Consider-About-Your-AI-1.jpg" alt="" width="2081" height="1166" srcset="https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/10-Questions-To-Consider-About-Your-AI-1.jpg 2081w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/10-Questions-To-Consider-About-Your-AI-1-300x168.jpg 300w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/10-Questions-To-Consider-About-Your-AI-1-768x430.jpg 768w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/10-Questions-To-Consider-About-Your-AI-1-1024x574.jpg 1024w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/10-Questions-To-Consider-About-Your-AI-1-20x11.jpg 20w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/10-Questions-To-Consider-About-Your-AI-1-150x84.jpg 150w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/10-Questions-To-Consider-About-Your-AI-1-600x336.jpg 600w, https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/10-Questions-To-Consider-About-Your-AI-1-900x504.jpg 900w" sizes="(max-width: 2081px) 100vw, 2081px" /></a></span></p>
<p><strong>Here are 10 questions that everyone should explore before/during building bots and AI solutions.</strong></p>
<ol>
<li><b>How can I future-proof my bot’s design, development and management? <i><span style="font-weight: 200;">Now this may seem like an advanced question, and it is, but in order to save yourself and your organization lots of painful time and money, we’re going to get you thinking about it early. There’s no better way to get thinking about it than to get some important questions stuck in the back of your head &#8211; try your best to keep running through them as you’re working through building great bot experiences. </span></i></b>
<ul>
<li><b>How c</b><b>an I avoid betting early on AI platforms without missing early payouts or stifling progress?</b> <i><span style="font-weight: 200;">Wow &#8211; that’s a doozy. There’s a lot of action in the AI space right now and a lot of money getting poured into it by all sorts of companies that want you to bet on them. If you’re like us, you might feel a bit like it’s too early to bet on investing in one particular platform like a Watson, Google’s API.ai, Luis, etc, etc. Pick one? Seems like a tough bet. So we subscribe to not picking one &#8211; instead AB test them all and see which one is best for each pieces of the puzzle, knowing that they’ll all continue to change.</span></i></li>
<li><b>What do I need to know in order to avoid super-gluing myself to platforms, providers and languages that might not be future-proof? <i><span style="font-weight: 200;">We’ve learned how important this question becomes to all of our customers by seeing how painful it can be to change platforms, providers and languages mid-flight &#8211; maybe your SMS provider gets too expensive or your understandably weary of building a solution on a proprietary language that’s only usable on one platform &#8211; like Twilio or Nexmo, etc. </span></i></b></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<ol>
<li style="list-style-type: none;">
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 200;"><span style="font-weight: 200;">How could reporting hold my bot back from it’s class, and how can I break the shackles early or avoid them altogether?</span></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li style="font-weight: 200;"><strong>Do I just want AI, or do I need AI?</strong></li>
<li style="font-weight: 200;"><strong>What’s the right channel(s) for my bot, and how can I build my bot to be as scalable as possible to other channels?</strong></li>
<li style="font-weight: 200;"><strong>Is my bot trained to do the right things and report on the right things, in the right ways for the right people? &#8211; What’s the scope and for who?</strong></li>
<li style="font-weight: 200;"><strong>What should my bot say if it doesn’t understand somebody’s intent and why does that question matter so much?</strong></li>
<li style="font-weight: 200;"><strong>What am I doing to make sure my bot’s integrations and 3rd party connectivity scalable and interchangeable?</strong></li>
<li style="font-weight: 200;"><strong>What’s appropriate for bots and what’s not, and where does my bot fall on the line? </strong></li>
<li style="font-weight: 200;"><strong>What do I need to consider when designing hand-offs from my bot to a human?</strong></li>
<li style="font-weight: 200;"><strong>How can I be sure I’m incorporating graceful failure into the experience my bot offers?</strong></li>
<li style="font-weight: 200;"><strong>What can I do to ensure my bot is developed in ways that don’t eternally hand-cuff me to it’s management, iterations and reporting?</strong></li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>The High Demand for Customer Service via Text Message</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/the-high-demand-for-customer-service-via-text-message/</link>
				<pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 12:27:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Robb]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal-popular]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://onereach.ai/?p=4131</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[One emerging customer service channel—texting via SMS—is turning out to be more important than previously thought. To find out exactly what customer. . [..]
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[One emerging customer service channel—texting via SMS—is turning out to be more important than previously thought. To find out exactly what customer. . [..]
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
