<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Self-Service &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<atom:link href="https://onereach.ai/category/self-service/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<description>Intelligently Automate Your Company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 11:39:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/cropped-OR-ICON-GOLD-W-DOTS-Larger-Background-02-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Self-Service &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Weekly Review: 06/19</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/weekly-review-06-19/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/weekly-review-06-19/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Communication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Satisfaction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OmniChannel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Self-Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best way to improve customer service]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/weekly-review-06-19/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Happy Friday! Here’s our picks for the best customer service, customer experience, bot and mobile articles of the week, in no particular order.</p>
<h2><span id="more-7438"></span></h2>
<h2><span style="font-size: x-large;"><a href="http://customerthink.com/customer-centricity-is-more-than-promotional-hype/">Customer-Centricity is more than Promotional Hype</a> &#8211; by Mitchell Goozé</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-size: medium;">How do companies drive emotional engagement and guarantee they are fully committed to the needs of the customer? According to this article, centricity is key. Providing better customer service will ultimately end up in more profit, which is almost always the end goal for companies. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-size: x-large;"><a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/ibm/2016/06/20/how-to-architect-a-cognitive-future-for-business/#305197e0b173">How to Architect a Cognitive Future for Business </a> &#8211; by <a href="http://@TomRosamilia">Tom Rosamilia</a></span></h2>
<p>Many businesses are looking at the wide-spread possibilities of artificial intelligence to redefine their industries, businesses and customers. Business leaders are embracing artificial intelligence because consumers are using cognitive applications through phones and in their cars, creating better customer engagement.</p>
<h2><span style="font-size: x-large;"><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2016/06/21/the-hidden-risks-of-the-bot-explosion/">The Hidden Risks of the Bot Explosion</a>&#8211; by <a href="http://@JenniferLSnell">Jennifer Snell</a> </span></h2>
<p>Whenever something new is introduced people are naturally skeptical about jumping into it. Building trust between humans and machines is very important and, like any relationship, takes time. People will only trust their bots if they trust the makers of their bots. At OneReach we want to make sure customers trust that we’re acting responsibly behind the curtain, and that we value the significance of their customer experience.</p>
<h2><span style="font-size: x-large;"><a href="http://customerthink.com/you-machines-and-the-future-of-customer-service/">You, Machines, and the Future of Customer Service</a>&#8211; by <a href="http://@jtwatkin">Jeremy Watkin </a></span></h2>
<p>The newest technologies have an amazing capacity to make customer service more effective. Knowing that 40% of customers prefer to handle issues on their own, technology can reduce the effort put forth in order to get their issues resolved.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>To learn more about providing a great customer experience across channels, <a href="https://onereach.com/resources/omnichannel-seamless-experience">download our whitepaper here</a>.</strong></p>
<h2></h2>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/weekly-review-06-19/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Reasons Why Your Customer Service Should Include Chatbots</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/5-reasons-why-your-customer-service-should-include-chatbots/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/5-reasons-why-your-customer-service-should-include-chatbots/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Communication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Live Chat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Self-Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/5-reasons-why-your-customer-service-should-include-chatbots/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It’s an exciting time to be involved the customer service and communications space. There are more ways to interact with a brand than ever before (email, Twitter, even Snapchat), but one of the most new and exciting advancements is chatbots.</p>
<p><span id="more-7420"></span>In a recent article, The Guardian described chatbots as:</p>
<blockquote><p>“Chat bots are computer programs that mimic conversation with people using artificial intelligence. They can transform the way you interact with the internet from a series of self-initiated tasks to a quasi-conversation.”</p></blockquote>
<p>In the customer service space, chatbots are using the growing power of artificial intelligence to allow customers to interact with a brand as they would with a customer service representative. However, there are some marked benefits to managing conversations with chatbots. Read on to find out why.</p>
<h2><strong>Chatbots are where the market is trending. </strong></h2>
<p>Last year, Uber’s director of experience Chris Messina wrote a post hailing the rise of something he called <a href="https://medium.com/chris-messina/2016-will-be-the-year-of-conversational-commerce-1586e85e3991#.jzhm93htd">conversational commerce</a>. He described it as:</p>
<blockquote><p>“Utilizing chat, messaging, or other natural language interfaces (i.e. voice) to interact with people, brands, or services and bots that heretofore have had no real place in the bidirectional, asynchronous messaging context.”</p></blockquote>
<p>His vision of conversational commerce has come to fruition this year with the exciting and not unrelated rise of bots. Messaging platforms like Facebook Messenger and Kik recently doubled down on chatbots, rolling out their own bot stores where developers can go in and code their own conversational chatbots.</p>
<p>While initial reaction to the chatbots has been somewhat lukewarm (their ability to handle natural language leaves something to be desired), we have to remember we’re just at the beginning of a very exciting evolution of B2C communications. In fact, Gartner made a prediction a few years back that by 2020, <a href="http://mktimages.gartner.com/pv_obj_cache/pv_obj_id_92DB197B681D1A1003F701CB30B626FF3B111B00/filename/brochure_crm_2011.pdf">85% of customer interactions</a> would be managed without a human. The rise of chatbots dovetails nicely into this prediction.</p>
<h2><strong>Customers are open to the idea of chatbots.</strong></h2>
<p>While there’s still something to be said for a human touch in customer service, research has shown that 40% of <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/stevenvanbelleghem/the-self-serving-economy">customers prefer self-service</a>. In addition, Zendesk found that <a href="http://cdn.zendesk.com/resources/whitepapers/Omnichannel-Customer-Service-Gap.pdf">over 50% of customers</a> think it’s important that they can solve their problems themselves without having to rely on customer service agents.</p>
<p>Customers are also interested in interacting with your business over messaging (and already are). <a href="https://onereach.com/resources/high-demand-for-text-message-2014-report">A study</a> conducted by Harris Poll and commissioned by OneReach found that 64% of customers would rather text than call your business, and insights released during the <a href="http://www.edelman.com/83621/2016/04/15/facebook-messenger-for-business-brands-chatbots/">recent F8 Conference</a> showed that more than one billion messages are sent to businesses each month.</p>
<p>Combine the two approaches (self-service and texting/messaging) and you arrive at chatbots. Chatbots leverage a channel that customers are already using (texting/messaging) and blend it with their desire for a self-service experience.</p>
<h2><strong>Chatbots are cheaper and faster than live agents.</strong></h2>
<p>We’ve talked before about how much cheaper an automated interaction is compared to a live agent interaction (25 cents vs. $6-20). But in addition to being cheaper than live agents, chatbots are also an efficient way to deliver customer service—customers can type in their question and get a response back almost immediately based on pre-programmed logic.</p>
<p>For instance, I recently tried out Spring, one of the first Facebook Messenger bots to go public. It asked me if I wanted women’s or men’s items, then asked what kind of clothing I was looking for, all in rapid succession. Soon I was scrolling through results quickly and easily.<img class="aligncenter wp-image-2601 size-medium" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/chatbots2-250x300.png" alt="chatbots2" width="250" height="300" /></p>
<p>Just like with Spring, most people will and are using chatbots for simple requests (getting a ride via Uber, ordering flowers, etc.), but sometimes customers may have more complex queries than the bot can understand. Going back to the Spring example, I found a cardigan I liked (it’s still kind of chilly in Denver, okay?) but wanted to know if they had it in a different color. When I asked the chatbot if they had it in white, the bot kindly told me they’d get back to me soon with an answer.<br />
<img class="wp-image-2600 size-medium aligncenter" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/chatbots-250x300.png" alt="chatbots" width="250" height="300" /></p>
<p>By pivoting to a conversation with a live agent from within the bot conversation, you can ensure that every customer has a great experience.</p>
<h2><strong>Chatbots can incorporate visual media.</strong></h2>
<p>Humans are very visual creatures—in fact, <a href="http://info.shiftelearning.com/blog/bid/350326/Studies-Confirm-the-Power-of-Visuals-in-eLearning">we process images 60,000 times faster</a> than we do text. Images are a quick and easy way to communicate information, so that’s why it’s great that chatbots can incorporate rich media like picture and GIFs into conversation. While chatbots primarily communicate through text, images can help chatbots seem more human or showcase a product that’s easier to display than describe.</p>
<p>When I was talking with the Spring bot, once I had determined what types of products I was looking for, it pulled up a few options that I could click on and expand to get more information. There was also the option to add in images and GIFs on my end, and while the chatbot itself didn’t add in an image, I think it could have benefitted the interaction quite a bit and made it seem a little more human.</p>
<h2><strong>It’s almost indistinguishable from a human (when written correctly).</strong></h2>
<p>Your worst fear about chatbots might be that they deliver a clunky, robotic user experience (or, on a more existential level, that they’re coming for all of us and our jobs). However, bots can actually deliver a really seamless, natural human experience when written correctly.</p>
<p>It really depends on what your brand’s voice is, though. If you’re a more informal brand, using slang and casual language (“like,” “love,” etc.) and referring to your brand as “we” or “I” will work well. If you’re a more formal brand, referring to yourself in third person and dropping the slang is probably a better bet.</p>
<p>Spring was more informal, so when the chatbot greeted me with “Hey there!” and referred to itself as “We,” it sounded pretty similar to a human. I almost couldn’t tell the difference between the bot’s responses (left) and the human’s responses (right) when they stepped in.<br />
<img class="size-large wp-image-2607 aligncenter" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/chatbots5-546x308.png" alt="chatbots" width="546" height="308" /></p>
<h2><strong>Conclusion</strong></h2>
<p>Brands are increasingly receptive to using chatbots in their B2C communications. While we’ll have to wait a little bit to see how the chatbot wave plays out over the next few months, early responses and clear benefits just might indicate the rise of chatbots in customer service.</p>
<p><strong>To learn more about providing a great experience across channels, <a href="https://onereach.com/resources/omnichannel-seamless-experience">download our whitepaper here</a>.</strong></p>
<p>Image of <a href="https://www.pexels.com/photo/smartphone-technology-typing-person-7395/">person typing</a> courtesy of Pexels. CC0 License.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/5-reasons-why-your-customer-service-should-include-chatbots/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why AI Is Well-Suited for Business Communications</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/why-ai-is-well-suited-for-business-communications/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/why-ai-is-well-suited-for-business-communications/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Communication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Self-Service]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/why-ai-is-well-suited-for-business-communications/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong> </strong>Business communications have traditionally been person to person—someone answers the phone, sends an email, etc. But in recent years, business communications have started incorporating automation in their IVRs, live chats and call routing. In fact, 53.6% of contact centers today use IVRs.</p>
<p>However, some businesses have moved beyond using automation in their business communications—they’re using artificial intelligence. Take <a href="https://slack.com/">Slack</a>, for instance. The popular collaboration platform uses bots to onboard users and <a href="http://www.wired.com/2015/08/slack-overrun-bots-friendly-wonderful-bots/">interact with them for a variety of reasons</a>. <a href="https://www.narrativescience.com/">Narrative Science</a>, the natural language generation platform, uses artificial intelligence to draft reports that read just like a human-written report would.</p>
<p><span id="more-7413"></span>These companies are doing extremely well using artificial intelligence for communications, but why? Part of it could be attributed to the fact that AI is well-suited for business communications. AI can process natural language and integrate with other platforms, all while saving your business money.</p>
<p>Here are six reasons why AI and business communications are a great match.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>AI can process natural language. </strong>Whenever you call into an IVR, you either type in your input or say a word or two to be directed to the next menu option. But what if the system could understand you without you having to speak with stilted dialogue? With AI, callers can talk or type as they normally would and natural language processing can decipher it, leading to an overall better customer experience.</li>
<li><strong>It can help your business be brand compliant. </strong>We’ve all heard of the infamous instances when a contact center agent loses their temper with a customer and calls them a bad name or refuses to let them out of their contract. With AI, your business can circumvent those uncomfortable situations by preprogramming responses to certain keywords, phrases or scenarios. (Just make sure your AI is programmed to be friendly in all scenarios, and learn from Microsoft’s Tay malfunction).</li>
<li><strong>It’s cheaper than live agent interactions but doesn’t replace them. </strong>A typical phone call costs $6-20 per interaction, but an automated interaction, one managed by AI, only costs 25 cents. That’s not to say it should replace live agent interactions—far from it. In fact, AI can learn from live agent interactions and then provide them with the most common solution based on customer input.</li>
<li><strong>It’s something customers want. </strong>Over 40% of customers would rather use self-service than talk to a live agent. AI is a natural extension of self-service. By adding AI to your business communications, your company can help customers self-serve across channels, and, as mentioned above, let them communicate as they normally would.</li>
<li><strong>It’s easy to integrate with other platforms for increased functionality. </strong>AI isn’t hard to implement and add on to. For instance, IBM Watson lets you integrate AI into your own communication solution. Alternatively, you can find a solution that already includes AI. Integrating your AI-powered communication solution with other platforms means your business can deliver more personalized, intelligent service.</li>
<li><strong>AI can help your business be more efficient. </strong>AI is great for handling lots of data, which is why it can be used to handle a lot of common customer inquiries while agents focus on more complex tasks. In both cases, your business ends up making happier customers—they’re getting served quicker via AI, or getting their issue solved more in-depth with help from an agent.</li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>So how can you add AI to your business communications? </strong></h2>
<p>The best way to start introducing AI into your business communications is through messaging. But why messaging? Let angel investor and prolific author <a href="http://www.nirandfar.com/2015/07/the-message-is-the-medium-3-reasons-apps-as-assistants-work.html">Nir Eyal</a> explain:</p>
<blockquote><p>With text, there are no voice intonations to decipher or accents to understand, no facial gestures to interpret, and no body language to translate. Text is something computers can understand and process quickly and it’s why messaging is a great place for humans and A.I. to work together to serve customer needs.</p></blockquote>
<p>While you can use AI for both voice and text interactions, starting with a medium that AI can understand means your business can have artificial intelligence implemented sooner rather than later. This means your costs will also start to decrease as well, since text communications are cheaper than voice communications, as mentioned above.</p>
<h2><strong>Conclusion</strong></h2>
<p>If there was any time to add AI to your business communications, it’s now. Venture capitalists invested more than $300 million in <a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2015-02-03/i-ll-be-back-the-return-of-artificial-intelligence">AI startups</a> in 2014, a 300% increase over 2013. AI is a growing presence in business communications—will it be part of yours?</p>
<p>Image of <a href="https://pixabay.com/en/phone-technology-work-mobile-869669/">phone technology</a> courtesy of Foundry via Pixabay. CC0 License.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/why-ai-is-well-suited-for-business-communications/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Your Business Needs a Bot</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/why-your-business-needs-a-bot/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/why-your-business-needs-a-bot/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Big Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Self-Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/why-your-business-needs-a-bot/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Both technological capabilities and consumer preferences are evolving faster than ever before, which amplifies the challenge organizations have as they attempt to establish and maintain competitive advantage. It is not surprising, then, that organizations of all sizes are struggling to adopt artificial intelligence and weave it into a comprehensive consumer engagement strategy.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The promise of artificial intelligence (AI) is compelling; a world where humans can interact with intelligent computers to perform tasks more efficiently. While 2016 may not be the year the promise of AI is fully realized, it is certainly the year that it becomes an integral part of  communication strategies for leading organizations. In fact, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">these emerging capabilities are increasingly being applied to business.</span></p>
<p><span id="more-7396"></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">IBM Watson, for example, is incorporating its machine learning offerings into healthcare, finance and education. With a conversational nature and vast knowledge base, AI is a natural fit for business. It’s such a good fit, in fact, that it’s slowly rendering the apps businesses have focused on over the past few years obsolete.</span></p>
<h2><b>An interface out of place</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For the past few years, businesses have relied on mobile apps to interact with their customers, and it’s not hard to see why. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But mobile apps aren’t always going to be the best channel to engage with customers. Getting your customers to download your </span><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2016/1/6/10718282/internet-bots-messaging-slack-facebook-m"><span style="font-weight: 400;">application</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is expensive (averaging $4.73 per installation). In addition, getting your customers to keep your mobile application on their phone is difficult: Despite the fact that every day over 50 million mobile apps are downloaded, </span><a href="http://www.nuance.com/ucmprod/groups/enterprise/@web-enus/documents/collateral/nc_020218.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">95% are abandoned</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> within a month. Finally, getting your customers to use your mobile application more than once is difficult: </span><a href="https://info.dynatrace.com/rs/compuware/images/Mobile_App_Survey_Report.pdf"><span style="font-weight: 400;">79% of consumers</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> will only retry an app once or twice before abandoning it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With most apps touting different user interfaces and functions, it’s no surprise that messaging apps have surged to the forefront of the app market. Their simplicity and ease of conversation, not to mention free or low cost communication, attracts users the world over (six out of 10 of the top global mobile apps are </span><a href="http://www.slideshare.net/kleinerperkins/internet-trends-v1/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">messaging apps</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">). But keep in mind that native text messaging (SMS) lays claim as the most adopted and frequently used feature on a phone, according to <a href="http://www.pewinternet.org/2015/04/01/us-smartphone-use-in-2015/#smartphones">Pew Research</a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Given the landscape outline above, some key questions emerge. Where does artificial intelligence come into play? What are the best channels to introduce AI? Why is it that mobile applications and websites aren’t enough anymore to have a complete mobile strategy?</span></p>
<h2><b>Enter the age of the chat bot.</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now you might be asking yourself, &#8220;What is a bot?&#8221; Truthfully, there are many definitions. Many will wait to see what </span><a href="https://www.facebook.com/zuck/posts/10102577175875681"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mark Zuckerberg</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> comes up with. But for the sake of this article we’ll focus on chatbots,  an evolution beyond the traditional virtual assistant. A chat bot is an automated communication tool that can process natural language via text message (SMS, Facebook Message, etc.) and </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">actually transact. </span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">2016 is the beginning of the post-graphical, pre-voice UI era (more on this to come), where text-based messaging is all you need to book a flight, make dinner reservations, or check to see if your local coffee shop has any of that espresso that you really like. And best of all, the messaging experience can be powered by artificially intelligent chat bots that can process natural language inputs and actually transact.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But this brings a  few key questions come to mind:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">What if you could engage with your customers on an application they </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">already have?</span></i></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">What if you could engage with your customers on the application </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">they use the most?</span></i></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">What if you could engage with your customers on a channel where artificial intelligence is </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">real</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">accessible to you today?</span></i></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can, and you can do it through text messaging. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to Pew Research, texting is the most-used “app” on a smartphone, with 97% of respondents reporting that they used it at least once a day. From a business standpoint, texting platforms can also leverage integrations, such as those of artificial intelligence, to provide a personalized, more intelligent customer experiences. Texting is the first natural step for companies seeking to add AI to their business communications and be the proprietors of an intelligently automated customer experience.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is extremely important, because currently, companies like </span><a href="http://getmagicnow.com"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Magic</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> are making it possible for </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">your customers</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> give their business to who Magic thinks is best. </span><a href="http://www.wired.com/2015/08/facebook-launches-m-new-kind-virtual-assistant/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Facebook M</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is allowing </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">your customers</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to conduct commerce over Facebook Messenger. As a business owner, you should be asking, </span><b>“What role does my company play in these transactions?”</b><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><b>“How can I let my customers engage with us in the same way, </b><b><i>or better</i></b><b>?&#8221;</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Why rely on third-party solutions that allow customers to communicate with them over their channel of choice (messaging), when you could let your customers communicate in the same way directly with you? This is why your company needs a chat bot; so your customers can communicate and transact with you the way they want to without having to go through a third-party.</span></p>
<h2><b>&#8220;This sounds really complicated.&#8221;</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Think of building a chat bot as an exercise in composition, rather than development. Your company likely has many APIs that are already being used to power your mobile applications and internal tools. By using these existing APIs (both your internal ones and the ones offered by your existing software partners such as Salesforce, Stripe, etc.) in conjunction with powerful artificial intelligence services (such as IBM Watson), you have the technological bases covered. Think of SMS (or any messaging app) as just another interface to many of the features that you’ve already made available through other applications. Often times this ‘conversational UI’ is simply allowing you to get more value from the APIs that you’ve already built. </span></p>
<h2><b>Conclusion</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s not hard to get started with a chat bot&#8211;far from it. To get going, combine those various services you’ll need (AI, payment, communication) using a platform that allows you to iterate and pilot rapidly&#8211;preferably with a visual design tool. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The timing for chat bots is now. Businesses are just starting to realize their value, and the technology has been around long enough to reduce risk.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The only question that remains is:</span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">“What are you waiting for?”</span></em></p>
<p><strong>To learn more about providing a great customer experience through text messaging, <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/mobile-strategy">download our whitepaper here</a>.</strong></p>
<p>Image of <a href="https://pixabay.com/en/woman-artificial-intelligence-506322/">woman artificial intelligence</a> courtesy of Pixabay. CC0 License.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/why-your-business-needs-a-bot/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Lessons Learned from Customer Service Failures</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/5-lessons-learned-from-customer-service-failures/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/5-lessons-learned-from-customer-service-failures/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Customer Experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gripes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guest Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Self-Service]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/5-lessons-learned-from-customer-service-failures/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This guest post is written by Erica Strother Marois, the Community Specialist at <a href="http://www.icmi.com">ICMI</a>. </em></p>
<p>We’ve all been on the receiving end of poor customer service. Long wait times, annoying IVRs, unforgiving return policies, and a lack of channel options can all be maddening. And inevitably, these frustrations spill over to the front line employees. Customer service is more complex and stressful than ever, and ICMI research indicates that <a href="http://www.icmi.com/Resources/Research/2015-Smarter-Service-for-the-Connected-Consumer">the industry</a> is only growing more complicated.</p>
<p>What can customer service leaders do to alleviate stress and improve the customer experience? To answer that, we turn to some of the most infamous customer service failures in recent history. (After all, some of the best insight comes from the biggest failures).</p>
<p><span id="more-7385"></span>Here are five lessons learned from headline-grabbing customer service failures:</p>
<h2><strong>1. Sometimes customers are wrong. Make it easier for them to be right.</strong></h2>
<p>“The customer is always right.” It’s a quote that business professionals have recited for years, but <em>is</em> the customer always right? Or is the customer ever to blame for poor service?</p>
<p>Remember the Maine Diner that kicked a customer out of her restaurant last summer? The customer’s child was disruptive, so she asked them to leave. Who was right? Plenty of people actually sided with the owner.</p>
<p>And remember this controversial <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/matt-walsh/bad-customer-service_b_3799574.html">Huffington Post article from 2013</a>?</p>
<p>Honestly, the customer isn’t always right. But it’s our job to treat them like they are. And even more importantly, it’s our job to make it easier for them to be right.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-2414 size-full" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/erica-blog-post-1.png" alt="customer service failures" width="542" height="191" /></p>
<p>Are your customers calling the wrong line for service? Perhaps your customers are angry about late fees imposed on their account? Think about what you could do to prevent the situation from ever taking place.  Could you improve your website? Could you send text reminders to let your customers know their bill due date is approaching? In the case of that Maine diner—should the owner offer snacks and coloring books for young children? Perhaps a kid-friendly seating section?</p>
<p>Sure—customers are wrong sometimes, but that shouldn’t change their experience, or your company’s approach to service.</p>
<h2><strong>2. Taking ownership doesn’t mean taking blame.</strong></h2>
<p>It’s human nature to be defensive. No one enjoys being wrong. Unfortunately, defensiveness doesn’t solve problems. When it comes to customer interactions, it’s essential to take ownership when situations don’t go as planned. This doesn’t always mean falling on the sword and taking all the blame, it means taking responsibility for making the situation right. It also means listening—<em>really listening</em>—to your customers and looking for the lesson in their feedback. Help your customers regain confidence in your company by taking control of the situation, making it right, and preventing future problems.</p>
<p>View feedback as a gift, not a burden.  Don’t discourage your customers from sharing how they feel, or offering their tips for improvement. And certainly never approach customer feedback the way <a href="http://www.cnn.com/2014/08/04/travel/bad-hotel-review-fine-backlash/">this hotel</a> did.</p>
<h2><strong>3. Customer service is a tough job.</strong></h2>
<p>Remember the <a href="https://www.thedijuliusgroup.com/blog/2014/taco-bell-employee-shoots-unhappy-customer-frontier-pilot-buys-pizzas-for-all-passengers/646/">fast food employee</a> who in a fit of frustration <em>shot</em> a customer? Thankfully the customer was okay, but how did the situation escalate to that point?</p>
<p>Dealing with angry customers isn’t pleasant or easy. And while it’s never acceptable for an agent or employee to behave unprofessionally, it’s important to acknowledge the challenging nature of customer interactions. It’s impossible to prevent a problem if you don’t admit it exists. Show your employees that you know how tough their job is, and take steps to alleviate some of the stress.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-2415 size-full" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/erica-blog-post-2.png" alt="customer service failures" width="491" height="239" /></p>
<p>Offer on-site yoga classes. Dedicate a room for quiet meditation. Give your agents stress balls, or adult coloring books for breaks.</p>
<p>More importantly, arm your employees with the training and tools needed to tackle difficult situations. Consider difficult customer interactions as learning moments. Bring recordings or transcripts of heated exchanges to group training sessions, and ask team members how they’d respond in a similar situation.  Role play. Help agents prepare for the worst, and they’ll feel more comfortable and confident when a difficult call comes their way.</p>
<h2><strong>4. Don’t forget the human touch.</strong></h2>
<p>An expectation of 24/7 service, in a customer’s language and channel of choice is no longer uncommon. To meet these rising expectations, many companies have relied on automation to close the gap. While there are certainly instances when automation can be effective, remember that customer service is still a people business. Forgetting the human touch causes your company to feel unauthentic, and that can lead to less loyal customers. This is especially true in service channels such as social media that are supposed to be (you guessed it) <em>social</em>.</p>
<p>Case in point: a few months ago, a well-known telecommunications provider crashed ICMI’s weekly Twitter chat.  Awesome, right? Encouraging to witness a respected brand listening to their customers on social media, huh? Not exactly. It quickly became glaringly obvious that we were dealing with bots—and not the intelligent type.  You can read more about the entire exchange by checking out this <a href="http://www.toistersolutions.com/blog/2015/10/28/automation-fail-how-attcares-stumbled-into-a-tweet-chat">blog post by Jeff Toister</a>.  Spoiler alert: this company has become a running joke in the <a href="http://www.icmi.com/forums/forum1005-icmichat-forum.aspx">#ICMIchat community</a>, and serves as a prime example of how <em>not</em> to handle automated customer service.</p>
<h2><strong>5. Give your agents the freedom to make things right.</strong></h2>
<p>Just like scripts, policies can be used as a helpful guide for serving customers. Setting expectations makes the experience more positive for both customers and agents. But remember there are times when every rule must be broken.  Rigid policies can often make an employee’s job even harder, so it’s critical to empower your employees. Give them the freedom to exercise common sense and bend the rules when needed.</p>
<p>For example, imagine you work in a hotel. A distressed (and naked) customer shows up at the front desk. He’s been locked out of his room and needs help getting back in. You ask for his ID, but it’s in his room (which he’s locked out of). According to hotel policy, you’re only allowed to issue a new key to customers who are able to show photo identification. How would you handle this situation? This happened several months ago, and due to the <a href="http://news.yahoo.com/video/naked-guy-gets-locked-hotel-150253974.html">strict hotel policy</a> the employee wasn’t able to help the guest in the best way possible.</p>
<p>Rules and guidelines are valuable, yes.  But teaching your employees how to determine when to break the rules is even more valuable. Don’t let policies leave your customers feeling like a number instead of a valued guest.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter wp-image-2416 size-full" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/erica-blog-post-3.png" alt="customer service failures" width="493" height="175" /></p>
<p>Has your business learned any lessons from customer service gone wrong? Have you as a customer been on the receiving end of a customer service hall of shame moment? Share your experiences in the comments below! Let’s all remember to embrace the insight that comes from service failures!</p>
<h2><strong>About the Author</strong></h2>
<p>Erica Strother Marois is the Community Specialist at <a href="http://www.icmi.com">ICMI</a>. In her role at ICMI she hosts and plans the weekly #ICMIchat twitter chat, manages a robust network of contact center writers and speakers, and produces the weekly <em>Contact Center Insider Newsletter</em>. Erica is a connecter of people, and loves being a part of the contact center community.</p>
<p>Connect with Erica:  Twitter: <a href="https://twitter.com/ens0204">@ens0204 </a> |  LinkedIn: <a href="http://linkd.in/16kW2cj">http://linkd.in/16kW2cj</a>  | Google+: <a href="http://bit.ly/1zkp9YS">http://bit.ly/1zkp9YS</a>   | Email: <a href="mailto:estrother@icmi.com">estrother@icmi.com</a></p>
<p>Image of boy facepalm by <a href="https://pixabay.com/en/boy-facepalm-child-youth-666803/">mintchipdesigns</a>. CC0 license. Edited.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/5-lessons-learned-from-customer-service-failures/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Year End Review: Customer Service Trends in 2015 and Beyond</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/year-end-review-customer-service-trends-in-2015-and-beyond/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/year-end-review-customer-service-trends-in-2015-and-beyond/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Big Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Communication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Contact Center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Self-Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trends]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/year-end-review-customer-service-trends-in-2015-and-beyond/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As we look back on 2015, it’s tempting to refer to that age-old adage: “The more things change, the more things stay the same.”</p>
<p>This year, that couldn’t be further from the truth.</p>
<p>That’s because 2015 was the year the technology really made its presence known in customer service. Automation, artificial intelligence, social media, CRM integrations, texting&#8211;all were major customer service trends in 2015.</p>
<h2><span id="more-7370"></span><strong>Customer Service Trends in 2015</strong></h2>
<p>2015 was the year that:</p>
<p><strong>Customer service got smart.</strong> This year, artificial intelligence wasn’t just limited to the realms of science fiction a la Age of Ultron—it was also slowly incorporated into different companies’ service offerings. Amazon made its entry into the home automation market with Alexa, a virtual assistant that can field questions ranging from the time of day to traffic predictions to good restaurants nearby. On the enterprise-level side, IBM continued to expand the capabilities of Jeopardy-winning Watson, adding self-service into varied industries like healthcare, education and finance, among others.</p>
<p><strong>Customer service got automated.</strong> Over <a href="http://www.dimensiondata.com/Global/Downloadable%20Documents/2015%20Global%20Contact%20Centre%20Benchmarking%20Summary%20Report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">55% of customers</a> would like a self-service experience, which provides businesses with the unique opportunity to speed up the customer experience while decreasing costs. In the restaurant industry, established chains like Outback Steakhouse and Olive Garden let customers <a href="http://www.csmonitor.com/Business/Saving-Money/2015/0514/Restaurant-table-tablets-A-gimmick-or-actually-helpful" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">order via tablets</a>, while market newcomer <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2015/09/09/upshot/restaurant-of-the-future-service-with-an-impersonal-touch.html?_r=2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Eatsa</a> automated the bulk of the food delivery process. Automated self-service also extended to digital channels—companies like <a href="http://www.toistersolutions.com/blog/2015/10/28/automation-fail-how-attcares-stumbled-into-a-tweet-chat" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">AT&amp;T</a> automated social media responses (not always with the best outcome), while <a href="https://www.twilio.com/customers/stories/uber" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Uber</a>, Snooze and more texted customers about the status of their ride or table.</p>
<p><strong>Customer service got focused.</strong> Over 80% of companies want to use <a href="https://fonolo.com/blog/2013/09/17-important-customer-experience-statistics-for-the-call-center/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">customer service</a> as a way to differentiate themselves from their competition. But what defines a good customer service experience? In 2015, we interviewed over 60 industry influencers and found that the best way to <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/customer-service-report-2015" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">improve customer service</a> was to focus on the employee experience. By focusing on employees and treating them with respect, companies can ensure that they pass that goodwill onto customers. Case in point: <a href="https://jobs.zappos.com/why-zappos" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Zappos</a> or <a href="http://www.google.com/about/careers/lifeatgoogle/benefits/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Google</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Customer service got diversified.</strong> In 2015, companies made an effort to diversify their service offerings, providing support on established and emerging channels.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Mobile.</strong> In 2015, companies increasingly relied on mobile to interact with their customers. This year saw the official launch of Apple Pay, Starbucks’ continued success with mobile app <a href="http://www.nfcworld.com/2015/07/24/336798/one-in-five-starbucks-sales-in-the-us-made-with-mobile-payments/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">payments</a> (more than $9 million in orders processed per week) and Magic’s simple but powerful text concierge service. As mentioned above, more and more companies saw the value of adding texting to their support strategy, making it easier for customers to contact them on a channel they prefer. However, not every attempt to implement mobile customer service was successful—Domino’s unfortunately disappointed some customers with the rollout of its text-to-order service.</p>
<p><strong>Video.</strong> Audiovisual communication has been popular among consumers for years, but 2015 was the year when video really started to gain a foothold in B2C interactions. Amazon’s Mayday is probably the most well-known example, but <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2015/01/28/this-is-webrtcs-yearor-is-it/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">American Express</a> and other companies helped customers solve their problems over video. WebRTC’s open source nature also made it easier for any company to incorporate video into their service offering.</p>
<p><strong>Social.</strong> 2015 was the year social platforms got serious about customer service interactions. <a href="https://twitter.app.box.com/customer-service-on-twitter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Twitter</a>released a customer service playbook outlining the benefits of using social for customer service, as well as how to apply it to an organization. <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2015/06/15/facebook-pages-can-now-show-how-quickly-they-respond-to-customers-messages/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Facebook</a> also launched a new feature that keeps track of how long it takes company pages to respond to customer messages, giving customers better insight into the responsiveness of an organization. This is especially important, given the fact that over 40% of customers expect a response on <a href="http://www.convinceandconvert.com/social-media-research/42-percent-of-consumers-complaining-in-social-media-expect-60-minute-response-time/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">social</a> in 60 minutes or less.</p>
<p><strong>Voice.</strong> Voice is still king in contact center service interactions, but times are changing. Research from<a href="http://www.dimensiondata.com/Global/Downloadable%20Documents/2015%20Global%20Contact%20Centre%20Benchmarking%20Summary%20Report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Dimension Data</a> found that while voice accounts for 65% of all contact center interactions, digital interactions will surpass voice by the end of 2017. And with <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/07/07/technology/tech-companies-leave-phone-calls-behind.html?_r=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Internet-based companies</a> making a concerted attempt to direct customers towards digital, with other companies ditching corporate <a href="http://www.inc.com/associated-press/jpmorgan-chase-getting-rid-of-voicemail-for-some-employees.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">voicemail</a>, it became very clear in that businesses couldn’t just rely on voice for communication.</p>
<p><strong>Web chat</strong>. Over 70% of contact centers will offer web chat by the end of 2016, up from just 33% in 2015. There are several reasons why companies would want to invest in web chat—it’s cheaper than voice, agents can handle multiple conversations at once and respond in real-time, etc. And there’s a reason companies from Nordstrom to Nike are using web chat to interact with customers—while 91% of customers are happy with web chat’s ability to solve customer support issues, 62% of customers are more inclined to buy a product if live chat is available.</p></blockquote>
<h2><strong>Looking ahead to 2016</strong></h2>
<p>2015 was an exciting year for customer service, with lots of progress made in digital interactions and automation. 2016 is set to be an equally exciting year, if not more so, as companies continue to build on the advances made in 2015. We can’t say for sure what will happen in customer service in 2016, but we’ve got a few ideas.</p>
<p>Below are our customer service predictions for 2016.</p>
<p><strong>Continued rise in cloud computing</strong>. In 2016, businesses will continue to migrate to the <a href="http://www.icmi.com/Resources/Technology/2014/05/Is-the-Cloud-Contact-Center-Passing-You-By" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">cloud</a> for its accessibility, storage, simplicity, and security, among other benefits. In fact, 88% of businesses are currently using the <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/benkepes/2015/03/04/new-stats-from-the-state-of-cloud-report/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">public cloud</a>. In addition, <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/louiscolumbus/2015/09/27/roundup-of-cloud-computing-forecasts-and-market-estimates-q3-update-2015/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gartner</a> predicts that by 2020, roughly 25% of organizations will use cloud-based CRMs. Cloud-based software-as-a-service, or <a href="http://www.pwc.com/gx/en/industries/technology/publications/global-software-100-leaders/saas-trends.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SaaS</a>, will also become more prevalent, growing at a rate of 21.3% per year and making up 14.2% of software spending. <a href="http://www.statista.com/statistics/273642/worldwide-software-as-a-service-revenue-forecast/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">SaaS revenue</a> is predicted to hit $32.8 billion in revenue in 2016, up 17% from 2015.</p>
<p><strong>Delivering on the omnichannel promise. </strong>In 2013, <a href="https://d16cvnquvjw7pr.cloudfront.net/resources/whitepapers/Omnichannel-Customer-Service-Gap.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Zendesk </a>research found that over 85% of customers thought companies needed to do a better job of providing a seamless experience. In 2015, companies were on the right track but weren’t quite there yet—nearly 50% of contact centers named integration of Web, contact center and CRM systems as their top challenge, with <a href="http://www.dimensiondata.com/Global/Downloadable%20Documents/2015%20Global%20Contact%20Centre%20Benchmarking%20Summary%20Report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">integration</a> of systems to enable channel hopping close behind (41%). We predict that in 2016, companies will continue to take steps toward providing an omnichannel experience. Companies will find and use service platforms that manage and can integrate with multiple service channels/CRMs and similar systems.</p>
<p><strong>Personalization.</strong> This trend is a combination of the previous two trends—cloud services will enable companies to provide a personalized experience across channels. We predict that the ability to integrate customer data into service interactions will become increasingly mainstream in 2016, both in response to <a href="http://venturebeat.com/2015/07/14/consumers-want-privacy-yet-demand-personalization/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">consumer demand</a> and a desire to differentiate on great <a href="https://fonolo.com/blog/2013/09/17-important-customer-experience-statistics-for-the-call-center/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">customer experiences</a>. The SaaS pricing model of most cloud services will also make it easy for businesses of any size to provide great customer service.</p>
<p><strong>Proactive customer service.</strong> <a href="http://www.wired.com/insights/2014/11/the-internet-of-things-bigger/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Internet of Things</a> is rapidly changing our personal and professional lives. IoT-based companies, but other businesses as well, will leverage customer data to provide a proactive service experience. Although IoT is primarily focused on the B2C experience (think FitBit or any smartfridge), other organizations can learn from IoT innovations. Take, for example, the proactive service experience industry pundits anticipate will take shape in the IoT industry: <a href="http://www.destinationcrm.com/Articles/Web-Exclusives/Viewpoints/Revolutionizing-Customer-Service-with-the-Internet-of-Things-105722.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gartner</a> predicts that by 2018, five percent of IoT devices will automatically trigger service cases.</p>
<p><strong>More artificial intelligence.</strong> In 2016, AI will continue to get smarter, and its presence in business will continue to grow. This is evidenced by the amount of <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/article/artificial-intelligence-in-business-the-state-of-play-and-future-prospects/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">venture capital</a> being put toward AI-centered businesses, which grew from $75 million in 2013 to $300 million in 2014. And while <a href="http://www.zdnet.com/article/artificial-intelligence-in-business-the-state-of-play-and-future-prospects/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">artificial intelligence</a> is primarily being used for voice recognition and response, <a href="http://www.destinationcrm.com/Articles/Editorial/Magazine-Features/The-2015-CRM-Rising-Stars-IBMs-Watson-Brings-Cognitive-Computing-to-Customer-Support-102108.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Gartner</a> predicts that 10% of computers will be able to learn from past interactions by 2017. At OneReach, we’re helping to make this possible through the use of AI in IVRs or self-service.</p>
<p><strong>Moving towards a mobile-first future.</strong> Our world is becoming increasingly mobilized—nearly two billion global citizens now own a <a href="http://www.emarketer.com/Article/2-Billion-Consumers-Worldwide-Smartphones-by-2016/1011694" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">smartphone</a>. This mobile change extends to customer service, where 62% of companies think <a href="http://www.icmi.com/About-ICMI/Press-Room/2013-Mobile-Customer-Service-Strategy-Results-Released" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">mobile service</a> is a competitive differentiator and 64% of customers would prefer to text customer service. Texting is poised to make a big gain in the customer service field, with more than 60% of <a href="http://www.dimensiondata.com/Global/Downloadable%20Documents/2015%20Global%20Contact%20Centre%20Benchmarking%20Summary%20Report.pdf/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">contact centers</a>offering it by 2017. In 2016, we predict that companies will continue to provide customer service on mobile devices, whether it’s via text message, mobile applications, mobile websites, or other channels.</p>
<p><strong>More digital/emerging channels.</strong> As mentioned above, customer service interactions will shift to focus on emerging digital channels, both in response to consumer preference and cost savings. Take, for instance, the increased use emerging channels: One in four contact centers will offer <a href="http://www.dimensiondata.com/Global/Downloadable%20Documents/2015%20Global%20Contact%20Centre%20Benchmarking%20Summary%20Report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">video</a> by the end of 2017, one in two contact centers will offer a smartphone app by the end of 2017, and three out of five contact centers will offer texting/IM by the end of 2017.</p>
<h2><strong>Conclusion</strong></h2>
<p>2015 was a big year for customer service, and 2016 is set to be an even bigger one. We predict that new applications of technology like artificial intelligence and automation will define customer service in the coming years, as they already have today. Companies and contact centers that embrace the customer service trends in 2015 and beyond are poised to make an impact on the market that will be felt for years to come.</p>
<p><strong>For more on how to improve your customer service in 2016, <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/customer-service-report-2015">download our influencer report</a> with insights from more than 60 customer service pros.</strong></p>
<p><em>This post originally appeared on <a href="http://www.icmi.com/Resources/Customer-Experience/2016/01/Customer-Service-Trends-in-2015-and-What-They-Mean-for-2016">ICMI</a> and has been republished with permission. </em></p>
<p>Image credit: <a href="https://pixabay.com/en/man-guy-smoking-cigarettes-bench-691422/">Unsplash</a>. CC0 License. Edited.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/year-end-review-customer-service-trends-in-2015-and-beyond/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Can You Do to Kickstart Your Self-Service?</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/what-can-you-do-to-kickstart-your-self-service/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/what-can-you-do-to-kickstart-your-self-service/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Integration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Self-Service]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/what-can-you-do-to-kickstart-your-self-service/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today’s customer service is becoming increasingly digital—<a href="http://www.dimensiondata.com/Global/Global-Microsites/CCBenchmarking">35% of interactions</a> now take place on digital channels. In response, more and more businesses are providing support across a variety of digital channels, including but not limited to SMS, social media, and web chat. And while the use of these channels is growing rapidly, the use of digital self-service channels isn’t far behind.</p>
<p>Case in point: In 2011, Gartner predicted over <a href="http://mktimages.gartner.com/pv_obj_cache/pv_obj_id_92DB197B681D1A1003F701CB30B626FF3B111B00/filename/brochure_crm_2011.pdf">85% of the customer experience</a> would be managed without a human by 2020. The industry is certainly trending in this direction—Forrester found that <a href="https://www.forrester.com/North+American+Consumer+Technographics+Customer+LifeCycle+Survey+1+2014/-/E-SUS2568">self-service usage increased </a>from 67% in 2012 to 76% in 2014. If we follow Forrester’s trajectory, by the end of 2016 self-service usage could reach 84% penetration, meaning Gartner’s prediction might come even sooner than realized. But let’s take a look at where self-service is now.</p>
<h1><span id="more-7238"></span><b>Where self-service is now</b></h1>
<p>Self-service use may be on the uptick, but most companies have not actively expanded self-service beyond the Web. Research from technology evaluation hub <a href="http://www.softwareadvice.com/crm/help-desk-comparison/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Software Advice</a> found that most industries <a href="http://www.softwareadvice.com/crm/industryview/self-service-channels-report-2014/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">provide self-service predominantly online</a>. While<a href="http://www.intelliresponse.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/IR-State-of-Online-SS-WP-PROOF.pdf"> Web self-service</a> may have reached 100% penetration among businesses thanks to online knowledge bases and forums, businesses are lagging on other digital channels:</p>
<ul>
<li>39% offer email self-service</li>
<li>30% offer Twitter self-service</li>
<li>29% offer mobile self-service</li>
<li>29% offer Facebook self-service</li>
<li>25% offer chat self-service</li>
<li>19% offer SMS self-service</li>
<li>15% offer instant message self-service</li>
</ul>
<p>It’s important to consider that all of the channels listed above would require significant development to provide quality self-service. Web self-service is mostly made up of knowledge bases and forums, meaning businesses only have to add a new webpage, but <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/stevenvanbelleghem/the-self-serving-economy">include customer data</a> to make the experience better and more relevant. It’s also important to remember that self-service isn’t a channel itself&#8211;it’s an extension of an <i>existing</i> channel. However, only <a href="http://www.intelliresponse.com/the-state-of-online-self-service/">56% of companies</a> have added self-service, and that’s not even on every channel.</p>
<p>Regardless of where companies are with self-service, over <a href="http://cdn.zendesk.com/resources/whitepapers/Omnichannel-Customer-Service-Gap.pdf">50% of customers</a> think it’s important to solve issues themselves, and despite companies’ modest self-service offerings, As mentioned, Forrester found<a href="https://www.forrester.com/North+American+Consumer+Technographics+Customer+LifeCycle+Survey+1+2014/-/E-SUS2568"> self-service use</a> increased to 76% in 2014. Companies that add self-service stand to benefit in the following ways:</p>
<ul>
<li>Over 60% of businesses found self-service improved or considerably improved the call abandonment rate (<a href="http://www.softwareadvice.com/crm/industryview/self-service-channels-report-2014/?layout=var_ch1">Software Advice</a>)</li>
<li>Over 75% of businesses found self-service improved or considerably improved the speed to answer (<a href="http://www.softwareadvice.com/crm/industryview/self-service-channels-report-2014/?layout=var_ch1">Software Advice</a>)</li>
<li>45% of companies offering web or mobile self-service have reported an increase in site traffic and a decrease in phone calls. (<a href="http://www.destinationcrm.com/Articles/ReadArticle.aspx?ArticleID=90678">Destination CRM</a>)</li>
<li>By adding self-service, a typical utility could see $1-3 million in annual savings. (<a href="http://www.cpwerx.de/SiteCollectionDocuments/PDF/Accenture_Utilities_MultiChannelSelfService.pdf">Accenture</a>)</li>
</ul>
<p>So how can businesses go about adding self-service and receive better even better ROI than the stats above? In two ways: they can implement integration and automation.</p>
<h1><strong>Automation</strong></h1>
<p>Today’s customers hate to wait for coffee, let alone customer service. A study conducted by Harris Interactive and commissioned by OneReach found that<a href="http://onereach.com/resources/high-demand-for-text-message-2014-report"> 81% of customers</a> are frustrated waiting on hold over the phone or on the computer. Similarly, Accenture research found that<a href="http://www.accenture.com/sitecollectiondocuments/pdf/accenture-global-consumer-pulse-research-study-2013-key-findings.pdf"> 88% of customers</a> consider speed one of the most important parts of their customer experience.</p>
<p>Luckily, customers don’t need to wait on hold or weave through an IVR to get answers. Oftentimes, they’ll have questions that can be resolved without the help of an agent, like asking for store hours or resetting a password. By adding automation, companies can get customers the answers they need in a timely manner while letting agents handle more pressing cases. What we’ve found is that many call centers have a high percentage of calls that can be handled through automation. For example, some of our customers have found one use case equates to 40% or higher call volume&#8211;either to “reset password” or ask “where&#8217;s my order.” Both cases could be automated and have huge cost saving and time saving benefits—<a href="http://www.oracle.com/us/corporate/analystreports/enterprise-application/forrester-tei-atg-359304.pdf">Forrester research</a> found that a live agent call can cost between $6-12, while an automated interaction can cost as little as 25 cents.</p>
<p>But automation doesn’t just have to be used for simple, inbound interactions—it can also be used for more complicated interactions.</p>
<p><a href="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/automation-07annotated.png"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-1622" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/automation-07annotated.png" alt="automation-07annotated" width="600" height="269" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>For example, let’s say Bob is due for his annual physical. An automated communication flow could 1) send out a text notification to anyone who hasn’t been in for 11 months, 2) recognize the last doctor they talked to and the time the last appointment was scheduled to try, and 3) make the interaction as quick and seamless as possible. This lets Bob get an appointment set up quickly without needing to interact with staff. Of course, patients prefer different channels, so the same could happen via automated call or email.</p>
<p>How to add automation: You could hire a developer to add self-service to your existing channels, but a more cost-effective solution is to find software that lets you build automated logic on the channels customers use. A good solution would provide the following capabilities:</p>
<ul>
<li>reporting/analytics for individual and cross-channel experiences</li>
<li>seamless integration with other channels</li>
<li>the ability to create omnichannel experiences which allows multichannel use at the same time</li>
</ul>
<h1><strong>Integration</strong></h1>
<p>Sometimes, customers will want to switch with a live agent, and that’s completely fine. What they don’t want to do is start their conversation over—Accenture found that<a href="http://www.accenture.com/SiteCollectionDocuments/PDF/Accenture-Global-Consumer-Pulse-Research-Study-2013-Key-Findings.pdf"> 91% of customers</a> are frustrated by having to contact a company multiple times for the same reason. Similarly, 89% are frustrated by having to repeat their issue to multiple representatives. Equally bad:<a href="http://www.dimensiondata.com/Global/Global-Microsites/CCBenchmarking"> over 53% of contact centers</a> don’t pass information when a customer drops out of self-service.</p>
<p>Integration usually means “lots of time and money,” scaring off businesses that could potentially benefit from it. By using a platform like OneReach, businesses can let customers switch between channels and still maintain context, quickly and without high costs of development. If a customer switches from text message to voice, an integrated (or omnichannel solution) would track where the conversation left off so that the agent knows where to start. This creates a more seamless experience for the customer and a more informed experience for the agent, which ultimately creates a better overall customer experience.</p>
<p>As mentioned above, most businesses are primarily providing Web service. However, the use cases are endless&#8211;You could send customers to a web or text channel to avoid hold times by using <a href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/?p=499">channel pivot</a>, which lets customers seamlessly switch channels without losing context. Similarly, you could <a href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/?p=1351">promote adoption of mobile apps</a> with messages in the IVR or over SMS.</p>
<p>But integration isn’t just limited to channels—it also means integrating channels with existing data sources. Let’s take another look at the example above.</p>
<p><a href="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/automation08-annotated.png"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-1623" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/automation08-annotated.png" alt="automation08 annotated" width="600" height="269" /></a></p>
<p>The automated text message 1) greeted Bob by name, 2) asked if he wanted to schedule an appointment, 3) presented him with a time his doctor was available based around the doctor&#8217;s schedule, 4) then set up a follow-up message. The automated text messages couldn’t deliver that information without 5) being integrated with a CRM (for Bob’s name and attending physician) and 6) a scheduling system (for Bob’s doctor’s appointment times). This integration goes both ways, however—the information from the texts has to be passed back to the CRM and scheduling system so that Bob’s appointment is on record.</p>
<p>How to add integration: Currently,<a href="http://www.dimensiondata.com/Global/Global-Microsites/CCBenchmarking"> 60.6% of contact center technology systems</a> aren’t integrated, and over 48% of contact centers said one of the greatest challenges in implementing successful self-service was integrating different systems. Find solutions like OneReach that let you integrate with many systems. That way, you have an out of the box solution that is ready to roll out, but can also be customized to your needs.We’ve found that some integrations that aren’t available out of the box can be done in minutes or just a few weeks to get what is needed, based on the scale of the project and the overall goal.</p>
<h1><strong>Conclusion</strong></h1>
<p>Customer use of self-service is increasing, and the fact that businesses are adding self-service is a promising sign. Still, there’s some work to be done to provide the experience your customers are expecting while  reaching Gartner’s magic number of 85%. By adding powerful automation and integration to their self-service initiatives to provide quick and relevant answers to customers (or to the consumers), businesses will be able to bring the customer experience of the future into the present.</p>
<p><strong> <em>To learn more about automating and integrating your self-service, <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/omnichannel-seamless-experience">download our new ebook here</a>.</em></strong></p>
<p>Photo credit: <a class="author" href="https://stocksnap.io/author/471"><span class="author-name">Jan Vašek</span></a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/what-can-you-do-to-kickstart-your-self-service/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>10 Striking Statistics on Self-Service Today</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/10-striking-statistics-on-self-service-today/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/10-striking-statistics-on-self-service-today/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Self-Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Statistics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/10-striking-statistics-on-self-service-today/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today&#8217;s self-service is becoming more and more prevalent, spreading across channels from  web to voice to text to social. It&#8217;s a powerful, flexible form of service that more customers are using and businesses are adopting. In fact, <a href="http://www.intelliresponse.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/IR-State-of-Online-SS-WP-PROOF.pdf">over 50% of businesses</a> today are using self-service, and 64% plan to invest in and extend it to other channels (<a href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/?p=1299">texting, anyone?</a>)</p>
<p><span id="more-7216"></span>At OneReach, we think self-service is a valuable tool that not only cuts costs but increases customer satisfaction. By adding self-service (and automation to speed up resolution time), businesses can receive a great ROI and empower customers with quick and easy service experiences.</p>
<p>Check out these insights on the growth of self-service today (and beyond)!</p>
<ol>
<li>Over 50% of customers think it&#8217;s important to solve product issues themselves rather than rely on customer service. (<a href="http://cdn.zendesk.com/resources/whitepapers/Omnichannel-Customer-Service-Gap.pdf">Zendesk</a>)</li>
<li>Self-service usage increased from 67% in 2012 to 76% in 2014. (<a href="https://www.forrester.com/North+American+Consumer+Technographics+Customer+LifeCycle+Survey+1+2014/-/E-SUS2568">Forrester</a>)</li>
<li>45% of companies offering web or mobile self-service have reported an increase in site traffic and a decrease in phone calls. (<a href="http://www.destinationcrm.com/Articles/ReadArticle.aspx?ArticleID=90678">Destination CRM</a>)</li>
<li>A chat with a live agent can cost $6-12 per interaction, while an automated interaction on the IVR (or ITR) can cost as little as 25 cents. (<a href="http://www.oracle.com/us/corporate/analystreports/enterprise-application/forrester-tei-atg-359304.pdf">Forrester</a>)</li>
<li>40% of customers prefer self-service to human contact. (<a href="http://www.slideshare.net/stevenvanbelleghem/the-self-serving-economy">Steven Van Belleghem</a>)</li>
<li>The IVR makes up 27% of all calls in the contact center, but only 7% of companies offer an IVR solution that delivers a better experience than live agents. (<a href="http://www.howto.gov/sites/default/files/the-drivers-of-customer-satisfaction-in-the-contact-center.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">JD Power &amp; Associates</a>)</li>
<li>By adding self-service, a typical utility could see $1-3 million in annual savings. (<a href="http://www.accenture.com/SiteCollectionDocuments/PDF/Accenture_Utilities_MultiChannelSelfService.pdf">Accenture</a>)</li>
<li>By this year, 50% of online customer self-service tasks will be performed by virtual agents. (<a href="http://www.gartner.com/newsroom/id/1929014">Gartner</a>)</li>
<li>70% of customers prefer to use a company&#8217;s website to get answers to their questions rather than use phone or email. (<a href="http://blogs.forrester.com/diane_clarkson/10-04-06-do_your_customers_want_telephone_you_service">Forrester</a>)</li>
<li>By 2020, the customer will manage 85% of the relationship with an enterprise without interacting with a human. (<a href="http://mktimages.gartner.com/pv_obj_cache/pv_obj_id_92DB197B681D1A1003F701CB30B626FF3B111B00/filename/brochure_crm_2011.pdf">Gartner</a>)</li>
</ol>
<p>What&#8217;s your take on self-service? Does it get you the answers you need, or do you end up frustrated? Let us know in the comments, and don&#8217;t forget to download our ebook on the use of <a href="http://onereachcontactcenter.com/high-demand-for-customer-service-via-text-message/">texting for customer (self)-service</a>!</p>
<p>Photo by <a href="http://pixabay.com/en/office-notes-notepad-entrepreneur-614273/">FirmBee</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/10-striking-statistics-on-self-service-today/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Self-Service: The Next Channel You Can&#8217;t Ignore</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/self-service-the-next-channel-you-cant-ignore/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/self-service-the-next-channel-you-cant-ignore/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Self-Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trends]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/self-service-the-next-channel-you-cant-ignore/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Self-service has been around for generations, from the advent of personal shopping in grocery stores to the global presence of ATMs. But it was really in the last quarter century that self-service hit its stride, thanks to the rise of the Internet. Customers can solve their own problems or answer their own questions thanks to the ubiquity of this technology.</p>
<p><span id="more-7201"></span>OneReach&#8217;s Elias Parker explains further in his CustomerThink article:</p>
<blockquote><p>The now 25 year-old Internet quickly changed many industries, from communications to commerce to customer service. People can now search online for solutions to their problems, or check their account balance without having to talk to an agent. And frankly, people prefer to manage customer service themselves when they want, from where they want. In fact, Forrester found that more than 70% of customers prefer self-service to talking on the phone or sending an email.</p></blockquote>
<p><strong><a href="http://customerthink.com/the-future-of-self-service-the-next-channel-you-cant-ignore/">Check out the full article here</a> for insight on the future on self-service, and download the <a href="http://onereachcontactcenter.com/high-demand-for-customer-service-via-text-message/">free Harris Interactive report</a> to learn more about how customers want service delivered.</strong></p>
<p>Photo by <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/42806032@N07/5468105087/">Polycart</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/self-service-the-next-channel-you-cant-ignore/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Self(ish)-service: How Misused IVR Ruins the Customer Experience</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/selfish-service-how-misused-ivr-ruins-the-customer-experience/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/selfish-service-how-misused-ivr-ruins-the-customer-experience/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[IVR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Self-Service]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/selfish-service-how-misused-ivr-ruins-the-customer-experience/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>People hate IVR, everything from its automated voice to its endless wait times to its frantic button mashing. In fact, only 13% of consumers think IVR <a href="http://www.interactions.net/2011/06/so-people-hate-ivr-is-this-news-to-anyone/">is easy to use</a><b>. </b>Callers can never be sure if they’ll encounter an effective self-service tool, an ineffective self-service tool, or a call routing system. However, most experiences end the same way: with one frustrated customer.</p>
<p>IVRs were originally created to decrease the amount of time an agent had to be on the phone and increase conversions. Unfortunately, they didn’t do as good a job reducing the amount of time for the customer. As companies reaped the financial benefits and agents had more time to work with, customers grew increasingly dissatisfied with the IVR system. Today, only 15% of consumers think IVR use <a href="http://www.interactions.net/2011/06/so-people-hate-ivr-is-this-news-to-anyone/">benefits them</a>.</p>
<p><span id="more-7137"></span>Being overly reliant on IVR often comes at the expense of customer experience. Customers call in to resolve a seemingly simple problem like paying a bill and are taken hostage by never-ending wait times and prompts. (Interactions with live service agents aren’t necessarily better—just check out this <a href="https://www.yahoo.com/tech/comcast-serves-up-what-may-be-the-worst-customer-91851980684.html">Comcast horror story</a> that’s been circulating the web). We’ve all had bad experiences with IVR self-service, but the truth is, we don’t have to.</p>
<p>IVR can actually be a great (and cost-effective) contact center solution if we let it. <a href="http://www.oracle.com/us/corporate/analystreports/enterprise-application/forrester-tei-atg-359304.pdf">According to a report by Forrester and Oracle</a>, the average IVR call costs around 15 cents, compared to $15 for a live agent call. The key to using IVR is to make it as easy for the customer as possible to get their problem solved. The pain comes when the self-service fails, or when a customer knows they’re just being asked question to be routed to the appropriate agent. IVRs can offer a great experience. Here are some ways to improve them:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong style="color: #000000; font-style: normal;">Add a personal touch. </strong>Customers often have to sit through entire phone menus just to find the option they’re looking for, and they’re tired of it&#8211;over 40% consumers would prefer to have a text conversation immediately vs. waiting on hold. Drawing on data from past interactions can get customers to the option they want a lot quicker and out of phone menu hell.</li>
<li><strong>Keep it simple.</strong> IVR is a pretty basic system: it routes you where you want to go with the push of a button. It’s also very good at answering basic questions like what a store’s hours or address are. Don’t assign the system overcomplicated functions and your customers won’t be disappointed.</li>
<li><strong>Make it useful.</strong> Customers know what they want from an IVR experience, and that’s to get their problem resolved as quickly and easily as possible. Cater to the customer and their needs: for example, instead of making customers start a call over due to an incorrect entry and wasting their time, let them try again.</li>
<li><strong>Let them change channels.</strong> <a style="font-style: normal;" href="http://onereach.com/resources/infographics/OneReach_People_Want_to_Text_Your_Business.jpg">Over 64% of customers</a> prefer texting a contact center over calling them. Give customers the flexibility to switch between phone and text when it suits them without losing track of where they were in the conversation.</li>
</ul>
<p>IVRs may seem cheaper than adding another agent to your team, but don’t forget that improved customer service <a href="http://blogs.salesforce.com/company/2013/07/customer-service-tips.html">correlates to increased profits</a>.</p>
<p><i>If you&#8217;re interested in learning more about custom voice and IVR applications, professionally designed or do-it-yourself &#8211; check out </i><em><a href="http://onereach.com/">OneReach</a><a href="http://onereach.com/">.</a></em></p>
<p>Photo by Flickr user <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/mistressf/1434535494">Flavia</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/selfish-service-how-misused-ivr-ruins-the-customer-experience/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
