<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Use Cases &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<atom:link href="https://onereach.ai/category/use-cases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<description>Intelligently Automate Your Company</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 11:39:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/cropped-OR-ICON-GOLD-W-DOTS-Larger-Background-02-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Use Cases &#8211; OneReach.ai</title>
	<link>https://onereach.ai</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Bots Gone Bad: What We Can Learn From Microsoft’s Tay Malfunction</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/bots-gone-bad-what-we-can-learn-from-microsofts-tay-malfunction/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/bots-gone-bad-what-we-can-learn-from-microsofts-tay-malfunction/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Big Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Use Cases]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/bots-gone-bad-what-we-can-learn-from-microsofts-tay-malfunction/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By now you’ve probably heard the story of Tay, the AI-powered chat bot Microsoft debuted last Wednesday. Things started off innocently enough before Tay went completely off the rails, going on racist rants and tweeting her support of Adolf Hitler before Microsoft pulled the plug.</p>
<p><span id="more-7410"></span>But let’s start back at the beginning. Tay was created by “mining relevant public data and by using AI and editorial developed by a staff including improvisational comedians,” according to <a href="https://www.tay.ai/#about">Microsoft’s Tay website</a>. Tay was programmed to talk like a millennial and targeted at millennials (which apparently means lots of CAPS LOCK and poor grammar, but that’s a discussion for another time).</p>
<p>Unfortunately for Microsoft, people other than millennials found Tay easy enough to manipulate, goading her into spouting racist and sexist rhetoric through a “<a href="http://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2016/03/tay-the-neo-nazi-millennial-chatbot-gets-autopsied/">repeat after me</a>” feature. However, as <a href="http://fusion.net/story/284537/tay-and-you-microsoft-racism/">Fusion</a> reports, “some of the tweets were clearly generated by the bot itself.”</p>
<p>Twitter user @geraldmellor captured some of her incendiary tweets, seen below:</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">&#8220;Tay&#8221; went from &#8220;humans are super cool&#8221; to full nazi in &lt;24 hrs and I&#8217;m not at all concerned about the future of AI <a href="https://t.co/xuGi1u9S1A">pic.twitter.com/xuGi1u9S1A</a></p>
<p>— Gerry (@geraldmellor) <a href="https://twitter.com/geraldmellor/status/712880710328139776">March 24, 2016</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" async="" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p>Tay’s racist makeover didn’t go unnoticed, and Microsoft turned her off before things got more out of hand. But in <a href="http://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2016/03/25/learning-tays-introduction/">Microsoft’s blog post</a> commenting on what happened with Tay, Corporate VP of Microsoft Research Peter Lee pointed out this wasn’t their first foray into AI—Xiaolce, a chat bot Microsoft rolled out in 2014, hasn’t had any major issues. Lee also explained they stress-tested Tay and conducted user studies before her public debut.</p>
<p>Still, the very public meltdown of Microsoft’s AI chat bots left some people like @geraldmellor to wonder what exactly the future of AI might be like if bots go bad. But, looking at it from another perspective, what can bot designers do help ensure bots stay good?</p>
<p>First, you need to remember that bots just might get exposed to negative comments, as Tay was. As Microsoft’s Lee <a href="http://blogs.microsoft.com/blog/2016/03/25/learning-tays-introduction/">explains</a>, &#8220;AI systems feed off of both positive and negative interactions with people. In that sense, the challenges are just as much social as they are technical.”</p>
<p>Second, in accordance with Lee’s suggestion, you need to test the bots with large groups of people, and to do it often. But perhaps last and most importantly, you need to make sure they know how to understand language.</p>
<p>Caroline Sinders, an interaction designer at IBM Watson, put it this way in her <a href="https://medium.com/@carolinesinders/microsoft-s-tay-is-an-example-of-bad-design-d4e65bb2569f#.r6iv4kpv6">Medium post</a> about Tay:</p>
<blockquote><p>“These AIs have to be trained. Tay didn’t understand “Holocaust” as the Holocaust, it understood it as a blank word or an event. And the things before it as negative, so thus if asked “Do you think the Holocaust is real?” and then being told “Yes, it’s not real” or repeat after me “BLANK PERSON is a f—ing jerk,” it teaches the corpus those phrases and reinforces them as appropriate responses.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Whenever Microsoft does decide to rerelease Tay, they’ll need to keep in mind positive and negative interactions, large amounts of user testing and language comprehension.</p>
<p>Image of Microsoft store courtesy of <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/jeepersmedia/15966273430/in/photolist-qjTjQo-qjTkkG-owZ4o4-8ooubZ-qjSEJm-pErGVu-qzaaz9-qzaafw-qBgzEK-qBntWQ-ovee7S-rcddSo-qjZEuF-pErGbU-pEF2Sk-pEF26k-6EX2CH-qjSDNy-qza9PG-pErGTA-pErGqm-pEF2Cc-pErGiY-qza9yw-qBnsMA-qjSEow-rcjTrK-rtFhW7-AHzD1-4tCp8M-dGyrX-f7sz-5D68f7-68rzD-9mtDtV-jQSMKQ-9mwJgj-4s9mqe-4pq2tD-4pqj1g-8qm3fE-7Hi4KT-4rajfL-y2SQX-85V8X6-vfHoyy-L9aqg-L8VDW-L8VNC-b7wBV">Mike Mozart</a> / Flickr. CC2.0 License. Edited.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/bots-gone-bad-what-we-can-learn-from-microsofts-tay-malfunction/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Clinton Uses Texting and Voice To Attack Sanders</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/clinton-uses-texting-and-voice-to-attack-sanders/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/clinton-uses-texting-and-voice-to-attack-sanders/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Use Cases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/clinton-uses-texting-and-voice-to-attack-sanders/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/election-texting-post/">We&#8217;ve written before</a> about how texting could be used for political campaigns. You could use it for voter registration, voting day reminders, or even to set up a text hotline to get real-time feedback on what&#8217;s going on at polling places.</p>
<p>But now we can add a new texting use case to the list: attack ads.</p>
<p><span id="more-7393"></span>BuzzFeed News Reporter Evan McMorris-Santoro <a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/evanmcsan/clinton-uses-presidents-day-to-accuse-sanders-of-disloyalty#.hroMQE3RY">had a firsthand experience</a> with this texting use case. He received a text message from the Clinton campaign touting her support of Barack Obama and calling out &#8220;someone&#8221; who didn&#8217;t support Obama.</p>
<p>When Evan texted back the word HEAR to learn more, he got an automated call from the Hillary campaign with a soundbite of her supporting one of Obama&#8217;s decisions and Bernie Sanders opposing him. After the call, it ended with a text saying Hillary was the only one who would continue Obama&#8217;s legacy.</p>
<p>This is definitely a unique texting use case, not only for its message but for its use of two communication channels to get that message across. I won&#8217;t get into politics here, but I commend Clinton for using two powerful communication channels together to interact with her base and deliver a one-on-one experience that other channels can&#8217;t.</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/evanmcsan/clinton-uses-presidents-day-to-accuse-sanders-of-disloyalty#.hroMQE3RY">Check out the full article on BuzzFeed</a>, and don&#8217;t forget to <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/10-things-about-text">download our whitepaper</a> on the 10 things you need to know when adding texting to your business.</strong></p>
<p><em>The opinions expressed here are solely that of the contributor and don&#8217;t necessarily represent the views of OneReach.</em></p>
<p>Photo by Flickr user <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/cornstalker/23575629583/">Matt A.J</a>. <a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/">CC2.0 License</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/clinton-uses-texting-and-voice-to-attack-sanders/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>OneReach Helps Power City of Evanston&#8217;s Restaurant Inspection Text Messages</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/onereach-helps-power-city-of-evanstons-restaurant-inspection-text-messages/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/onereach-helps-power-city-of-evanstons-restaurant-inspection-text-messages/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Big Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ITR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Use Cases]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/onereach-helps-power-city-of-evanstons-restaurant-inspection-text-messages/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The city of Evanston, Ill. has worked with OneReach to provide residents with the ability to check the health inspection scores of local restaurants over text.</p>
<p><span id="more-7369"></span>Diners can text the keyword &#8220;food&#8221; to the city&#8217;s 311 number, and then text the name of the restaurant to see the health inspection score, as well as the date the inspection took place.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.govtech.com/health/Texting-Helps-in-Fight-Against-Foodborne-Illnesses-in-Evanston-Ill.html">Government Technology</a> points out that the use of texting makes getting restaurant scores a lot easier for consumers:</p>
<blockquote><p>It’s simple and much easier than Yelp’s mobile app, which compels users to tap and swipe their way to a restaurant’s “More Info” tab and deep dive through a list of miscellaneous information.</p></blockquote>
<p>The food safety text initiative follows the city&#8217;s initiative to local restaurant inspection scores onto Yelp.</p>
<p><strong>Check out the full article on <a href="http://www.govtech.com/health/Texting-Helps-in-Fight-Against-Foodborne-Illnesses-in-Evanston-Ill.html">Government Technology</a>, and don&#8217;t forget to <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/high-demand-for-text-message-2014-report">download our report</a> on why 64% of customers would rather text than call your business. </strong></p>
<p>Image credit: <a href="https://pixabay.com/en/iphone-5s-cafe-office-apple-hand-1114403/">dangquocbuu</a>. CC0 license. Edited.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/onereach-helps-power-city-of-evanstons-restaurant-inspection-text-messages/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ben &#038; Jerry’s and OneReach: A Sweet Combination</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/ben-jerrys-and-onereach-a-sweet-combination/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/ben-jerrys-and-onereach-a-sweet-combination/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Use Cases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/ben-jerrys-and-onereach-a-sweet-combination/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Climate justice is about to get a little bit sweeter.</p>
<p>Ben &amp; Jerry’s is rallying climate activists (and anyone with a sweet tooth) to take action on climate change. The ice cream maker, a long-time supporter of climate justice, is urging citizens worldwide to contact world leaders in advance of the <a href="http://www.cop21.gouv.fr/en">United Nations Climate Change Conference</a> in Paris, which begins at the end of November.</p>
<p><span id="more-7347"></span>Ben &amp; Jerry’s wants world leaders to commit to strong carbon reduction goals, and is supporting a transitioning to 100% clean energy by 2050. They’re currently offering citizens the ability reach out to decision makers over email, but that can be an easy channel for leaders to ignore.</p>
<p>Phone calls—well, let’s just say they know how to grab your attention.</p>
<p>For their current campaign, “Save Our Swirled,” Ben &amp; Jerry’s wanted to provide communication channels that were going to be the most impactful on this issue, and knew that direct calls would be a great, easy way to for citizens to take action. They decided to use voice calls to contact local leaders, specifically state governors to implement the US Clean Power Plan, and they turned to OneReach to help make their vision a reality.</p>
<p>OneReach designed a click-to-call widget for the website that not only lets citizens call governors, but also lets them tweet at or email them. (<a href="http://www.benjerry.com/flavors/salted-caramel-brownie-ale-ice-cream">Check out the widget here</a>&#8211;you have to be over 21). For Ben &amp; Jerry’s, this secondary option means they can engage with state leaders on the channel they prefer, but also have the ability to contact state leaders multiple times.</p>
<p>This isn’t Ben and Jerry’s only climate campaign, though. They produce a lot of content educating fans on climate justice, and have even taxed their own CO2 omissions to be used to reduce carbon impact. Their goal is to reduce their impact by 80% by 2050.</p>
<p>We’re excited to have helped Ben &amp; Jerry’s and are glad we’re giving activists (and ice cream lovers) the chance to serve up climate justice.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/ben-jerrys-and-onereach-a-sweet-combination/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Tried To Text Domino&#8217;s for Pizza And Had a Horrible Customer Experience</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/i-tried-to-text-dominos-for-pizza-and-had-a-horrible-customer-experience/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/i-tried-to-text-dominos-for-pizza-and-had-a-horrible-customer-experience/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Automation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Big Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Communication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Satisfaction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gripes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Use Cases]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/i-tried-to-text-dominos-for-pizza-and-had-a-horrible-customer-experience/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tired of ordering pizza over the phone? Domino’s understands—that’s why they’ve launched <a href="anyware.dominos.com">AnyWare</a>, letting you “order your favorite oven-baked goodness on your favorite devices.”</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’m not going to lie—this is a pretty awesome use case (in theory). With AnyWare, you can text, tweet and even use your Smart TV to order pizza and more, and all you have to do is send a pizza emoji.</span></p>
<p><span id="more-7253"></span></p>
<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/D1SrOjuBSEU" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>Easy as (pizza) pie, right?</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Not so much, which kinda sucks because I was really excited by the prospect of being able to text to order a pizza. (No really, I was).</span></p>
<p><a href="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-text-1.png"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-1743 size-medium" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-text-1-264x300.png" alt="dominos text 1" width="264" height="300" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">See, the key to ordering pizza from Domino’s on any of your smart devices lies in creating a Pizza Profile apparently, where you have to input your name, email address, and phone number to get your hands on that slice of cheese. By creating an account, you’re able to Easy Order based off of past purchases and skip entering your personal payment information every time.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’re all about text messaging and effortless service at OneReach, so this seemed like a great use case to test out. Pizza + texting = success, right?!?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Excited with the thought of pizza for lunch, and with my stomach growling, I went off to create my Pizza Profile. However, hitting the site should have been my first clue as to what I was about to experience because apparently you have to divulge your deepest, darkest secrets to order a pizza. After logging in to enable text ordering, I was presented with a whole lot of pizza legalese asking for my consent.</span></p>
<p><strong><strong><a href="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos1.png"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1744" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos1-546x331.png" alt="dominos1" width="546" height="331" /></a></strong></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I entered my phone number and saved my settings. Next, I had to double opt-in to confirm that I did, in fact, want to order pizza.  </span></p>
<p><strong><strong><a href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/dominos-text-2.png"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-1741 size-medium" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-text-2-e1440719073409-289x300.png" alt="dominos text 2" width="289" height="300" /></a></strong></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Then, I had to set up an Easy Order (oh, how I wish it had been) so the system knew what to query. </span></p>
<p><strong><strong><a href="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-double-optin.png"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-1745 size-large" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-double-optin-546x255.png" alt="dominos double optin" width="546" height="255" /></a></strong></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Almost done? I wish! The pop-up told me I had to place my order </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">online</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> before I could use text messaging. Honestly, I kind of got the feeling this was a cash grab to get everyone to order way more pizzas than they need, all for supposed convenience’s sake.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I was at a loss. I didn’t even know </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">where </span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">to place my Easy Order. Luckily, my phone came to my rescue when I opted in to receive messages and I could start placing my Easy Order.</span></p>
<p><a href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/dominos-text-3.png"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-1746 size-medium" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-text-3-e1440719007201-269x300.png" alt="dominos text 3" width="269" height="300" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Just kidding&#8211;I had to go back online </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">again</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">. So far, not so easy.</span></p>
<p><a href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/dominos-text-4.png"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-1747 size-medium" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-text-4-e1440719030547-289x300.png" alt="dominos text 4" width="289" height="300" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">No, I don’t want to </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">cheese it up</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">—I just want to order my damn pizza over text message.</span></p>
<p><strong><strong><a href="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-cheese-it-up.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1748" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-cheese-it-up.png" alt="dominos cheese it up" width="457" height="291" /></a></strong></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">C’mon, this is supposed to be easy! I just want to order my pizza over text message!!</span></p>
<p><strong><strong><a href="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-chocolate.png"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1749" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-chocolate-546x291.png" alt="dominos chocolate" width="546" height="291" /></a></strong></strong></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Finally</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, on the payment page, I found what I was looking for.</span></p>
<p><strong><strong><a href="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-easy-order.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1750" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-easy-order.png" alt="dominos easy order" width="318" height="142" /></a></strong></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Awesome. Easy Order saved. Right? Wrong. Even though I submitted my order (14” with pepperoni and mushrooms), I still had no Easy Order to show for it. At this point, I was getting really frustrated (and hungry).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Not to be deterred, I tried once again to order over text, but because I didn’t save my credit card information, I couldn’t order. Because guess what—the only way to update your payment method is to MAKE ANOTHER PAYMENT.</span></p>
<p><strong><strong><a href="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-credit-card-2.png"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1751" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-credit-card-2-546x73.png" alt="dominos credit card 2" width="546" height="73" /></a></strong></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Seriously. Yeah.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Still aiming for my end goal of ordering pizza over text message, I went back <em>online</em> to order something cheap (3 20 oz. sodas) to re-enter my payment information. And when I went back to my phone and texted my little pizza emoji, guess what? Still didn’t work, because life sucks sometimes.</span></p>
<p><a href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/dominos-text-5.png"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-1752 size-medium" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-text-5-e1440718690657-289x300.png" alt="dominos text 5" width="289" height="300" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Luckily, the delivery guy was nice enough to deliver my two orders together, and when I asked if my online credit card payment went through (because according to the texts, it wasn’t valid), he showed me the receipt, where it clearly did.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In summary, not only was I </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">not</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> able to order over text message, but I had a heck of a time even trying to order online.</span></p>
<p>The goal of this article is not to bash Domino’s&#8211;they should be applauded for even attempting to deploy a text-to-order service. In addition, I’m assuming that once I got my Easy Order set up, it would have been as easy to order as advertised instead of what I went through.</p>
<figure id="attachment_1753" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1753" style="width: 546px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-happy.png"><img class="size-large wp-image-1753" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-happy-546x287.png" alt="This is definitely not how I felt after trying to order. Photo from Domino&quot;sss" width="546" height="287" /></a><figcaption id="caption-attachment-1753" class="wp-caption-text">This is definitely NOT how I felt after trying to order. Photo from Domino&#8217;s AnyWare video.</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Still, what’s ultimately lacking from the Domino’s AnyWare experience is the “anywhere” aspect of it. Domino’s tried and failed to create a seamless omnichannel experience that lets you order pizza whenever, wherever, and however you want. It relied too heavily on the Web to enable an experience that should have taken place largely on other channels.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A true omnichannel experience would have seamlessly transferred customers from channel to channel (ie a link to a secure payment page for ordering), rather than forcing them back to the Web to do the very thing they should have been able to do by texting or tweeting: order pizza.</span></p>
<h1><b>Text Domino’s 2.0</b></h1>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Even though I didn’t get my pizza over text message, I still wanted to see if there was a better way to design this whole text debacle. Because even though it didn’t work, it should have worked. And it can work.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here’s how it should have been done (and can be done). Domino’s, feel free to use this model PUH-LEESE!</span></p>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">First, I would text into Domino’s, without needing a Pizza Profile. That was the one part of the user experience that continuously failed me, </span><a href="http://www.eater.com/2015/5/20/8631373/i-ordered-dominos-pizza-emoji-it-took-three-hours-twitter"><span style="font-weight: 400;">and I’m not</span></a> <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2015/05/20/dominos-tweet-to-order-system-isnt-as-great-as-it-sounds/#.v3rtkt:wfb2"><span style="font-weight: 400;">the only one</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Had I not been so committed to seeing this through, I would have bailed with many profanities following and ordered from Papa John’s.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">I would receive a text message asking if I’d like to place my usual order (not Easy Order, because that sure as heck wasn’t easy), or if I’d like to place a new one.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The system would already know my address and billing information, so I wouldn’t have to input that information online, taking me out of my mobile experience. </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’d confirm that I’d like the pizza delivered to my regular address.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The system would then ask me if I’d like to pay with the card I already have on file.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">I’d confirm, and then I’d get a message that my pizza was on my way.</span></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Easy as that.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But, why tell you when I can show you? Here’s how it would look&#8230;</span></p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-2388 aligncenter" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/dominos-texting2.png" alt="text dominos" width="301" height="573" /></p>
<p>Want to try a great text-to-order experience for yourself? <strong>Text “PIZZA” to 70700.</strong> Note&#8211;you won’t actually be ordering pizza, and there are no integrations to find the nearest Domino’s or to pay for pizza. Still, it’s an example of what a smart ordering experience could be (and should have been) like.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Enjoy!</span></p>
<p><strong>To learn more about adding text to your business (the right way), <a style="font-weight: bold;" href="http://onereach.com/resources/10-things-about-text">download our whitepaper here</a>, or shoot us a text at 303-974-7351. We&#8217;re always happy to chat.</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://www.kawankumagz.com/articleFoto/Hal-Hal_yang_Kita_Rasakan_Saat_Mengirim_Chat_ke_Gebetan_(Bagian_1).jpg">Photo credit</a>. Edited.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/i-tried-to-text-dominos-for-pizza-and-had-a-horrible-customer-experience/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>The ‘Magic’ Model &#8211; How To Instantly Build Your Own SMS Concierge Service</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/the-magic-model-how-to-instantly-build-your-own-sms-concierge-service/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/the-magic-model-how-to-instantly-build-your-own-sms-concierge-service/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Customer Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How To]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile Payments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Use Cases]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/the-magic-model-how-to-instantly-build-your-own-sms-concierge-service/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After graduating from <a href="http://www.ycombinator.com/">YCombinator</a> back in February, a startup called <a href="http://getmagicnow.com/">Magic</a>, an SMS concierge service,  went viral, wowing Americans with the prospect that they could order almost anything via text message and have it show up at their door &#8211; not to mention the $12 million investment they garnered from <a href="http://www.sequoiacap.com">Sequoia Capital</a>, with a $40 million valuation). After provisioning a<a href="http://www.wired.com/2015/02/magic-the-startup/"> Twilio number</a> and rolling the service out to a few friends, the service suddenly skyrocketed in popularity, thanks to some well-placed features on <a href="http://www.producthunt.com/tech/magic">Product Hunt</a> and <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=9087819">Hacker News</a> (and just good old word-of-mouth).</p>
<p>Investors and companies are now starting to see the value of SMS (finally!), and so are emerging Magic competitors. Entrepreneurs around the world have begun innovating on the “Magic” model, spanning from straight up copycats to various niche-specific spins on the model &#8211; for example, the SMS concierge service for travelling performers and staff in the music-touring business. If you have an existing or potential SMS concierge business in mind, you’ll be very glad to know just how easy it is to equip yourself with the right tools and services to make it happen.</p>
<h1><span id="more-7245"></span><b>How to Create Your Own SMS Service: What You&#8217;ll Need</b></h1>
<p>To make your own “Magic,” all you need is a phone number (any toll-free, short-code or 10-digit local number will do), a web-based or mobile-based chat tool that can manage text messages, and a payment processing system.</p>
<p>By creating a OneReach account, you’ll get these great features needed to make your own Magic SMS Service:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Provision a text-enabled number easily and cheaply.</strong> Magic uses a short code number (83489), which can cost <a href="https://www.twilio.com/HELP/faq/short-codes/how-much-does-a-short-code-cost">$1,000 a month</a> or more. We can set you up with a short code, as they can handle a larger volume of traffic, but if you’re just getting up and running, a long code will typically do just fine as it is far less expensive. These 10-digit numbers only cost <a href="https://www.twilio.com/voice/pricing">$1-2 a month</a>.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong><strong>Text chat and web chat in the same tool. </strong></strong><b></b>OneReach has a CTI integration, which is just a fancy way of saying that  we’ve created a seamless integration between SMS (text messaging) and web-chat &#8211; meaning, you can respond to SMS via a browser-based portal. Our Action Desk has the capability to handle both text chat and web chat and can manage multiple conversations at once. Although you’ll primarily be dealing with incoming text messages, you could create a field on your homepage so web visitors could input their number online and receive a text back from you to start the conversation.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Receiving requests anytime, anywhere, with our mobile app.</strong> You’re not always going to be able to stay at the desk all day, and that’s okay. If you’re out and about fulfilling a request and another one comes in, you can respond to it immediately or transfer it to someone else.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Assign agents to manage requests.</strong> As your business grows, you’re going to need a dedicated team of agents to field incoming requests. With OneReach, you can assign multiple agents to one number so that every incoming request gets answered. In addition, you can have agents claim an incoming text so that other agents know to move onto the next one.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Setting up business logic routing based on time, request type or any other parameter.</strong> You may not always be available (picking up orders, done for the day, etc.), which is where our business logic routing comes in. If someone specifically handles food requests, you can route all related requests to them. Similarly, if someone is off the clock, our system can route requests to a different agent based on their schedule.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Easily connecting or integrating with a payment system or food ordering system.</strong> We’re not 100% sure if Magic uses APIs (application programming interfaces) to fulfill all their requests, but APIs sure make things a lot easier. Our tool lets you integrate with the most popular systems out there, like <a href="http://stripe.com">Stripe</a> for payment or <a href="http://postmates.com">Postmates</a> and <a href="http://grubhub.com">GrubHub</a> for food ordering. All you’ll need is an API key to plug into our tool and you’re good to go.</li>
</ul>
<p>And the best part is you can get this all up and running in a matter of minutes.</p>
<p>Now let’s learn how to create your own SMS Service!</p>
<h1><b>How to Create Your Own SMS Service: Tutorial</b></h1>
<h2><b>Step 1: Sign up for OneReach</b></h2>
<p>To set up a OneReach account, visit our homepage, then<a href="http://onereach.com/pricing"> click on pricing</a>. There, you can pick the number you want and the pricing plan you want (or sign up for a 14-day trial). After you enter your credit card information, you’re set up with OneReach!</p>
<p><a href="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/screenshot2.png"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-1677 size-large" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/screenshot2-546x304.png" alt="screenshot2" width="546" height="304" /></a></p>
<h2><b>Step 2: Set up a payment system account</b></h2>
<p>In order to take payments, you’ll need to create an account for an online payment system. We suggest <a href="http://stripe.com">Stripe</a>, <a href="http://braintreepayments.com">Braintree</a> or <a href="http://dwolla.com">Dwolla</a>. They all have APIs so you can integrate with OneReach, link to a payment page and store payment information for future purchases.</p>
<p><a href="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/stripe2.png"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1678" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/stripe2-546x282.png" alt="stripe2" width="546" height="282" /></a></p>
<h2><b>Step 3: Log into OneReach’s </b><b><i>Action Desk</i></b></h2>
<p>Go to <a href="https://go.onereach.com/">go.onereach.com</a> to sign in to your new Action Desk and get familiar with it. This is where you’ll be fielding all your incoming texts.</p>
<p><a href="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/action-desk.png"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1679" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/action-desk-546x268.png" alt="action desk" width="546" height="268" /></a></p>
<p>That’s it! You now know how to create your own SMS service! Now all that’s left is to promote your new number and let the texts roll in! If you need to add more agents as demand increases, you can do that with OneReach. And if more messages start coming in, you can adjust your plan to compensate for that.</p>
<h2><b>Conclusion</b></h2>
<p>Magic has a pretty awesome concept—text in whatever you want and get it delivered to your door in no time. But there are already some pretty strong copycats out there, and you could be the next one since you know how to create your own SMS service. What’s really important now is how you’ll differentiate yourself from the pack. We found this quote from<a href="http://techcrunch.com/2015/04/01/go-butler/"> Magic competitor GoButler co-founder CEO Navin Hadzaad</a> pretty inspiring:</p>
<blockquote><p>Think of it this way: in 6 months, when you tell us ‘I want my favourite pizza now. I’m at home’ – we know what you’re favourite pizza is, we know where you live, we have your payment details. In the background, our integrated-API with our food delivery partner will trigger the order, the payment will automatically be processed and you’ll get a confirmation. Isn’t that convenient?</p></blockquote>
<p>With our tool, there’s no limit to what your OneReach-powered text service can do. Now, go make some magic happen.</p>
<p><b><i>If you need help with your new text service, shoot us an email at support@onereach.com. And don’t forget to download our whitepaper, </i></b><a href="http://onereach.com/resources/10-things-about-text"><b><i>10 Things Every Business Should Know About Text Messaging</i></b></a><b><i>.</i></b></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/the-magic-model-how-to-instantly-build-your-own-sms-concierge-service/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>OneReach Crafts Unique Campaign With Stella Artois</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/onereach-crafts-unique-campaign-with-stella-artois/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/onereach-crafts-unique-campaign-with-stella-artois/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Big Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IVR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Use Cases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/onereach-crafts-unique-campaign-with-stella-artois/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Are you ready to say bonjour to the simple life? Stella Artois thinks so.</p>
<p><a href="onereach.com">OneReach</a> recently collaborated with <a href="http://www.stellaartois.com/en_us/stella-artois-cidre/hamptons-picnic-properties.html">Stella Artois</a>, ad agency <a href="http://www.mothernewyork.com/">Mother New York</a> and production company <a href="http://www.stopp.se/">Stopp</a> to create a unique user experience for Stella Artois web visitors. To promote their Hamptons Picnic Properties sweepstakes, Stella Artois provided users with an interactive experience where users could chat with brand ambassador Le Président before entering to win the competition.</p>
<p><span id="more-7242"></span>Users who visit the Stella Artois Cidre website can input their phone number and receive a call from the fictional Le Président. The user and Le Président can then engage in a conversation about hair care, the perfect date, and even selfies.</p>
<p>Mother New York was responsible for the overall creative idea and campaign, while Stopp was responsible for the creative execution and development. OneReach facilitated the phone call and voice recognition through VoIP.</p>
<p>Nicole Ferraris, interactive producer at Stopp, had this to say about the OneReach platform:</p>
<blockquote><p>What caught our attention with OneReach was the turnkey solution for voice recognition and the graphical user interface, allowing us to design an interactive phone call very quickly. By leveraging an existing tool set like OneReach, we could devote more of our time to polishing the user experience instead of constructing the underlying system.</p></blockquote>
<p>OneReach CEO Rich Weborg was equally impressed with this unique use case, saying:</p>
<blockquote><p>We were really impressed by how the team at Stopp used IVR capabilities to create an engaging (and funny!) interactive video for their marketing program. Our product has a wide variety of use cases, but this was truly a first for us. Stopp’s creative use of our technology was really impressive. They did a great job of weaving the technology (voice and web) together for a seamless experience. We would love to work with them again on equally exciting programs.</p></blockquote>
<p>Want to try out the experience for yourself? Give Le Président a call below! And to learn more about creating a personalized experience for customers, <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/omnichannel-seamless-experience">download our ebook here</a>.</p>
<p><iframe src="http://hamptonspicnicproperties.com" width="750" height="422" frameborder="0" scrolling="yes" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe>Photo Credit: <a href="http://www.mothernewyork.com/news/hamptons-picnic-properties">Mother New York</a>. Edited.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/onereach-crafts-unique-campaign-with-stella-artois/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Strengthen Your Disaster Response Efforts With SMS</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/strengthen-your-disaster-response-efforts-with-sms/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/strengthen-your-disaster-response-efforts-with-sms/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Big Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Communication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Non-Profit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Use Cases]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/strengthen-your-disaster-response-efforts-with-sms/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Three weeks ago, a devastating 7.8 magnitude earthquake hit Nepal, killing 7,000 people and displacing millions. Homes were leveled, monuments were reduced to rubble, and a people were shaken.</p>
<p>In the hours that followed, aid organizations rushed into action, mobilizing medical personnel and rescue workers in response to the crisis. Organizations like Doctors Without Borders and global Red Cross societies organized search and rescue efforts, tended to the wounded and distributed supplies.</p>
<p>Then, a second earthquake hit.</p>
<p>Across the world, countries have put forth millions of dollars in aid, <a href="http://www.usaid.gov/news-information/press-releases/may-5-2015-usaid-announces-11-million-additional-assistance-nepal-earthquake"> with the U.S. alone pledging $26 million</a>. On a smaller scale, global citizens have made donations of their own, whether online, over the phone or through text messaging. But in the wake of a disaster, it’s important not only to only to have donations set up—it’s important to have communications as well.</p>
<h1><span id="more-7233"></span>How to communicate in a disaster</h1>
<p><a href="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/text-response.png"><img class="alignleft wp-image-1542 size-medium" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/text-response-300x300.png" alt="text response" width="300" height="300" /></a>In the aftermath of a disaster, people are trying to find loved ones, shelter, and food and water. In the United States, FEMA sends out<a href="https://www.fema.gov/frequently-asked-questions-wireless-emergency-alerts"> Wireless Emergency Alerts</a> when disasters strike. These messages detail actions residents in afflicted areas should take, as well as the agency sending the message. Residents can also<a href="http://www.fema.gov/text-messages"> text the short code 43362 (4FEMA)</a> with the keyword SHELTER and their zip code to find shelter near them.</p>
<p>You might be asking why texting and not, say, a mobile app. One reason is that a lot more people use feature phones than smartphones in developing nations. Take the United States and Nepal, for instance. Mobile phone penetration is about<a href="http://www.statista.com/statistics/222307/forecast-of-mobile-phone-penetration-in-the-us/"> 80% in the United States</a>, with about<a href="http://www.pewinternet.org/2015/04/01/us-smartphone-use-in-2015/#smartphones"> 64% penetration for smartphones</a>. In contrast, mobile phone penetration is at<a href="http://www.nta.gov.np/en/2012-06-01-11-33-01/mis-archives/mis-reports/nta-mis-85/download"> 79% in Nepal</a>, but is only at<a href="http://www.nepalitelecom.com/2015/03/top-ten-phone-makers-market-in-nepal.html"> about 20% for smartphones</a>.</p>
<p>This isn’t to say that mobile apps and the Internet aren’t valuable post-crisis, but in Nepal,<a href="http://www.pcworld.com/article/2915012/nepal-communications-hit-by-power-outage-lastmile-issues.html"> when links aren’t going through</a> and the Internet is slow, text might be the only option. Case in point: after the earthquake,<a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-intersect/wp/2015/04/27/how-google-and-facebook-are-finding-victims-of-the-nepal-earthquake/"> Google deployed its Person Finder tool</a>, where global citizens could search for a missing person with SMS (shown here with the US search phone number).</p>
<p><a href="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/text-response2.png"><img class=" size-medium wp-image-1543 alignright" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/text-response2-300x300.png" alt="text response2" width="300" height="300" /></a>Google had experience from past disasters like the Boston bombing and the earthquake/nuclear disaster at Fukushima. Similarly, the U.S. government has also been more prepared with disaster communications. After Hurricane Katrina,<a href="http://www.computerworld.com/article/2506949/mobile-wireless/communication-key-to-post-disaster-survival.html"> major carriers mobilized portable cell towers</a> and made necessary repairs. In addition, <a href="http://www.disasterready.org/blog/humanitarian-aid-workers-increasingly-use-smartphones-online-learning">today’s relief workers</a> do have smartphones, which become tools to make things happen when communication is at its peak.</p>
<p>So what’s the most effective way to communicate in a disaster? According to the FCC, many times<a href="https://www.fcc.gov/emergency-communications-tips"> text messages will go through</a> when calls won’t,<a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2012/05/31/uk-usa-weather-storms-idUSLNE84U01D20120531"> a sentiment FEMA echoes</a>. After the Boston bombing,<a href="http://www.fastcompany.com/3008458/tech-forecast/why-your-phone-doesnt-work-during-disasters-and-how-fix-it"> carriers urged customers to use texting</a> because they take up less bandwidth than voice. Text is not only a highly used channel&#8211;it’s also the only one that might get through.</p>
<h1>Preparing for the worst</h1>
<p>Google and American Red Cross are big organizations, so they’re able to rapidly deploy preexisting communication solutions. However, not all organizations have a communication solution in place, and they need to get one up and running quickly. And sometimes the magnitude of the disaster might wipe out the wireless network or cell towers.</p>
<p>That’s why it’s important to have a solution in place beforehand, if possible. Solutions like OneReach can be deployed in under an hour, and in the midst of a disaster, every second counts. Whatever platform you do use, make sure you have the right kind of number. Short codes can send more messages per minute than <a href="http://www.onereach.com/blog/?p=534">long codes</a>, but they typically take three months to provision, so plan ahead.</p>
<p>The next step is activating the flow before the disaster hits. This way, you can get people the answers they need even if your Internet connection goes down, because the phone number is stored in the cloud. If communications are restored after a disaster, you can then create additional outbound flows for people to engage with. One best practice is to get people to opt-in to updates and disaster notifications beforehand, instead of having to rely on inbound numbers that might get overwhelmed (or maybe not even seen at all).</p>
<p>But it’s not enough to get your message out—it’s important for people to read it, especially after a disaster. Text has a 98% open rate, so if an organization needs to get an important message out, there’s no better channel to use for maximum exposure. However, sometimes people want more information than an outbound alert provides, and sometimes the network bandwidth is overwhelmed. That’s why it’s so essential to create two-way text communication flows, to get people the answers they need as soon as possible.</p>
<p>However, text messaging won’t always be enough, as some citizens will want to call. You may not be able to answer everything, which is where automation comes in. If people contact you with the same question, you can create automated flows so people can get the answers they need via text while leaving space for more pressing calls. Questions about shelter, food and water, people&#8211;all of those can be managed through an automated voice or text flow that directs people to different questions based on their input.</p>
<p>If residents do need more specific information, they can also talk to an agent over text chat. The important part is that people are able to get their questions answered.</p>
<h1>Conclusion</h1>
<p>In the wake of a disaster, information can be as vital as food and water. By enabling a text solution before, during and after disaster strikes, organizations can get people the information they need on a reliable channel. And after your world gets shaken, having something you can count on is everything.</p>
<p><em>Want to be a part of the relief effort in Nepal? Text <strong>REDCROSS</strong> to <strong>90999</strong> to donate $10 to the American Red Cross Disaster Relief fund. Every contribution counts!</em></p>
<p>To learn more about adding text to your organization, <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/10-things-about-text">download our whitepaper here</a>.</p>
<p>Photo from <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/dfid/16691218724">DFID- the UK Department for International Development</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/strengthen-your-disaster-response-efforts-with-sms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Cities Should Let Residents Text 311</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/why-cities-should-let-residents-text-311/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/why-cities-should-let-residents-text-311/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Big Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Use Cases]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/why-cities-should-let-residents-text-311/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the past, business SMS focused on marketing programs and simple notifications. That’s changing. There is now significant consumer demand to text a business for customer support. This extends to the public sector&#8211;large cities are starting to provide text messaging services to their residents for 311 service. This is partially in response to consumer demand for texting for support: <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/high-demand-for-text-message-2014-report">over 64% of Americans</a> would rather text than call for help.</p>
<p>Nearly 300 cities across the nation have a 311 call system in place that citizens can contact, but only a handful of cities—New York City, Minneapolis, Chicago, Denver, Pittsburgh, Dallas, Boston—have these numbers text-enabled. It costs cities an average of $3.40 to answer a phone call, whereas answering a text only costs 60 cents (and even less if the message is automated).</p>
<p><span id="more-7232"></span>By text-enabling their 311 numbers, cities can deflect calls that come into the often understaffed response centers and still interact with citizens. If citizens call into the 311 number, they can channel pivot to text to chat with a city employee. The city employees can respond to multiple incoming texts at once, as opposed to only one call at a time.</p>
<p>Offering the option text 311 doesn&#8217;t just benefit cities. 311 numbers are an easy way for citizens to contact their city with questions, concerns, or important updates about their surrounding area. 311 numbers improve the user experience: they’re easier to remember than a short code or toll free number, meaning citizens are more likely to engage with their city. Text-enabling these numbers lets citizens use the same number to text and call, rather than having to remember a brand new number.</p>
<p>Text-enabling 311 numbers benefits citizens as well as wireless carriers. Currently, text-enabled long codes (10-digit numbers) are passed through several aggregators, each of whom charge a service fee. A text-enabled 311 number cuts out the middleman altogether, providing a safe and dependable income stream with a low probability of spam.</p>
<p>There are an incredible amount use cases for text-enabled 311 numbers. In <a href="http://311.dc.gov/">Washington, D.C.</a>, citizens can text 311 to report potholes or broken parking meters. In <a href="http://www.cityofevanston.org/311-service/index/">Evanston, Ill.</a>, citizens can text a restaurant name to their local 311 number and get its health rating. In <a href="http://www.ci.minneapolis.mn.us/311/">Minneapolis</a>, citizens can opt-in to receive 311 snow alerts, and in <a href="http://www1.nyc.gov/311/index.page">New York City</a>, citizens can text 311 to pay a parking ticket or report a noisy neighbor.</p>
<p>Providing 311 phone support was a significant improvement in communication between a city and its residents. Adding the ability to text 311 will be just as significant. With other n11 services like 911 starting to support text, a text-enabled 311 number will improve the public infrastructure of any city. Communicating with citizens has never been easier.</p>
<p><em><strong>To learn more about citizens&#8217; preference for text support, you can <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/high-demand-for-text-message-2014-report">download the 2014 Harris Report here</a>.</strong></em></p>
<p>Photo by Flickr user <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/garryknight/11138705943">Garry Knight</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/why-cities-should-let-residents-text-311/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>[INFOGRAPHIC] Implementing the Omnichannel Experience</title>
		<link>https://onereach.ai/infographic-implementing-the-omnichannel-experience/</link>
				<comments>https://onereach.ai/infographic-implementing-the-omnichannel-experience/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elias Parker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Big Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Infographic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OmniChannel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Use Cases]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onereach.ai/infographic-implementing-the-omnichannel-experience/</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[&#8230;]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Companies are connecting with customers in more ways than ever, but when it comes to customer support, many businesses still rely on just phone or email. While these are important channels, customers are beginning to expect more options from the companies they do business with. Customers ultimately expect businesses to support how they want to communicate — phone, email, web chat, social media and texting—and they want to work with the companies that make interacting easy.</p>
<p><span id="more-7223"></span>Unfortunately, that&#8217;s not always the case:</p>
<ul>
<li>87% of customers think brands need to work harder to create a seamless experience.</li>
<li>61% of customers were unable to easily switch from one channel to another when interacting with customer service</li>
<li>42% of customer experience professionals say their agents must use multiple applications to manage inquiries across channels</li>
</ul>
<p>Today&#8217;s customers demand an omnichannel experience, one where they can use any channel and receive personalized, seamless service. This type of strategy brings various channels together in a more integrated and consistent way, drawing on past interactions and customer data to create a seamless experience. If customers do have to switch between channels, this kind of approach maintains the conversation no matter what channel they use or where they leave off. A customer can start on a web chat and transition to text conversation without losing the context of that interaction.</p>
<p>But what is an omnichannel customer experience <em>really</em> like? Check out what a day in the life of an omnichannel customer might look like, <strong>and don&#8217;t forget to <a href="http://onereach.com/resources/omnichannel-seamless-experience">download our new ebook</a> on the seamless customer experience.</strong></p>
<p><img class="alignnone" src="http://onereach.ai/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/Implementing_Omnichannel.png" alt="" width="960" height="5399" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>https://onereach.ai/infographic-implementing-the-omnichannel-experience/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
